Chapter 5: The Forbidden Forest

They met Hagrid and the quietly quivering Quirinus Quirrell in the Great Hall. Hagrid, evidently some sort of half-giant Ranger, was carrying a heavy crossbow (Milo was skeptical, light crossbows were much more damage-efficient) and carrying Fang's leash. Milo had carefully prepared his spells that morning, and avoided casting any throughout the day—meaning the Gryffindors started to be late for class, again, as Peeves could harass them with impunity, and Milo was starting to appear rather useless in their lessons. Still, he wasn't about to venture into something called the Forbidden Forest without a full complement of spells.

"Mage Armour," he cast as soon as they approached the professor and the Keeper of the Keys. A thin, invisible field of force surrounded him like a second skin. It was far from complete protection, but it would help a little.

"Hagrid!" Harry said happily.

"A-all right" Quirrell said, "our j-job is simple: all we're t-to do is enter the f-f-forest and f-find whatever it is a-attacking the u-unicorns," he stammered nervously. "A-and then r-return to H-Hogwarts so the H-Headmaster and I can d-d-decide what to do."

"Sounds like a plan," Milo said, although he privately wondered why all the powerful wizards living in Hogwarts didn't just use some Divinations to determine what was in the forest.

"Yeh all right, Harry?" Hagrid asked the Harry, who looked a little nervous, but determined. Milo was a little impressed that he'd volunteered for this, his friend was only three days into his wizard training. Milo hadn't, in fact, seen him perform any actual magic, yet. Now that's guts, he thought. But smart. If he lives, anything we encounter will give him so much XP that he's bound to level up at least once.

"Let's be off, then," Hagrid said, and led them through the grounds. Hogwarts sure looks eerie at night, Milo thought. A bit like Thamior's old place. Milo felt a brief pang of homesickness; Thamior was evil to the core, sure, but after the number of times Milo and his party had defeated him, he was practically family. "Now, I want ter be clear: anythin' happens—anythin' at all—and yer ter send up red sparks an' run, yeh hear?"

Harry and Milo nodded mutely. Milo could do close enough with a Dancing Lights spell.

"A-and keep y-your eyes p-p-p-peeled," said Quirrell. "A-and stick c-close."

A soft breeze caused the chill night air to bite clean through their school uniforms, and Milo pulled out a warm scarf and some wool gloves (fingerless, so as not to interfere with his spellcasting gestures) from his Belt of Hidden Pouches.

"Right. I'll take Harry an' Fang, Quirrell can take Milo," Hagrid said as they reached the outskirts of the forest.

"What, we're splitting up?" Harry asked.

"We've had bad experiences with that before," Milo added.

"Best way to find what we're lookin' fer," Hagrid said. "Too big of a group, an' we'll spook it. Remember: run in ter trouble, send sparks."

"Well, Harry," Milo said. "See you on the other side, right?"

"'Course. Don't worry, I'm sure we'll be fine," Harry said. Milo was astonished: was Harry trying to reassure him?

"You know, Harry, I think that one day—when you've gone up a few levels, and get a few magic items—you'll be quite the hero. Good luck."

The two groups split up and entered the forest.

"So, what are we looking for, exactly, Professor?" Milo asked Quirrell.

"We are not yet certain," Quirrell said. "Something that's been attacking unicorns—almost certainly some kind of animal. Keep an eye out for any unicorn's blood; it has a distinctive silvery colour."

Again, Milo had the nagging feeling that he'd failed a skill check. Quirrell had his wand at the ready. It felt like they'd been walking for hours, but Milo doubted it was more than half of one.

"Bet this is old hat for you, right?" Milo asked, feeling slightly nervous. "You probably charge into the Forbidden Forest every other week, fighting monsters and things?"

"No, that's Hagrid's job. I've only been this deep twice before," Quirrell said.

"Oh. Good."

"Wait, quiet—I think I heard something," Quirrell said. "Best hide behind that tree, I'll investigate. Just stay down."

Before Milo could argue, Quirrel strode off the path with his wand held out like a weapon—which, Milo, supposed, it was. Milo shrugged and ducked behind a tree, which was covered in soft moss. He heard rustling in the darkness, and debated whether to cast Dancing Lights to see what was going on. He eventually decided against, reasoning that the light might reveal some sort of monster sneaking up on him but would certainly attract everything in the entire forest.

Then he heard another rustle, closer this time. Okay, something is definitely sneaking up on me. He moved to stand up quietly, but found, to his surprise, that he couldn't. He appeared to be stuck to the tree.

"What the—oh, gross." What he'd thought was moss turned out to be webs. He struggled against it vainly, but it was useless—he was stuck.

"Protection from Evil, Mirror Image, Invisibility," Milo cast in quick succession. He vanished abruptly, but five identical illusory copies of himself remained. Classic shell con—none of the visible Milos were the real one. He hoped he wasn't jumping at shadows, because he'd just burned through most of his daily allotment of spells.

He was mildly satisfied when one of his illusory doubles was abruptly torn to pieces by a shadowy creature. The satisfaction vanished when he realized he was, illusions aside, stuck to a tree being attacked by a monster he couldn't see.

"Dancing Lights," he cast, sending four glowing red spheres into the sky above him. On the way up, they briefly illuminated, in red, horrible compound eyes and sharp pincers.

Great, he thought. Giant spiders. His invisibility spell would end as soon as he attacked one of them—that is, cast any spell that included them in the area. That ruled out Glitterdust and Grease, Milo's two favourite spells, but not creative use of Levitate. He could move himself or up to 400lbs of objects vertically, but not horizontally. Generally the spell was used by Wizards to escape, but Milo doubted it would pull him off of the webs.

"Levitate," he, and all of his doppelgangers, said. A hefty fallen log nearby Milo rose up slowly, ponderously, into the air a foot or two. Another mirror Milo fell to the spider's attack, and Milo started to sweat. Seeing yourself being eaten by a giant spider in dim red light while alone and trapped in a forest is, probably, one of the worst experiences a kid can go through (after visiting the dentist, of course). Milo then carefully reached into his Belt of Hidden Pouches with his right hand (his left was stuck in the webs) and withdrew an old adventurer's staple—fifty feet of silk rope and a grappling hook. The rope was invisible, but would cease to be as soon as it came to be more than ten feet from Milo—and the log was about twelve feet away. Hopefully the spider(s?) wouldn't notice two feet of taut rope appearing from nowhere. He awkwardly tossed the rope at the log—and missed. Milo saw another mirror Milo wink out of existence, presumably hit by the unseen attacker.

Milo looked at the fallen grappling hook, lying uselessly in the mud, and panicked slightly. Shouldn't help be coming? He thought. The glowing lights are up above me and everything. Wish I prepared Mage Hand this morning. His plan had been to lift the fallen tree up into the air, and use the grappling hook to pull it over to above the monstrous spider, then drop it. He doubted he'd have time to pull the hook back and throw it again. Well, nothing for it.

"No sense in us both dying, Mordy," he whispered to his familiar as he pulled him from his belt. "Run back to Hogwarts, see if Hermione or Hannah want you to be their familiar. Good luck, old friend."

Fear. Despair. Reluctance. He felt through their bond. Mordenkainen reluctantly crawled out of Milo's grasp, and turned around briefly. Love, he felt, before the magical creature skittered off.

"GLITTERDUST," Milo bellowed. The spider, now covered in glowing dust, was huge. The hairy creature's legs spanned at least fifteen feet across. The thing was blinded by the spell, but that would only last for twenty-four seconds. Also, his invisibility was gone, and he was still stuck. He decided to try burning the webs off of him with Prestidigitation—he might well get set on fire, but at least he'd be free.

"Prestidigitation," he said, and a small jet of fire sprung out of his hand at the tree… but nothing happened. Milo was confused, he was sure that would work. (Milo's only experience with webs came from the Web spell, which was used frequently by his arch-nemesis Thamior, and only bear passing resemblance to actual spider silk. Notably, the magical webs burn rapidly when exposed to fire—real spider silk, as Milo would know if he'd put any skill points into Knowledge (Nature), is fireproof).

Only eighteen seconds left. The spider flailed about awkwardly, catching one of Milo's duplicates with one of its eight hairy legs. The duplicate flickered and vanished. All Milo had left was Silent Image, Feather Fall, Grease, and some cantrips.

"Grease," he cast at the ground under the spider. The blind spider's eight legs flailed about, trying to get traction on the slippery ground, it's pincers creating an agitated clicking sound. It managed to keep its balance, however—Milo had forgotten that creatures with extra legs got a bonus to stability. He felt, after casting, that it might have been more effective to cast it on himself in case the spider tried to pick him up. Ah, well, twelve seconds to live. Milo frowned, thoughtfully. One effect of Grease was that anyone standing on the slippery surface had to make a Balance check to stay standing, and one effect of Balance was that anyone who took damage had to redo the check or fall. The amount of damage didn't make a difference.

Milo grinned.

"Acid Splash," he cast, and a pitifully small orb of acid hit the spider in what its face would be if it had one. Acid Splash was one of the most useless spells in existence—it hurt even less than just punching someone would, or even throwing a small rock—but Milo, as a Conjurer, got an extra Conjuration spell per level, and Acid Splash was the only 0th-level Conjuration spell in the multiverse. Milo had no choice but to prepare it every morning.

The spider fell to the ground, and Milo had six seconds before Glitterdust wore off and the spider could see. Milo gestured at the Levitated log, still floating a little above the ground, and it flew up into the canopy.

"Hey, ugly," Milo said, reaching into his belt. "Fear me, for I hold the mighty eldritch power of an eleven-foot pole!"

He gave the fallen spider a light push, and it slid (slightly downhill) along the Greased dirt, until it came to a stop in the slight depression where the log once was.

The spider's vision returned, and as Glitterdust ended, it became stealthy again. The spider's dark brown carapace was all but invisible in the darkness.

Milo dismissed Levitate.

He couldn't see what happened, but he definitely felt the 600 XP he got for defeating a Challenge Rating 2 Monstrous Spider solo. Milo sighed. He was somewhat disappointed by that, he thought the spider was worth way more than that. Well, I guess the spiders here are pushovers compared to the ones back home, he thought.

When Quirrell, Hagrid and Harry found him, he was whistling softly to himself, stuck to a tree.

"Milo!" Harry shouted, panicked. "Are you alright?"

"Yeah, totally fine," he said, though in truth he felt a little woozy.

"Yeh managed ter kill an Acromantula?" Hagrid asked, shocked. "Aragog's not gonna like this. We'd best be leavin'."

"What took you guys so long?" Milo asked dizzily as Hagrid pulled him out of the webs.

"We ran in ter Quirrell, who was in a right state, said we had ter help yeh—but we were delayed by centaurs. Them stargazers took an unnatural dislike to our Defence Professor."

Quirrell appeared to have lost his short-lived courage, and was as pale and quivery as ever.

"Centaurs… in a forest? I figured horse-y types would prefer plains… not planes, mind, 'cause of all the… weird… monsters…" Milo's eyelids felt heavy and his head drooped slightly. He felt sort of numb all over.

"Hagrid? I think something's wrong with Milo," Harry said to the giant.

"What? Can't see anythin' in this ruddy darkness. Professor, could you…?"
"O-of c-c-c-course, Hagrid," Quirrell stammered. "L-lumos."

Quirrell held the tip of his glowing wand over Milo, so Hagrid could investigate closer. It was hard to tell, because of the poor lighting and Milo's black uniform, but there was a patch that seemed slightly darker than the rest.

"Oh, no," Hagrid gasped. "He's bin bit."

Milo frowned. He definitely didn't remember that happening. In fact, he was all but certain the acromantula never got even close to close enough to him to bite him.

"Nah, hairy brute never touched me," Milo said.

"H-he's delusional from the v-venom," Quirrell said. "I f-f-feel terrible, he w-was my r-r-responsibility."

"You're stuttering," Milo said. Something was nagging at him, but it felt as though his head were packed with wool.

"I-I a-always st-st-stutter," Quirrell stuttered.

"We need ter get 'im back to the castle," Hagrid said. "Acromantula venom can be lethal."

"Poison?" Milo asked, and reached for his belt. He kept antitoxin in one of the pockets… which one? It seemed like it should be important, but he was having difficulty focussing.

"I-I'll take him," Quirrell said. "You c-c-can keep s-searching."

"Right. Harry, you'd best be goin' with 'em," the giant said to the Boy-Who-Lived.

"But, then you'd be out there alone," Harry protested. "Are you sure you'd be okay?"
"Nah, I got Fang. Don't worry yerself about me."

"Wingardium Leviosa," Quirrell said, casting the Hovering Charm on Milo, who was starting to lose consciousness. Quirrell led Harry through the forest back towards the castle.

"Shouldn't we hurry, Professor?" Harry asked anxiously. "Milo looks really sick."

Quirrell shook his head.

"N-not in a f-forest," he said, "and c-certainly n-not in a f-forest in the d-d-dark. W-we could tr-trip in j-just about a-anything, and th-then we would take e-even longer."

Harry supposed Quirrell had a point, but their leisurely pace seemed torturously slow to him.

Harry, frightened by the forest, gradually drifted closer to Quirrell as they walked. The Defence Professor was a bit spineless, but he seemed pretty competent with magic—and he had faced down vampires at some point. However, as Harry drew nearer, his scar began to ache abruptly. He doubled over, clutching at his forehead. When his hand drew away, there was blood on it.

"A-are you al-alright, boy?" Quirrell asked.

"Uh," Harry said as the pain gradually decreased. "Yeah… yeah, I'm fine. It's nothing. It just… my scar hurts sometimes, usually around Snape."

"Th-the scar—I understand y-you got i-it from the D-d-d-dark—from H-H-He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named?"

"Yes, Professor. That's what I'm told, at least."

Quirrell frowned.

"Th-then I'd s-s-suggest you b-be wary around the Potions M-M-Master," he said. "H-He used to be a D-D-D-Death Eater, I-I'm told. A-and this d-d-detention was h-his idea."

Harry was surprised. He didn't like Snape, but he hadn't realized that the greasy professor had been one of Voldemort's followers. Maybe he was going to try and finish the job that the dark wizard had started? Perhaps it was Harry, and not Milo, who had been meant to be attacked by the giant spider. Good thing Quirrell had been there.

As they continued to walk, Milo's condition worsened. He started babbling incoherently about his pockets and Quirrell's stutter, before passing out entirely.

o—o—o—o

Mordy scampered as fast as he could across the cold stone floor (which, considering he was a rat (more or less), was not terribly fast) towards the Gryffindor Common Rooms.

Everything was going swell until he encountered The Fell Beast. The Fell Beast gave a cry of rage that would haunt Mordy's dreams for weeks and charged. Mordy tried to dodge, but the cat was too fast—its claws left a bloody gash down the rodent's back. It would have been enough to kill a lesser rat, but Mordy, as a familiar, had more hit points—barely. He had half as many as his master, who unfortunately decided to dump Constitution at character creation.

Mordy climbed a suit of armour (rusty, the Gryffindors hadn't got this far yet) to escape the dreadful claws. He tensed, and jumped over to the next suit, barely catching hold of the helmet's visor. The Fell Beast, meanwhile, sat on the ground, debating what to do. He saw her tense up, ready to pounce, and Mordenkainen started to wish, heartily, that his master had taken the Improved Familiar feat.

As the Fell Beast jumped, Mordy let go of the visor and landed on the ground painfully. The cat's collision with the armour toppled it to the ground, and it spread in pieces over the hallway. Mordy evaded them easily (Improved Evasion could be handy) and sprinted as the cat regained her senses. Terror, Panic, Despair, he felt through the empathic bond with his master.

He rounded the last corner before the common room, and finally reached the portrait. The Fell Beast was hot on his heels.

"Password?" asked the Fat Lady.

"Squeak," said Mordenkainen.

"Correct," said the painting, and swung open. He barely made it through the portal as the painting swung shut. He could clearly hear the irritated sound of the Fell Beast hissing in frustration on the other side. There was a promise of pain and death in that hiss. Victory, Satisfaction, Triumph, he felt through the bond with his master.

In the common room, he saw Scabbers eating some crumbs off the floor.

"Squeak!" he said to the ugly rat.

"Squeak?" the appropriately-named Scabbers asked, surprised.

"Squeak, squeak-squeak squeak!" Mordy said urgently. Fear, Pain, Dizziness, he felt. Oh, no, Mordy thought. Has he been poisoned? Is he sick? Mordy concentrated and tried to send strength through the bond. Every species of familiar had some sort of special power—and rats could convey a measure of resistance against things like sickness in their master, as long as they were within a mile.

"Squeak," Scabbers said, and gave the rat-equivalent of a shrug. Mordy gave Scabbers a solid kick to the stomach, and ran into the girls' dorms. He had to find the one with the nice teeth. She was smart, she would understand, she would help. The problem was that the humans all looked alike to him.

"Squeak?" he said hopefully to one, who woke up, looked at Mordy, and screamed. Wrong one, he thought.

"There's a rat in my room!" she cried. "Lavender! Wake up!" another girl stirred irritably.

"What?" Lavender asked sleepily. "Ack!" she shrieked. The other humans all stood up out of bed while Mordy looked at them each, carefully, trying to figure out which was the one with nice teeth. The fact that they all were screaming made it easier.

"Hey, it's that rat Milo carries around all the time," said one (Hannah, in case you were wondering, not that Mordy knew that).

"What's he doing in here?" Lavender asked. Mordy gave the rat equivalent of a sigh. This wouldn't happen if I were a mouse, he thought. Everyone loves mice.

"Squeak!" he said urgently.

"He looks kinda distressed," Lavender said. "Wait, is he bleeding?"

"He should be with Milo," said one. "And Milo's out in the Forbidden Forest…" she frowned. "We need to find McGonagall, immediately. Milo could be in trouble—and this poor rat looks half dead." As she spoke, he could see her teeth—good, rat-like teeth. Yes, this is the one, he thought as his hit points slipped into the negatives.

o—o—o—o

This is taking way too long, Harry thought. Is Quirrell lost?

"Sh-should be just past the next few t-trees," Quirrell reassured him. "Th-then we'll b-be in open t-t-territory and can sp-sprint."

Harry was skeptical. He was fairly certain they were going roughly perpendicular to the castle, but then again, he'd never been in a forest before—it was more than likely that his sense of direction was misleading him. Still, he felt that the return journey should be faster than the trip out—they were taking all kinds of twists and turns while searching for the mysterious unicorn-killer—but it had been at least that long since they'd left Hagrid.

Harry gripped his wand, for all the good that it would do. His scar still ached somewhat, so he wondered if Snape was around, creeping in the bushes.

"Hello?" he heard a familiar voice call out. "Hagrid? Harry? Quirrell? Milo?"

"Headmaster!" Harry shouted. "We're over here!"

Quirrell, Harry noticed, looked briefly frustrated before regaining his composure.

"Wait there!" Dumbledore shouted. As the grandfatherly man approached, Harry could see a glowing red light coming closer. It looked like fire, but it felt oddly soothing. Quirrell shielded his eyes from the bright light, but Harry felt fine

"H-Headmaster, th-the boy was b-bit by an acromantula," Quirrell said to Dumbledore, who had a red, glowing bird of some sort perched on his shoulder. "H-he's been p-poisoned."

Dumbledore acted quickly.

"Quirrell, take Mr. Potter back to the Gryffindor common room. Fawkes," Dumbledore said to the bird, "take me and Milo to the hospital wing." There was a burst of red flame, and Dumbledore and Harry's friend vanished with a small puff of smoke.

"Sh-showy, b-b-but effective," Quirrell noted.

o—o—o—o

Milo awoke, staring at an all-too familiar ceiling.

"I'm in the hospital again, aren't I?" he asked weakly.

"I'm sorry to say that you're correct, young man," Madam Pomfrey said. "And, don't take this the wrong way, but it would be nice to go five days without seeing you."

Milo laughed weakly.

"You'll note," she continued, "that we left you with your magical belt this time. Your… pet… is on the bed next to you."

Mordenkainen was lying on the next bed over, wrapped in bandages.

"What happened to him?" Milo asked, his voice full of concern.

"He was attempting to get the Gryffindor common room, we believe, and was attacked by Ms. Norris. He almost died, but Hermione got him here in time, bless her. His appearance was how Dumbledore knew to go looking for you."

Milo frowned.

"Why did I need rescuing, again? It all seems so foggy."

"You were bitten by an acromantula, a highly intelligent and extremely dangerous magical spider-like monster. You're lucky to be alive. It's the sort of thing I'd think you'd remember," she said. The bite wound had, largely, healed mysteriously during the night, much like his injuries had when he'd first arrived. The venom's effects, however, lingered somewhat.

"No," Milo said. "I definitely don't remember that. There was a spider, and I dropped a tree on it, but it never touched me."

"You're still very sick, and I'm sure it all happened very fast. I wouldn't worry about it," she said, while pondering his words. He thinks he dropped a tree on it? Pomfrey thought. He is delirious.

"How long was I out?" he asked.

"A day and a half, roughly. We managed to stabilize you, but it took until this morning for Snape to brew the antidote," she said. "He worked all night, you know."

Milo frowned. That story didn't add up at all. Something weird was going on.

Chapter 6: Crime Scene Investigation

Author's Notes: Thank you to all of the nice reviews I've gotten (they make my day), and to Blinded in a Bolthole in particular for helping me rewrite my summary.

Don't forget that you can check my Author page for a link to Milo's character sheet and the free Fantasy, Sci-Fi, and/or Modern RPG, Semiautomagic, that I'm working on.

o—o—o—o

Throughout the day, several Gryffindor wellwishers came to visit Milo in the hospital wing. Apparently, word had spread of his run-in with the acromantula, and the rumours had quickly gotten out of hand.

"We heard you fought off a horde of giant spiders, mate —" said one of the Weasley twins (Milo decided, for convenience's sake, to call him George).

"— and save a beautiful unicorn princess —" said Fred (maybe).

"— which is unusual, because unicorns tend to be male —"

"— and also managed to rescue Professor Quirrell —"

"— while growing increasingly weak from spider venom —"

"— defeated You-Know-Who for good —"

"— became king of the Goblins —"

"— found a Philosopher's Stone —"

"— so now, you can live forever —"

"— discovered a thirteenth use for dragon's blood —"

"— and that you're still an available bachelor —"

"— but maybe not for long, based on the rate these stories are spreading."

Following the conversation was somewhat dizzying, but sort of entertaining as well. Hannah and Lavender dropped by with candy (though the people in this strange land called them "sweets," which Milo supposed was generally accurate, with the exception of several trillion flavours of the Every-Flavoured Beans), and Lavender apologized for her behaviour during detention. Milo appreciated the gesture, but was somewhat suspicious of wizarding candy as a whole – he remembered Harry's chocolate frogs trying to escape back on the train (Milo shuddered at the thought of that mechanical monstrosity) and the more unpleasant flavours of the every-flavoured beans.

Hermione, naturally, brought him copies of her class notes from the ones he missed (Milo copied them all into a notebook with Amanuensis (an obscure 0th-level spell that copies text rapidly) and then read it with Scholar's Touch (an invaluable 1st-level spell that reads an entire book (and not, say, a stack of loose-leaf) in a few seconds)).

Ron approached somewhat sheepishly to apologise for not going to the forest with him and Harry, but said that it was really for the best because he was absolutely useless around spiders and would probably just have gotten in the way. Milo forgave him, and they played a game of Wizard's chess, which was just like regular chess except the pieces were apparently intelligent. It really changes the game when, instead of sending a rook forwards to be sacrificed, you're sending up an old, tired wooden soldier begging to be allowed to live and return to his family (he had a pair of pawns to take care of, after all), yet nonetheless resigned to his fate. Ron won, of course, because Milo couldn't remember ever playing chess before. He knew the rules, oddly, but had no memories of an actual game — probably because he was still cut off from any of his backstory not yet explicitly stated.

While he recovered from his ability score damage, Milo tried to solve the puzzle of the spider bite. There was, without a doubt, an ugly injury caused by a fang in his side. However, Milo was absolutely certain that he hadn't been bitten. Even if the spider tried, Milo had Mage Armour and Protection from Evil, which gave him a net boost of +6 to Armour Class, assuming the spider was evil (which it totally was). It was improbable, though not impossible, that the spider had hit him in one attack. But between being blinded and off-balance from Milo's magic, he really doubted the acromantula had a chance — unless he'd been bit before Milo started his attack. But that was impossible because Milo was invisible, and had illusions up besides…

He frowned. No, it really can't have been before I became visible, and probably wasn't when the spider was blinded. Milo could account for the spider's actions during the duration based on the number of mirror images it destroyed and the number of spells he cast.

This doesn't add up at all.

And then there was the matter of Snape. If Snape had been trying to kill him, why did he brew an antidote? Was it really some sort of terrible, slow-acting poison that would kill Milo over the course of weeks, making it look natural? But why bother — he could have just left Milo to succumb to the acromantula venom.

No, there must be another player at work here. Snape was evil, sure — but he wasn't actively trying to kill Milo. He might not even have realized, yet, that Milo was a threat to him.

"Hey, mate," Harry said, breaking him out of his thought process. Milo hadn't noticed the boy entering the room. "Sorry I didn't come earlier, we had broomstick lessons — it turns out I can fly really well! I don't have any idea where the skill came from, I was always rubbish at P.E. — and anyway, Draco must still be mad from that time on the train, so he stole Nev's Remembrall (poor fellow just got out of St. Mungo's) and ran off with it. Anyway, I'm rambling. The point is, I got it back, but McGonagall saw and guess what — I'm on the Quidditch team!"

"What, the game with six pointless players and one PC?" Milo asked.

"Yeah! And I'm the Seeker!" Harry said excitedly. "Hermione's upset because it's against the rules and thinks McGonagall shouldn't have made an exception, but Ron is beside himself."

"That's pretty cool. Bet you'll catch the Snitch — like, really. Ten gold pieces — Galleons, whatever — that you win the first match by the skin of your teeth."

"You're on, but I probably won't be able to pay you for a while when I lose. My money's all in Gringott's," Harry said.

"Oh?" Milo asked. "What's Gringott's?"

"It's this big underground thing, full of dragons and run by goblins," Harry said. "I was there once, it was actually kinda scary."

Milo's ears literally perked up upon hearing this (he was one-sixty-fourth elf).

"Goblins got your gold, eh?" he asked. "Well, well, well. Sounds to me like we have a dungeon crawl in our future," he said excitedly.

"What's a dungeon crawl? Is that some sort of dance? Only, I've never danced before," Harry said.

"What? No. It's where you go into a big underground thing, full of dragons and run by goblins, and come out with piles and piles of gold," Milo explained.

"Oh, I've done that already," Harry commented. "Though I left most of the gold behind for later."

"You— you did what now? I think you're not really getting into the spirit of the thing."

"Well, I was with Hagrid, and he only let me take so much out—"

"Oh, that makes sense. Higher level character, he probably did most of the work to get there. Still, try to argue for an even split next time. If you play your cards right, you could wind up way ahead of your WBL," Milo said.

"My what?" Harry asked.

"Wealth By Level," Milo said. "It's the average amount of total money, in cash, magic items, fortresses, that kind of thing, that a person has based on their level. So like, a powerful wizard can use a Broom of Flying to clean his floors with because he can afford twelve, while a lower-level wizard couldn't even get one."

"Oh," said Harry. "Here, we just call it capitalism."

"Weird. So, what's the deal with this Hagrid guy?"

"Oh, he's a giant, he's my friend — he took me from the Dursleys — and lives in a hut outside the castle. Takes care of the grounds and things. He actually sent me a letter inviting me down to visit him," Harry said. "I think I'll head down later this evening."

"Huh. So tell me, did you notice anything weird about Quirrell's stutter last night?" Milo asked.

"You mean, two nights ago?" Harry asked. Milo nodded, he was still sort of disoriented from sleeping all day. Harry frowned. "I can't swear to it, but I think, just briefly, he was talking normally. Maybe he was so frightened that he sort of stuttered so far he wrapped around and came back the other side?"

"Yeah, maybe," Milo said. There was something he was missing, he was sure of it. His forehead wrinkled with deep thought. "Okay, hang on. Describe Quirrell to me, and pretend I've never met him before, okay?"

Harry looked at Milo like he'd gone crazy (Milo was used to that look by now) but complied. Quirrell: had a verbal tic (one) wore a weird turban (two) was completely spineless (three) but could apparently summon courage when necessary (four!) and emanated an odour of garlic (five).

"Oh my gods," Milo said. "How could I have been so stupid?"

"What, what is it?" Harry asked.

"Five adjectives! Nobody gets five adjectives so soon after meeting them!"

"What?" Harry asked.

"It's just like on the train, remember? When I told you to write down everyone who could be described with more than two adjectives? It's why we go on adventures with Ron and not Dean or Seamus. The more unique a person is, the more important they are."

"So, what does this mean?" Harry asked. He was beginning to feel that Milo's sanity was much like Quirrell's stutter: he went so far through insane that he came out the other side, and started making sense. Well, kind of.

"It means Quirrell is big news, but it's too early to say yet which side he's on. I feel like there's something I should be remembering but just can't."

"You mean, like your parents?" Harry asked.

"No, like something someone said in passing but I didn't write down. Can I see your notes?" Milo asked.

"What, you mean, like from Herbology?"

"No, not those. The adventure notes."

"Oh, sure," Harry said, pulling the lists that Milo had asked him to write from his bag. There were the lists of mysterious things people had said, of unexplained events, and of important characters. Milo pointed out Quidditch: Seeker is for PCs with some satisfaction, but otherwise the search was fruitless.

"Ah, well. It was worth a shot. Maybe we'll hear something that'll make all of this make sense," Milo sighed. "Until then, we'll just keep listening closely."

His next visitor after Harry left was quite unexpected.

"So, we meet again, Malfoy." Milo said coolly.

"Indeed, we do at that," Malfoy sneered. "I just came to see if you were really as weak, injured, helpless, and alone as they say."

"Oh, are you threatening me? Is this really happening? Because as I remember, I've got you two for two, Slytherin."

"Not a threat, no, not at all," Malfoy said, and grinned. "Just thought I'd drop by, say hi, wish you well and tell you I know what you're up to."

"What I'm — I mean, you don't know anything. Fool." Milo said, but quietly his mind raced. What was Milo up to? Not much, really. Just sort of blundering through encounter after encounter, so far; brute forcing his way through problems with magic. But active plotting? Not so much.

"And more importantly, my father knows," Malfoy said. "And my father controls the Wizengamot." Malfoy grinned. "I'd keep an eye on the morning paper, if I were you." He moved to leave, but paused. "Fortunately," he added, "I am not you." He then walked off, whistling softly to himself.

"Well, that was cryptic," Milo mused to himself. "I'm starting to think I should maybe figure out what in Baator is going on before I wind up there."

To do that, he had to go to the library. To do that, he had to get out of this accursed hospital bed — but that wouldn't happen until he had healed to Madam Pomfrey's satisfaction.

"New plan," he said. "Bring the library to me."

o—o—o—o

"He asked for what?" McGonagall asked.

"He wants to borrow half the library," Madam Pince, the librarian, said calmly. "Said he didn't want to get behind in his studies, and that he would just start at A and work his way down to Z"

"Don't we have rules against this?" McGonagall asked.

"Well, frankly, it's never come up," said the librarian. "Until Hermione Granger, nobody ever took out more than a book or two at a time. Most students only read when they absolutely have no other option, and even then, generally only the Ravenclaws."

"Well… I feel we have no choice but to allow it, save, obviously, those in the Forbidden Section," McGonagall said. "Lest we encourage rule-breaking among the students by example. I'll allocate a few first-year Gryffindors to help transfer the books, I suppose. You owe me a favour, though, Irma."

The professors had started using Gryffindor's detention hours as the basis of a crude barter system. Snape had been selling them at a premium price, mostly to get out of his scheduled time patrolling the corridors of Hogwarts and dealing with Peeves. They were then re-sold between the professors in exchange for favours, assistance, and occasionally even money (the going rate three knuts per hour per student, well below what minimum wage would be if the wizarding world had a minimum wage). The students, of course, knew nothing of this.

o—o—o—o

"Scholar's Touch," Milo cast, and tapped a handful of books. He could read four per casting, and could cast the spell nine times. Mordy's head perked up as his brain, too, was flooded with information. Milo tossed the books into a rapidly-growing Finished pile, and reached for the top few books in the To Read pile, which was less of a pile and more of a small mountain. "Scholar's Touch, Scholar's Touch, Scholar's Touch, Scholar's Touch…"

o—o—o—o

The next morning, Milo was finally allowed out of the hospital wing. He was still under strict orders not to exert himself, and to avoid any undue stress. As a result, he was freed from the gruelling labour that the teachers were forcing the Gryffindors to undertake by way of detention. He walked, somewhat gingerly, down to the Great Hall for breakfast. As he entered, he made sure to affect an exaggerated limp and weak pace. He staggered towards the Hall, and pushed open the massive double-doors dramatically. He was deliberately a few minutes late, ensuring that the enormous chamber was more-or-less full, thus maximizing the impact.

o—o—o—o

Conversation in the room dimmed to a murmur as he walked silently down to the Gryffindor table, and sat down between Hannah and Ron.

"Hey," he said casually. "I miss anything?"

"Nice entrance," said Ron. "Though I think you were missing some sort of dramatic announcement, like 'that dragon won't bother us again anytime soon,' or possibly, 'the time has come.'"

"Everyone's a critic," Milo sighed.

"Don't be rude, Ron," Hannah said. "Or should I call Lavender back to have another little talk with you?"

Ron's face paled, and he fell silent. Hermione, Milo noticed, was very pointedly not speaking with Ron. Milo shrugged. The intricacies of most social interaction were lost on him, and they seemed largely pointless anyways.

"I want everyone to keep a careful eye on Malfoy," Milo said. "He's up to something, but I'm not sure what, yet."

"Sure thing, mate." Ron said as the owl post arrived. Milo questioned the hygiene of having a flock of owls flying in during breakfast every morning, but as he always ate from his perfectly-sterile Everlasting Rations anyways, he didn't mention anything. Also, owls? Seriously?

A particularly large package was delivered to Harry, carried by three owls working in unison.
"Oh, that reminds me," he said to the Gryffindors. "Anyone got a copy of the Daily Profit — sorry, Prophet — that I can borrow?" A flood of papers were offered to him immediately. Milo grinned. Celebrity had its perks, apparently. His newfound fame for defeating the acromantula apparently overshadowed the hatred for his losing 110 house points.

"Thanks," he said, grabbing one from some random NPC.

He looked at the cover, and nearly dropped it in surprise. Not because of the headlines, or even the content of the newspaper at all, but because the photo on the cover — of some smiling blond wizard being awarded a medal — was moving. Someone out there saw fit to cast some kind of spell, Milo wasn't even sure what would do this (some sort of Illusion, perhaps?) on every single one of these papers. Or, gods forbid, they were all magic items, each costing XP. If each newspaper cost even one Experience Point to make… Milo shuddered, imagining the soul-sucking factory needed to produce these tabloids, where wizards were dragged in en masse to be drained of the essence of their power, left a shallow husk of themselves.

Milo shook his head to clear his mind, and started scanning the headlines. Gringott's Break-in Still Unsolved… Nope, not that. Lockhart Saves Australia. Unrelated. Moody Stops Bicycle Theft, Takes No Prisoners. Nothing to do with him, certainly. Harry Potter Biography Hits Shelves, Shelves Hit Back. Apparently Flourish and Botts had attracted a malicious poltergeist. Nimbus Two Thousand Named Official Broom of Chudley Cannons. Yawn.

"Oh, by the way," Milo said as he read. "I found out what You-Know-Who is after."

"What?" Ron spluttered. "How?"

"Well, I cross-referenced everything on Harry's list with everything in the Hogwarts Library relating to extending one's life," he said. "And the Philospher's Stone is the only thing that appears in each. Nicolas Flamel was on the back of Dumbledore's chocolate frog card — which were invented in 1983 — back on the Hogwarts Express, which was, incidentally built in 1936, and he's the creator of the Stone."

"Why does it matter that he was on the card?" Harry asked.

"Well, something as important as the motives of the main villain would have been mentioned at least once by now by way of foreshadowing," Milo said. "Hells, you've probably been in the same room as the thing at least once and didn't even know it."

"Oh," said Hermione, sounding disappointed. "Here I'd hoped, against all reason, perhaps, that you'd finally found an ounce of sanity and logic."

"Mark my words," Milo said. "He's after the Stone — or he's a vampire."

"Well, if it's the stone he wants, we don't have anything to worry about," Hermione said. "Nicolas Flamel has it, and he's seven hundred years old. He's been able to keep it safe all this time, he must be pretty good at it. I mean, surely You-Know-Who isn't the first person to want to be immortal? I bet Flamel has to fight off dark wizards every other fortnight."

"Well, I'm glad that's settled," Harry said, cutting off Milo's reply. "Wait till you guys see what I got in the mail."

o—o—o—o

Harry was so excited he could hardly speak as they hurried to the Gryffindor common room to open his package. He skipped up the stairs two at a time, and blurted out the password to the Fat Lady so quickly he had to repeat it twice before she was satisfied.

"It's a Nimbus Two Thousand!" Harry exclaimed.

"Don't be daft, mate," Ron said. "Anyone who owned a Nimbus wouldn't just give it away."

"Oh, a broomstick," said Hermione. "Hooray."

"I had one of those, once," Milo said. "Stole it from a Death Eater I defeated. Dumbledore took it, though."

"Course you did, mate," said Ron condescendingly. "Course you did."

"Hey, Harry," Milo said. "Tell me something: why were you so excited to get this broomstick?"

"It's a Nimbus Two Thousand!" Harry said, practically shouting. "They're top-line racing brooms!"

"Right, right, but how do you know that?" Milo asked.

Harry frowned.

"I saw one in the shop in Diagon Alley," he said. "There was a crowd around it and everything."

"Ron, correct me if I'm wrong," Milo said to the redheaded boy, "but aren't there a number of top-line racing brooms out there?"

"Well, yeah, but the Nimbus is the best one," said Ron.

"Sure, but still — there'd be ones that are used by, I dunno, national sports teams that still far outstrip those used by Hogwarts players, and are maybe almost as good as the Nimbus?"

"Well, sure," Ron said thoughtfully. "There's the Comet Four-Eighty and it's hush-hush, but apparently Firebolt is working on something really fantastic."

"Yet none of those," Milo said with satisfaction, "were on Harry's list of notable items."

The four fell silent.

"There's a perfectly rational explanation," Hermione said. "McGonagall took Harry to Diagon Alley, remember? She must have seen it there."

Milo laughed.

"Of course there's a rational explanation, if you look closely enough. Still bears thinking about. Which is why we need to worry about this Philosopher's Stone. It just keeps popping up."

"When I was in Diagon Alley," Harry said excitedly. "Hagrid took us to a mysterious vault in Gringott's — and all that was in it was a tiny package! I bet it was the Stone!"

"Oh, come on," Hermione said. "That's just ridiculous — if it were the Stone, Dumbledore would have gone himself, surely. He's the only one Voldemort was ever scared of."

"But Gringott's was broken into that same day, but they didn't find what they were looking for!" Harry continued. "Remember, it was all over the news? They didn't find it — because Hagrid took it to Hogwarts!"

"Or, maybe they just couldn't find it — or they were after something else — or Gringott's vault security, famed in the world, it employs dragons after all, was too good for them," said Hermione with growing frustration.

"Wait, wait, wait — is Gringott's some sort of bank?" Milo asked.

All three of them gave him the usual look.

"If the security is so good, why is it overrun with goblins?" Milo asked.

"The goblins are the security, duffer," Ron said. "They run the bank. It's their bank. A goblin bank."

Milo couldn't take it anymore.

"This world is insane!" he shouted. "GOBLINS running a bank? Dragonhide gloves? TWELVE uses of dragon's blood? What are they, raised in farms? Elves — cooking, as servants? Wands? There's only one person in the entire country who makes your wands and he's just allowed to wander about! What if he trips and dies, or some evil git — what the Hells is a git, anyways — comes by and knifes him? What will you all do then? Also, broomsticks? If you're all wizards, why don't you just cast Fly? By Bigby, why don't you just cast Fly? You have infinite spells per day and you let goblins guard your gold! With dragons! More dragons! You have centaurs living in your forest — Centaurs. The only possible reason having four legs with hooves would be an advantage is if you were in the open plains! It's like... it's like someone who had only vaguely heard of real magic got all the words right but their meanings completely wrong!"

"You about done, mate?" Ron asked. "'Cause our magic is just as real. You see us using it every day, it's just a bit different from what you're used to."

"Yeah, I'm done. So. Your resident Dark Wizard is trying to get the Philosopher's Stone. The Stone is in Hogwarts. Dumbledore is guarding the stone, apparently, but just being in Hogwarts isn't guarding — guarding is guarding. He'd have to be sitting next to the thing, all day, every day, for it to be really safe. Seeing as how the other professors, perhaps with the exception of McGonagall, are either completely useless, dead, or downright evil, that leaves us."

"Leaves us for what?" Ron asked.

"When Voldemort — oh, shut up, Ron, it's just a name — makes his move, we have to stop him," Harry said quietly. "He killed my parents. He killed a lot of people's parents. We need a plan, though."

"I'd just like everyone to realize you have nothing remotely concrete," Hermione said. "The world doesn't work that way. You-Know-Who is dead. Flamel has the Philosopher's Stone. Professor Snape is stern and sometimes maybe a little unfair, but he's not evil. Until you can prove even one of those statements is wrong, you can do this without me. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have Transfiguration homework — as do you, in point of fact." With that, she stood up and strode out of the room.

"You know, she has a point," Ron said. "What we've got is a bit thin. Mind, Snape's evilness is pretty self-evident."

"Right, well, I think someone tried to kill me the other night," Milo said. "And even if I can't remember it happening, I'll find out how. Tomorrow, when I've got my spells back, I'm going back to the Forbidden Forest. Something's not right."

"The forest with the giant spiders, the werewolves — and I know it's not a full moon — the human-hating centaurs, the... that's actually all that I can remember, but I'm sure it's just the beginning," Ron said.

"Unicorns," Harry said. "What's killing the unicorns? And why?"

"Uh," Milo said. "I don't know, yet." Even Scholar's Touch had limitations — each one allowed him to read one book per level (so, four books, for those keeping score back home) but he could only cast so many per day. He resolved that from here on out, whenever he had extra spells remaining before going to bed, he was going to burn them on Scholar's Touch until he'd learned everything there was to know about this zany campaign setting. Seriously, he thought. This place makes Eberron look as familiar as Faerun. "But I can find out tomorrow — or maybe the day after."

"Right. Once you can prove it was Snape who tried to kill you — and come on, it totally was — then Hermione can help, and she probably already knows loads about unicorns and things we don't even know to look for," Harry said. "Meanwhile, Ron and I are going to try to find out everything we can about the Philosopher's Stone and Nicolas Flamel. He's a seven-hundred year-old wizard, right? I bet he's really famous. "

"Yeah," Ron said. "He was like, the Dumbledore of his day. I heard he's the one who trained Dumbledore — he might well be the most powerful wizard alive, really, if he hadn't retired. That kind of takes you out of the running, retirement."

o—o—o—o

Fortunately, the next day was Saturday, so Milo didn't have to worry about using his spells to bluff his way through classes. Instead, he prepared the same combat spells he did on the first trip into the forest, and set out. This time, there would be nobody to rescue him — so he went in the middle of the day, protected by his invisible Mage Armour.

"Locate Object: acromantula's corpse," he cast, swapping out Mirror Image. As far as the magic was concerned, a dead creature was an object (unless it was undead, of course).

"You know," he muttered to himself as he followed the path set out by the spell. "I think I've realized why I'm having so much trouble here. I was really designed to neutralize a horde of enemies so that Zook and the others can take them out with pointy sticks and things," he said. "My spell selection was never designed to win fights solo." Now that he thought about it, Milo realized he didn't have anything actually, you know, lethal. Just sort of annoying. "The other thing about this crazy world," he complained. "There's no Wizards. I mean, there's these people here who call themselves wizards, but they're really more like Warlocks gone wrong. But no proper Wizards." No Wizards meant he couldn't copy spells for any amount of money, which is why his selection was still so limited. Every level, all Wizards learned a mere two new spells from independent research.

"It's all so unfair," he muttered. "I have to re-invent the wheel every time I want to learn a new spell. Ah, here we are."

He turned a somewhat familiar corner and felt the angle of Locate Object change suddenly, meaning he was close. It all looked so different during the day, but there was the web-covered tree. He couldn't believe he hadn't noticed it during the night, there really was a lot of web everywhere.

He cautiously approached the remains of the monstrous spider. Were Milo a normal human, he would be repulsed by the smell — but, Milo's nose, like those of everyone from his world, only picks up on plot-sensitive scents. The rest are just assumed to be there, but not explicitly mentioned.

If Milo had thought that the acromantula would look less frightening during the light, he would have been wrong. It was enormous. His estimate of fifteen feet across was wrong — it was closer to twenty-five. Milo shuddered.

"A-ha!" he exclaimed. "That thing is way too large to have been killed by that little log I dropped," he said. The log weighed at most 400lbs, because that was as much as Levitate could carry, and only dropped twenty feet (the furthest he could raise it in the one round he had to do so) meaning it only did 2d6 damage. That's twelve, max, and if acromantulas (acromantulae?) are anything like the monstrous spiders back home then it should have had twenty-four hit points, minimum, but probably closer to fifty-two. "It should have shrugged that off and bitten me in half."

Milo frowned. There was more, too. Even if the spider was only CR 2, he should have had somewhere in the vicinity of 22 hp – and Milo only did, maximum, 12 damage. Actually, he added mentally, 15 with Acid Splash. But the odds of that happening are slim – only one in 108. He shouldn't have been able to even kill a CR 1 monstrous spider with all he did. And from what the people around here had been saying, acromantulas were dangerous. Really dangerous. From that alone, he would have thought that they were Challenge Rating four or more.

He moved closer to the body to investigate. It was, clearly, quite dead.

"So what happened to you, big guy? Were you already wounded? Expose the Dead," he cast, switching out Levitate. This was a spell the good people of Eberron had developed, but it had been carried to Milo's world by powerful spellcasters using Planeshift. He'd never actually seen it done before, and had no idea how to cast it, but Spontaneous Divination let him do it anyways. Best ability ever. Anyways — the spell gave him a gigantic bonus to searching crime scenes, and let him discover clues as if he were a trained professional. Some quick math told him that he'd have to be able to beat DC fifteen (easy, given his massive Intelligence and the bonus from the spell) to find a clue, if there was one, and then twenty-one to figure out any information from it. He frowned. It would take a twenty-six to find out everything he needed, and that was beyond him without more magical assistance.

"Master's Touch, Instant Search," he cast, this time in favour of Grease and Glitterdust, respectively. He was starting to worry that he would run out of spells before he was done. The spells together gave him another +6 to search.

Details of the spider's corpse, more than he really wanted to know in point of fact, suddenly appeared in his mind as if he'd diligently investigated the body.

Aside from a few long-since healed scars on its side and face, a sprained ankle (do spiders have ankles?), minor acid burning and 400lb of tree sitting on its back, the spider was in perfect health – except that it was missing one of its fangs.

"Well," Milo said triumphantly. "This explains everythi– wait a minute, no it doesn't. Can acromantulas shoot fangs? Why didn't I feel it? I know I didn't take any damage." Milo was aware, at any given time, how many hit points he had. "Well," he said. "You weren't a wounded high-CR monster, or I would have found the other injuries. You weren't CR 1, or I would have gotten less Experience Points. You weren't weak to acid, or there would be more serious burns. There is only one possible conclusion... and it changes everything," he said, pausing dramatically for the scene to change.

Chapter 8: Sidequests

The antidote, as it turned out, was harmless. That didn't stop Milo from buffing himself up with a Resistance spell and keeping his Antitoxin on hand before taking his dosage, however. Despite the fact that, aided by Snape's potion, Milo recovered from the after-effects of his poisoning fairly quickly, the rest of Autumn at Hogwarts was, well, unpleasant.

Harry and Ron made absolutely no progress in their hunt for information about the Philosopher's Stone among the teachers, and for such a powerful and famous artifact, Milo could barely find anything about it in the Hogwarts Library. He Scholar's Touch-ed his way through mountains of thick, dusty tomes without even opening their covers, and while he learned a lot of apparently useless information, there was little that seemed relevant to him. Scholar's Touch didn't grant any special powers to aid in memorization, so the fact that he 'read' the books so rapidly actually made it harder to keep his facts straight. Still, he reckoned he'd absorbed enough general setting information that he could start making Knowledge (History) checks about this world.

It was during this period that Milo noticed something unnatural about the people here. The more he watched them learn, the less he was sure that they were even human at all—they looked human, sure, but...

Well, to start, there was the food. The people here were obsessed with it, and kept comparing the various flavours of dishes that the house-elves cooked up for them (Milo was dying to meet one of the elves here, he was sure they could help him. Elves were annoying, sure, but the pointy-eared pansies and magic went hand in hand). Some even developed favourite foods and avoided certain ones altogether. To Milo, food was a logistical challenge to be overcome while adventuring and a source of danger if it ran low (thus, the Everlasting Rations, which were all that Milo ever ate). The actual taste of food was something that only came up in plot-relevant situations – like smell, and the weather. The people of Milo's world only smelled things when they were important, like a Troglodyte's stench or a potential clue (or red herring, for that matter). Otherwise, why bother even mentioning it?

Another peculiarity in these people was the inordinate amount of down time they required. Milo had to spend eight hours sleeping and an hour memorizing spells, but that left fifteen hours a day to put to use attending class, fighting monsters, and crafting items off-screen. Milo knew an Artificer by the name of Alton who, when he finally got his hands on a Ring of Sustenance, spent two hours sleeping, eight hours crafting magic items (the maximum amount per day) and the other fourteen hours in a day mass-producing baskets to fund his adventuring. Alton did that every day for three hundred years straight, with breaks to fight monsters to recover lost Experience Points, until he'd amassed a fortune large enough to attract the attention of a wandering Blue Dragon. Alton's unfortunate demise aside, it was just good sense to put their hours to use—they were only given twenty-four in a day, after all. And besides, manual labour was the sort of thing done during a timeskip, anyways, it's not like it got in the way of the story. Even Hermione seemed shocked by the amount of time he spent reading and working. In just one week, Milo managed to custom-tailor his fifth-hand Hogwarts uniform (untrained, but with +2 for masterwork tools (which Milo also made himself) and +4 from his Intelligence) until it rivalled Draco's in quality, read more books than any of his classmates (save Hermione) could in a year, and carve holy symbols of Pelor, Heironeous, St. Cuthbert, and Boccob into key locations around Gryffindor Tower. That had earned him some strange looks, despite the fact that the residents there were fully aware that there were vampires on the same continent as them. That was all in addition to the daily chores all first year Gryffindors were required to do as punishment for trying to kill or maim the Slytherins back in September. Milo theorized that, while he had to spend an hour poring over his spellbook, performing arcane research, and memorizing spells every morning, the Wizards here had to spend at four to eight hours a day (judging by comparisons between Hermione and Ron, it was an amount of time equal to eight minus their Intelligence Bonus, in hours per day) sitting around on armchairs and talking about the weather.

But that wasn't the really weird thing. The more Milo watched these students in their classes, the harder a time he had sleeping at night. The way they were learning was wrong. It was oh, so, incredibly wrong. Ordinary people learned in discrete increments: they levelled up, their powers, skills, and abilities increased, and then they plateaued until attaining enough Experience Points to go up another level. It was just obvious. That was, intuitively, the way everyone—humans, elves, dwarves, kobolds, mindflayers, small fluffy hamsters, everyone—learned.

Watching his fellow Gryffindors, Milo wondered, though it seemed impossible, if their skills didn't develop gradually. There seemed to be a slow, constant growth in magical ability, historical knowledge, broomstick skills, or whatever, that depended on that student's particular aptitude in that area. Hermione, for example, was the fastest to learn in Defence Against the Dark Arts, Charms, Transfiguration, Potions, Herbology, Astrology... actually, pretty much all of their classes except for Broomstick Flying (which went to Harry, who was also, to be fair, pretty close to even Hermione in Defence), and History of Magic (to Milo's intense embarrassment, it was the only class he seemed to be doing any good in, and even that was only as a result of his supersonic library binge).

That wasn't to say that Milo was completely useless in class, it was just... he had to wait and hope that whichever particular Charm (this world had a totally different definition of Charm than Milo's, which caused him no end of confusion) they were about to learn was fairly close to his limited repertoire of spells so he could fake his way through. If it wasn't... well, having to be helped by Neville Longbottom when attempting to learn the Cutting Charm was somewhat embarrassing. Transfiguration wasn't too bad. He managed to get by, to a certain extent, with using Prestidigitation to change the colour and, on one memorable occasion, taste of the object he was attempting to transfigure. He started out ahead, but now he was barely scraping a A (which stood for Acceptable, and was counter-intuitively, the lowest passing grade) but if he didn't get some new spells soon, he'd slip into P (for Poor) territory with alacrity. Charms was going distressingly poorly until Flitwick announced they'd be learning how to levitate objects. Milo simply cast Levitate quietly then said "Wingardium Leviosa" with the rest of them, and astonished the class and earned him five House Points by lifting an entire table, complete with Neville (who had been leaning against it and grabbed one of the legs in a panic as it started to float away) and lowering it back down again.

Defence Against the Dark Arts was kind of pointless. Quirrell, for all the mystery surrounding him, didn't seem to care whatsoever about teaching. What they did learn was mostly limited to dealing with magical household pests. Milo was forced to wonder what the Muggles did when confronted with a Bowtruckle in their trees, or if the magical creatures had an inbuilt sense of decency and fair play, and as a result only targeted humans carrying wands. Milo caused quite a stir when he suggested the best way to deal with vampires was to impair them with Webs, Glitterdust, and Grease so that your non-spellcaster allies can take them out with wooden stakes.

"You would bring Muggles with you?" Quirrell had asked, sounding genuinely shocked.

"Well, sure. You don't see many a Wizard pumping irons or practicing hand-to-hand combat, now do you? Deck 'em out in full plate, give 'em a pointy stick, and point 'em in the right direction." It was incredible. They seemed to never have heard of the concept of a meat shield, and even the Slytherins were shocked and appalled when he attempted to educate them. That there was something morally questionable about sending the heavily armoured, greataxe-wielding barbarian with mighty thews out front to soak up damage had never occurred to Milo. It seemed to him that the wizards here were remarkably selfish, never giving a thought to how their nonmagical allies would feel when the spellcasters hogged all the glory and XP with their vastly superior powers.

Broomstick lessons, however, were dreadful. Milo had come to the conclusion that the broomsticks weren't actually magical at all, but that the local wizards had a spell or class feature that let them animate certain broomsticks (probably with a specific cost requirement, which is why they didn't use ordinary cleaning mops) for flight. Milo, not having said spell or perk, was completely unsuccessful at making the thrice-damned stick float, and finally gave up and Levitated the accursed thing. This let him go up and down, but to move horizontally he had to awkwardly kick off of walls and objects. He felt like a six-year-old who'd accidentally been signed up for swimming lessons for eight-year-olds, and was desperately trying to dog paddle around the room while everyone else was demonstrating backstrokes.

The worst, the absolute worst, was Potions. Snape seemed to go out of his way to make Harry's life as miserable as possible, which was annoying, but the concerning thing was how he always kept a very close eye on Milo. The thing was, the potions didn't work. He chopped up the ingredients exactly how the book suggested and made sure to turn the spoon clockwise three times and counterclockwise one-and-a-half times, or whatever, but nothing happened. Even Neville's potions occasionally exploded, or melted, or screamed, or caught fire, or in one case got up and ran out of the room blabbering about the Kennedy Assassination. But Milo's potions, though Milo would bet his spellbook he was doing everything right, were just water with stuff floating in them. Whenever one of Harry's potions failed catastrophically, Snape would deduct house points and scold him, but whenever he noticed that Milo's was use-impaired (Milo was hesitant to call them useless, because they could still be, and frequently were, employed to put out fires) Snape just smiled to himself and made a note in the compact, leather-bound notebook he carried about his person.

It was that evening that Milo learned about Hallowe'en.

"So, what are you going as?" Hannah Abbot asked him. She seemed to enjoy sitting next to him at meals for some inexplicable reason. Milo only bothered to go to the Great Hall for dinner (as opposed to munching on Everlasting Rations in his dorm) because he'd noticed a correlation between mealtimes there and having important conversations.

Milo blinked in surprise. Being knocked out of a timeskip was rather like spending the whole day reading a good book, then remembering you had a party to go to, but the book was so good that you read it the whole way on the bus and were completely distracted and absent-minded all evening, until you hear someone say your name from the other side of the room, and snap. Broken out of your reverie, just like that.

"Sorry, say that again?" Milo asked. "I was distracted."

"I was just asking what you were going to dress up for on Hallowe'en," Hannah asked.

"No, that still doesn't make any sense. What's Hallowe'en?"

Hannah blinked, shook her head slightly, and blinked again. She looked like someone had just asked her what a Natural 20 was.

"You don't even know? Everyone knows what Hallowe'en is!" she exclaimed.

Milo sighed.

"Look, I've been over this. I wasn't raised by wizards, etcetera etcetera, fill me in?"

"No, but even Muggles know about Hallowe'en!" Hannah said.

"I'm not from around here, remember?" Milo reminded her.

"Well, I guess, it's a holiday where everyone dresses up as monsters and goes around taking candy from strangers," Hannah said. "Which always confused me a little, because that's exactly what me mum is always reminding me not to do."

"I see," Milo said. "that seems... terribly mundane, actually. Surely I didn't get pulled out of compressed time for that?" Milo frowned. "Harry," Milo said, turning to his left, "is Hallowe'en written on your list, anywhere?"

"Ah, lemme check," Harry said, and flipped through his lengthy list of notes. "Nope, not at all."

"Try All Hallows' Eve," Hermione suggested, "and Samhain."

"Hey, I thought you weren't helping?" Ron pointed out.

"I'm not," she said defensively. "I'm just... advising. Oh, and Harry, try just looking for October Thirty-First."

"Advising is helping. And of course Hallowe'en is significant for Harry," Ron said. "Everyone knows—oh, right, sorry. I forgot. Anyway, it's the day that Harry defeated You-Know-Who ten years ago."

"You mean, the day when my parents..." Harry sighed.

"Uhm. Right. Sorry," Ron said apologetically.

"Still don't see what's important about that," Milo said. Hermione shot him a look that could curdle milk, nodding slightly towards Harry. "I mean, aside from, you know, being tragic. Just tragic. Uh. Terrible, that is. Tragic and terrible."

"Don't worry about it," Harry said quietly.

"Oh, phew." Milo said, relieved, before moving on to what he saw as more pressing issues. "Anyways. Tenth anniversary of You-Know-Who's alleged demise? Dumbledore doesn't look very concerned," Milo said, nodding to the eccentric Headmaster at the Head Table, "meaning there was nothing about it in the Prophecy."

"Wait, what Prophecy?" Hermione asked.

"There's always a Prophecy, Hermione," Milo rolled his eyes. "Everyone knows that."

"Point for his side," Ron muttered.

"I hadn't realized we were keeping score," Hermione said sharply.

"We're Quidditch players," Ron said nodding to Harry, "we always keep score."

"So, when's this Hallowe'en thing?" Milo asked.

"October Thirty-First," Hannah supplied. "Tomorrow."

"Hermione," Milo said. "If I'm right, and something dramatic does happen tomorrow evening, will you admit that I'm right, that Snape is evil, that the Philosopher's Stone is involved—that it's maybe even at Hogwarts, in or about the clearly relevant third floor corridor—that You-Know-Who isn't really dead, and that... wait, was there something else? No, I think that's about it. Anyway, will you?"

"Nope," Hermione said simply. "Because there is absolutely no correlation between any of those events. Say, tomorrow, the Chamber of Secrets is opened and Muggleborns start dying. There's no connection between that and You-Know-Who being alive. If You-Know-Who is alive, that's absolutely no reason to think that Snape is, quote, evil. If Snape is evil, that's no reason to think the Philosopher's Stone is in Hogwarts. Unless Snape releases Slytherin's Monster to use as a distraction so he can get the Stone to bring You-Know-Who back to life. That would make perfect sense, actually. Can the Philospher's Stone do that?"

"The great Hermione Granger, asking a question?" Milo laughed. "Well, mine can. That is, Philosopher's Stones' from my universe can bring back the dead –"

"What?" Harry asked quietly. "Really?"

"Sure," said Milo. "Of course, any old Cleric can do the same for a few gold pieces and some diamond powder, so I don't really see what the big deal is."

Harry choked on his food.

"Wh-wh-what?" he asked.

"Raise Dead, Resurrection, True Resurrection, Reincarnate, Revivify, Miracle, and Wish," Milo said, ticking off his fingers as he listed the spells, "are all spells that can bring back the dead, to name a few."

"Y-you can bring the dead back to life?" Harry asked.

"Me? Ha! Boccob, No. It's really more Divine spellcaster territory. I think, but I'd have to do a little research to be sure, that Wizards have to use Wish to do it, and it's really powerful magic. Demands a huge sacrifice of Experience, and in any case it's way beyond my abilities."

"Oh," said Harry, looking crestfallen.

"Milo," Hermione said acidly, "You and I will have words about this later. You're going to have to learn some tact one of these days, even if I have to shove it down your throat at wandpoint."

"Point for her side," Ron said.

"Oh, shuttup. So the Philospher's Stone can bring back the dead?" Hermione asked.

"What? Oh, haha, no. Yours can't, anyways. From what I found in the library, it just turns stuff into gold and lets you live forever."

"Well, that's a—ah. Nevermind," Hermione said, glancing at Harry.

"That's a what, Hermione?" Harry asked.

"Well, it means You-Know-Who can't come back, so it's kind of a..."

"A relief, isn't it? That the Stone can't bring back the dead?" Harry pushed.

"Yes, if you must know, that's what I was going to say. But that was before I thought about it, and stopped myself, because I didn't initially think it through the whole way."

"Fair enough," Harry said.

"I think I missed something there," Ron admitted quietly to Milo.

"Hermione was about to say it was a relief that the Philosopher's Stone can't bring back the dead, but right now Harry's thinking about his parents," Milo explained in a whisper, "so she was as good as saying it'd be worth it that we couldn't bring back Harry's folks, as well as anyone else decent who'd died, just to keep You-Know-Who down."

"Let's try to stay on topic, okay?" Harry asked.

"Right. Sorry," Hermione apologised.

"Forget it. What should we do about tomorrow?" Harry wondered.

"Tell a professor," Hermione shrugged.

"We can't very well go up to McGonagall and say, 'excuse me, Professor, tomorrow's Hallowe'en and Milo's Spidey Sense is tingling so can you lock down the school, just to be sure?' she'd think we were nuts, for sure," Harry said.

"What's a Spidey Sense?" Ron asked.

Harry suppressed a grin.

"Blimey! You don't even know what the Spider-Sense is? Everyone knows that! It's Spider-Man's ability to sense danger before it happens," Harry said. "How on Earth did you become eleven years old and not know that?"

"Point for his side," Hermione smirked. "But Harry makes a good point. The reason it sounds crazy is because it still is crazy."

"You're too hung up on actual, you know, facts, Hermione," Milo said. "Just be on your toes tomorrow, okay? That goes for everyone," Milo added.

"In all seriousness, what could I possibly do, even on my toes?" Hermione asked. "Use the Levitating Charm to save the day? Transfigure up some sewing needles? I've only been a Witch for two months. I'll stay inside the castle tomorrow, not that I have much choice, because someone got us all a full year of detention. Aside from that, I don't know about you, but I'm going to enjoy Hallowe'en in family tradition, passed down the Granger line for generations: by revising and doing homework. Exams are only eight months away, after all." She sighed, a slightly dreamy expression coming over her, "I do so love Hallowe'en. Which brings me to the matter at hand: Harry, Ron, and I have to go now."

"What?" asked Harry.

"What?" asked Ron.

"I said that already," said Harry.

"Yeah, but, I was confused, too, right?" said Ron.

"I just don't think it added much, is all. It was, what's it called... redundant."

"I think it's considered polite to say learning disabled now, actually," said Ron primly, "and I don't care for your tone at all."

Hermione coughed.

"Right. Why were we leaving, Hermione?" Harry asked.

"For a very important thing that we have to do far over there," she said, pointing frantically to the far corner of the Great Hall. "You know? The thing?"

"Uh, nope, Hermione, sorry," Ron said. "I think you've lost a marble or ten. I have no idea what you're talking about."

"Oh, just get up and walk, Weasley, Potter, or I swear I'll... I'll... I'll think of something," she threatened. "and mark my words: I am very good at thinking of things. Very, very good. Bwa, ha, ha."

"Did you just say Bwa ha ha?" Harry asked.

"Pardon," Hermione said. "I appear to have caught the hiccups."

"Only that didn't sound like a hiccup," Ron said. "It was more of a, you know, evil laugh, sort of thing."

"Nope, it was a hiccup. What would an eleven year old girl be doing laughing evilly? I hiccupped. I even covered my mouth and everything."

"Only... only, aren't you twelve?" asked Ron.

"Ron, mate," Harry whispered. "I think we should just go with her. It's less painful that way."

"Fine," Ron muttered, and they stood up and walked away. Hermione kept glancing surreptitiously back at Milo and Hannah.

"Well," Milo said, taking a bite out of his Everlasting Rations. "That was... weird."

"Yeah, kinda," Hannah agreed evasively. "Anyway, about Hallowe'en tomorrow...?"

o—o—o—o

"He thinks he's so clever," Malfoy sneered. "He has no idea what's coming to him."

"Yeah!" said Crabbe (or Goyle).

"Right!" said Goyle (or Crabbe, but you get the idea, right?)

"After the last one, he acted like he didn't care, but you could tell. Oh, man, you could tell, if you looked close. Real close," Malfoy said. "I got him, like, right to the core. Just wish I saw him read the paper."

"Yeah, we got him deep down," said Crabbe.

"Yeah, we got him so deep you'd need a Bubble-Head Charm to swim down there to see," said Goyle.

"Yeah, so deep you'd die from the pressure," said Crabbe.

"Okay, guys. Seriously, stop that," said Malfoy. "You aren't helping."

"Yeah, you're not helping, Goyle," said Goyle. Wait, Crabbe. Said Crabbe. Phew, close call.

"Yeah, you're just making things worse, Crabbe," said Goyle.

Draco rolled his eyes.

"This time," Draco said, "this time, it'll get him so bad he won't even be able to hide it. He'll be begging for mercy. And you know what I'll do then?"

"Relent, as he's seen the error of his ways, and demonstrate your kind, forgiving personality?" suggested Goyle.

"Relent, and buy him a puppy," said Crabbe. "A fluffy one. So he doesn't feel so bad about losing."

Draco gave them a peculiar look. Seriously, what was with these two?

"Nah, I'll kick 'im!" he cackled.

"Yeah!" said Crabbe.

"Yeah!" added Goyle, not wanting to feel left out. Goyle frowned, which made his forehead looked a little like Mount Etna would if it collapsed – slowly – and said, "So, boss, what's the plan?"

"The plan? You want to know the plan?"

"Yeah, boss, so's we can help," said Crabbe.

"Yeah, boss, so's we can... know the plan," said Goyle.

"I'll tell you the plan! It'll all go down tomorrow," Draco said. "Do you know what day it is tomorrow?"

"Uh," said Crabbe. "Thursday?"

"No!" shrieked Malfoy. "Well, actually, yes. Tomorrow is Thursday. But that's not what's important!"

"Uh," said Goyle. "Friday?"

"No!" shrieked Malfoy. "Wait... what? Look, Goyle, I just said that tomorrow is Thursday. Surely even you... I mean, really?"

"Well, you also said it wasn't what was important, so I thought, maybe the important thing about tomorrow is that, while it's Thursday, it's really Friday. You know?"

"Uh," said Malfoy. "No... not... really..." he frowned. "Look, guys, we're getting off topic. It's not about the day of the week, okay?"

"Oh! Oh! I love this game," said Goyle. "Is it smaller than a breadbox?"

"Uh. Well, kinda, I guess, in an abstract sort of sense, tomorrow is bigger than a breadbox... wait, no! We're not playing Twenty Questions! Just... just... just guess, okay? It's like, really obvious. Here's a hint, even. Today's the Thirtieth of October, so tomorrow is..."

"Friday!" said Crabbe.

"You're fired. You're both fired."

"The Thirty-First!" said Goyle.

"Yes!" Malfoy resisted, barely, the temptation to fist-pump. "And what happens every year on October Thirty-First?"

"Hallowe'en!" said Crabbe.

"NO! Well, actually, yeah, again, kinda. But once again, you're right but completely wrong! Tomorrow morning is the Northwestern Regional Semi-Finals for the UK Quidditch League!"

"Bwa ha ha!" Crabbe cackled.

"Mwa ha ha!" Goyle cackled, too.

o—o—o—o

"I'm confused," Ron admitted.

"Well, there's a surprise. Look," Milo explained, "a sidequest is a short adventure at most tangentially related to the major events of the story used primarily for character development."

"Character development?" asked Ron.

"Yeah. Getting hauls of XP, magic items, and gold, and thus making your character more powerful, or developed. Character development."

Harry frowned. "Look, unlike you two, I actually went to primary school, and I'm fairly certain that's not actually what character development means."

"Irregardless," Milo began.

"Not a word," Harry muttered.

"Says the boy on the Quidditch team. Anyways, regardless — there, happy? — of the meaning of character development, sidequests are brief excursions, more focussed on a single idea, generally simpler, and also where most of the best loot comes from."

"And that's why you're going on a date with the cute blonde?" asked Fred (or George, but we're not starting this again, okay?).

"Not a date. A sidequest," corrected Milo. He, Ron, Harry, and the Weasley twins were sitting in a corner in the Common Room. Milo had planned to co-ordinate his Hallowe'en schedule with them, so that they'd all know where the others would be at any given time (for when, inevitably, disaster struck) but the conversation had taken an unexpected turn when he'd filled them in on his conversation with Hannah.

"On a secluded, dare I say, private walk around the Hogwarts lake," said George, "where, being right out in the open, of course, everyone can see you."

"Yeah. An adventure past a body of water filled to the brim with monsters of every sort," said Milo.

"Ah, I see," Fred said knowingly. "So you can protect the fair maiden, eh?"

"Well, if I have to. She's a witch, though, should be more than competent at defending herself."

"I think, Fred," said George, "that he's not really getting into the spirit of things."

"I'm forced to agree, George," said Fred.

"She said she wanted to talk to me alone for a while," Milo shrugged. "So I just assumed she had some critical information she has to pass along, or possibly a magic item. For all I know, she'll give me a quest."

"Maybe she has some sensitive information, if you know what I... ah, nevermind, you know?" said Fred.

"Yeah, it's just not working. He seems to be immune to teasing," admitted George. "Such a shame."

"A missed opportunity."

"A wasted chance."

"A moment passed, never to return."

"Such a shame."

"No, we actually said that one, already," said Fred.

"Ah, nuts," said George. "And here I was, getting all Zen."

"Well, one way or another," Fred said, "I think you're going to have a very interesting Hallowe'en."

o—o—o—o

Quirrell paced back and forth irritably in his office. He just had to think. There must be some way to get rid of that boy... how did he know? How could he possibly know that the Dark Lord was returning? Dumbledore must have told him, Quirrell thought. No... that explains nothing. How could Dumbledore himself know?

And the boy had just told him. He'd just come out and said it was obvious. Obvious! To anyone with half a brain! He'd even named his three friends as accomplices... Was it a trap? A test of some sort? Perhaps the boy had been bluffing, trying to gauge Quirrell's reaction?

Irregardless, it didn't matter. The boy had to die. Snape would make things difficult, though... he seemed to know, somehow. The only times the accursed Potions Master isn't watching the boy, Quirrell thought, he's watching me. He must be trying to protect the boy... they're all in it together. That's what they were doing out in the forest... Snape went out to meet Milo in the Forbidden Forest, to discuss how to stop me. It's too much of a coincidence to be anything else. They must think they're so clever, but if they were really clever they wouldn't have let me notice. No, they weren't half as sneaky as they thought. Well, it'll all happen tomorrow, if everything goes according to plan... No. No, there's no if about it.

"A Power He Knows Not..." Quirrell heard the horrible, hissing voice say behind him.

"W-w-what was that, Master?"

"Nothing that need concern you," the voice lashed out at him, like a cobra. Then the pain started.

It would be a long night for Quirrell.

Chapter 10: Odds of Survival

Author's Notes: Hallowe'en was originally going to be a three-part chapter, but it's stretched out to four parts now (I had way too much fun with this). Thanks to all of my readers! My inbox is flooded with hundreds of fanfiction subscription and favourite alerts, which make me very, very happy indeed.

And remember: if you like it, review it! I try to read them all.

o—o—o—o

"So, if it wasn't Draco who poisoned Neville," Harry asked Milo as they sat down at their Defence Against the Dark Arts desks, "who was it?" Harry had been trying to get Milo to speak throughout their whole History of Magic class, but Hermione kept shushing him (talking in History carried across the whole room, not that the ghost of Binns noticed or apparently cared).

"I don't know, yet," Milo confessed. "But there's one thing I do know."

"What's that?" Harry asked.

"It was someone on your list," Milo said. "Adding a whole new character now who poisoned Neville would ruin any element of mystery. It has to be someone we met in the first two adventures."

"Just once, you're going to use logic based on actual facts," said Hermione primly, "and all the trees on Earth will wither and die."

The class filed in gradually in groups of two or three. Quirrell's course was basically a joke, so punctuality wasn't exactly a top priority for most students—Quirrell hardly ever deducted House Points for tardiness. The Gryffindors were marginally more excited today than usual, because rumour had it that Quirrell had been preparing something special for today, it being Hallowe'en and all.

"I-I-I-I've been p-p-p-preparing s-something sp-sp-special for t-today," Quirrell announced when the last of the students arrived, "it being H-Hallowe'en and all—or, as s-s-some n-now call it, Harry P-P-Potter Day." There was, Milo thought he noticed, a hint of a sneer in Quirrell's voice. Milo had to agree with Quirrell: Harry Potter Day was a pretty silly name, especially compared to something as cool as 'All Hallow's Eve.' Quirrell was standing in front of something massive and mostly rectangular, covered by a sheet of canvas.

Harry muttered something under his breath.

"Sorry, what was that?" Hermione whispered quietly.

"Should be Lily and James Potter Day," Harry answered simply. "I don't even remember it."

"B-b-but before we b-begin," Quirrell said, "I'd l-like to ask y-y-young M-M-Milo something," Milo perked up as he heard his name. "I'd heard th-that you've b-b-been losing a g-great deal of the n-n-noble House G-Gryiffindor's P-P-Points lately," he said across the classroom. There were a few chuckles, and a number of angry looks. "I-I-I was w-w-wondering if y-y-you m-m-might like an opportunity to earn s-s-some b-back?"

Whatever could have possessed a person with a crippling stutter to get a job which required lecturing large groups of people on a daily basis escaped Milo. Milo shrugged.

"Sure," he said. "Anything for the House, after all. Have to win the House Medal and all that."

"Cup," Ron whispered.

"Cup Medal, that is." Milo corrected himself, wondering what Quirrell was getting at.

"Excellent," Quirrell said. "C-c-come see m-me after c-c-class, then."

Milo nervously ran his fingers through his hair. Was there anyone who wasn't going to want to see him this evening? This was something of an opportunity, though—Milo could just go to whatever Quirrell's thing was, then let him deal with the fallout from Snape. If anyone can stand up to Snape, Milo thought, it's Quirrell. I like the cut of his jib.

Quirrell's 'something special' for Hallowe'en turned out to be rather awesome, in the sense that it was something that evoked awe.

"A-and w-w-without further ado," Quirrell stammered excitedly to the class, "allow m-m-me to p-p-present my H-H-Hallowe'en surprise!" With a dramatic flourish, he pulled off the tarp, revealing, as it turned out, a cage of monstrous proportions. The bars were made of thick steel wrapped in unpleasant-looking razor wire. Hanging from the cage was an almost cartoonishly-oversized lock, though Milo was certain that there were likely layers of Abjurations protecting the cage not visible to the naked eye. The cage emanated an entirely non-magical aura of immobility and intimidation. Nothing short of the Tarrasque itself was getting out of that cage. It wasn't the cage, however, that caused the collective gasp of fear from the Gryffindors—the house noted for its bravery—but what lay inside.

"Blimey," said Ron quietly. "It's a Troll."

"A Giant," Milo corrected.

"Right," Ron whispered. "A Giant Troll."

Milo sighed. The brute inside was very clearly a Giant. Trolls, unlike Giants, were green and sort of... weirdly proportioned, with long dangly limbs and spiky black hair. This was obviously some non-core species of Giant—simple enough to prove with a dagger, as only Trolls could regenerate.

"Th-th-this is a T-T-Troll," Quirrell stammered to the class, "The G-Groundskeeper and I c-caught it in the F-F-Forb-Forb... in the Forest. It appears to have b-b-been h-harassing the unicorns."

"Excuse me, Professor," asked a Gryffindor NPC (probably Seamus) "I thought that was werewolves?"

"W-werewolves aren't f-f-fast enough," said Quirrell. And they're only active on full moons, Milo thought irritably. I mean, seriously. What's the one defining characteristic of a werewolf? It turns into a wolf on the full moon.Only the full moon. Sheesh. "And T-T-Trolls, b-believe me, are f-faster than they l-l-look. N-now, there's n-n-no need to w-worry about the T-T-Troll getting out," he continued, "as this c-cage is very n-nearly indestructible. The w-w-wire you see is, in addition to b-b-being very sh-sharp, b-bewitched to entangle a-anyone trying to g-g-get out. A-a-anyone who t-t-touches the lock w-without the k-key—kept in the H-H-Headmaster's Office—will be struck by a F-F-Full Body B-B-Bind and trigger an a-alarm. The b-b-bars themselves are Goblin-made, and c-can withstand anything short of D-D-Dragonfire. There are a f-f-few other s-s-surprises as w-w-well. Q-quite f-f-fortunate we h-had it on h-h-hand, in f-f-fact. N-n-now, who c-c-can tell me w-w-what Trolls eat?"

Quirrell continued into a detailed lecture (in fact, significantly more detailed than his usual lectures, which were generally considered 80-minute long naptimes. Everyone's had at least one teacher like him) about Trolls. He seemed quite enthusiastic on the subject, not unlike a Fighter asked about pointy sticks.

As the class came to a close and three o'clock approached, Quirrell dismissed the rest of the students a little early to enjoy their Hallowe'en evenings.

"M-M-Milo?" Quirrell asked. Right, he wanted me to stay after. Almost forgot about that.

"So," Milo said as he walked towards the alleged Troll. "What can I do you for?"

"Th-this fellow," Quirrell said, pointing to the monstrous humanoid in the cage. "W-we have to m-m-move him t-to the d-d-dungeons until the M-M-Ministry can d-deal with him."

Milo sized up the brute.

"Ah," he said. "Look, I know they say I'm good at Levitating things, but this..."

"Oh, d-d-don't worry," said Quirrel. "The c-cage is S-Self Levitating. H-however, it's e-easiest to p-p-push it from the b-b-back," he said, pointing to a small area on the cage not covered in razor-sharp wire, "but then I c-can't see where I'm g-g-going. So, if you could p-p-push it, I can l-l-lead? H-H-Hagrid helped me b-bring it here, b-but he's b-b-busy now."

"Sounds like a design flaw to me," Milo said. "But sure, I can lend a hand."

Quirrell smiled. There was no warmth whatsoever in his expression. Milo gave the cage a light push, and it drifted in front of him with surprisingly little effort. He was reminded of his brief adventure with Neville that morning, pushing the cage after Quirrell. The Giant inside seemed more perplexed than frightening as Milo guided the cage down the ever-shifting hallways of Hogwarts, only half paying attention to his surroundings. Quirrell was right—it really was impossible to see from behind this brute. Every so often, Quirrell called out a direction to him. Milo wondered briefly why Hogwarts had such a cage—it looked reasonably new, and could likely hold something quite a bit bigger than its current occupant—before remembering who the residents of the Forbidden Forest were.

"So," Milo asked, more to make conversation than anything, "this is who we were looking for in the forest?"

"L-l-looks like," Quirrell said from the other side of the cage. "H-H-Hagrid caught him covered in u-u-unicorn blood. W-w-we'll know f-f-for sure if the u-u-unicorns stop d-d-disappearing."

"Go figure," Milo said. "I sort of thought it would have been one of the Death Eaters, or Snape."

"W-w-why?" asked Quirrell.

"Isn't it obvious? Well, we know You-Know-Who is returning, right? But he's supposed to have died, and you guys don't have Clerics or Wish."

"Clerics? Wish?" Quirrell asked.

"Where I come from, death is pretty cheap. Well, not cheap, exactly, but with enough diamonds and the right spellcaster, pretty much anyone can be brought back from the dead in some form. Clerics are the best at it by far, but a Wizard like me can pull it off, too, with some difficulty." Milo explained.

"You can do this? You can bring back the dead?" Quirrell asked sharply.

"Not yet, but maybe in a few years at this rate. Unlike back home, there's only a few methods available to you people for cheating death that I could find in the Hogwarts Library—Scholar's Touch is so broken!—and those methods were as follows: Flamel's Stone, Unicorn's Blood, and becoming a vampire."

"Go on," Quirrell urged.

"In order of preference, the order is probably the Stone first, then the blood, and lastly becoming a vampire. There wasn't much I could find on any of these subjects—they're probably in the forbidden areas in the library, or books written by authors whose names start with letters after F—but from what I can tell, there's no mention of a cure for Vampirism, so it'd be a last resort. All I could find about the unicorns was that whoever drank their blood would be cursed to living a 'half-life,' which is cryptic as a crypt tick but sounds at least halfway better than total unlife."

"So, why not simply assume he's after the Stone?"

"Oh, he is, of course. Dumbledore's supposedly guarding it, but there's about a million and a half problems with that —he runs a school, and he's chief whatever of the thingamajig, and Supreme Muggle of the other thing. He can't be on guard twenty-four hours a day like an orc in a ten-by-ten room guarding a treasure chest. So in practice, the staff of Hogwarts are defending it, and while Dumbledore is this legendary wizard, you aren't. I mean, you and McGonagall clearly know what you're doing, and while you're a match for his minions, if you could take You-Know-Who, you would have last time. But here's the thing: You-Know-Who is weak right now, or he'd already be Dark Lord of the world already."

"That he would."

" What's more, he's politically crippled—Hells, even the Malfoys have publically renounced him. He can't storm the castle personally, and he doesn't have enough minions to do it for him outright. He probably only has a handful of loyal Death Eaters left, and they're all vying for who's going to be top guy when You-Know-Who returns. He might not even know about their existence."

"Not all of his servants are Death Eaters, boy."

"Really? I thought that was just the catch-all term for it here."

"Interesting. What does this have to do with unicorns?" Quirrell asked. His voice sounded somewhat hoarse.

"You would know more than anyone else, Professor," Milo said. There was a brief silence, and Milo heard a rustling of robes. "Vampires, Professor, vampires! There's only three ways for him to return, and they've all been mentioned in the story. Three ways, a pretty significant number, if you ask me. So, there's likely followers going for the Stone, the Blood, and rounding up friendly vampires as we speak. You're a trained combat wizard, Professor of Defence Against the Dark Arts at the best school in the country, and pretty clearly high level. And yet, even you got captured by vampires—so, unless they were the vampire of Merlin himself, your captors had to have help from a wizard. A Good wizard wouldn't help vampires, so it had to have been an Evil one—maybe working for You-Know-Who. So, one of his minions has more than likely succeeded in rounding up some poor sucker, no pun intended, to vamp our Dark Lord. That means that another minion, if he wants to top the first one, has to one-up vampires. That means unicorns, because the Stone is too well defended. The dead unicorns would have implied that the second, at least, was successful, and You-Know-Who can return, if he hasn't already, in some sort of limited form. That it was this Giant sort of throws a wrench in my thinking, to be honest. Means we have to be even more careful about Snape getting the Stone."

"Snape?" Quirrell asked, surprised.

"I'm surprised you hadn't put it together. Snape's after the Stone for sure. He's probably one of those minions I was telling you about, and You-Know-Who doesn't even know he exists. Or he does know. Or he is You-Know-Who in disguise. Amounts to the same thing, really. So we have to be on the lookout for Snape."

"Why," Milo heard an unfortunately-familiar voice, "do you have to be on the lookout for me, exactly? Is it because you're skipping detention?"

Ah, nuts.

"Ah, ah, no Professor," Milo stammered. "I was just helping the Professor—the other Professor—with this Giant, and we were going to the dungeon anyways, so I was just going to see you right after."

"Interesting," said Snape. "Because you're heading in completely the wrong direction. This is the third floor—the dungeon is that way." Why has Quirrell become so attached to the boy? Snape thought. He must know what I'm up to, and he's trying to prevent me from having him expelled for Lucius. What's his game? Is he after the Stone?

"The b-b-boy is with m-me, Severus," Quirrell said fiercely. Why has Severus become so attached to the boy? Quirrell thought. He must know what I'm up to, and he's trying to prevent me from feeding the boy to Hagrid's dog. What's his game? Is he after the Stone?

"Is he, now?" Snape asked. "I'm afraid I have prior arrangements with him."

"He c-c-can have his d-detention later. I n-need him now, this is of upmost i-importance," Quirrell maintained.

"Discipline is what's important, Quirinus," Snape pressed. Milo wondered why it was so important to Snape that he get Milo for detention... oh, Milo realized suddenly. He's going to kill me. I'll just ready a Glitterdust—wait, no, that didn't work so well last time. I'll just be on my guard, and not get caught flat-footed. Hopefully Quirrell can get rid of him.

"Th-th-the Troll is what's m-most important. You c-can have him a-afterwards."

"Milo," Snape commanded, "come with me at once. You have detention; this transparent method of escaping it shames your house and our school. Come with me, or I'll see to it that you're expelled."

Quirrell ground his teeth in frustration, but couldn't think of any way to prevent the boy from going with Snape without compromising his cover. Quirrell would pay for this soon, when no-one was around. He'd already failed his master too many times...

"Sorry, Professor Quirrell," Milo said sadly. "I suppose you'll have to manage for yourself—maybe you can find a House Elf to help? I'll... well, I'll see you around." Sweating profusely, Milo followed Snape towards the dungeons, away from his perceived protector. Their every footstep, made by Snape's polished loafers and Milo's worn adventurer's boots, rang through the empty corridors. Even the normally garrulous wall portraits were uncharacteristically reticent. Milo took the opportunity to plan his defence, should Snape make his move.

Opening move, he'll be expecting a surprise round, but I know he's coming, Milo thought. Then it'll be a test of reflexes. If I lose, he draws his wand as a move action and uses the Killing Curse as a Standard. I die. If I open with Glitterdust, and he makes his save, I die. If I open with Glitterdust and he fails his save—or, for that matter, I use Invisibility—but he beats my 50% concealment, I die. If I open with Mirror Image, I have an effective 50%-80% miss chance, meaning I only have a 20%-50% chance of dying. Mirror Image it is, then, followed by an expeditious retreat of a non-magical nature.

Milo licked his lips nervously as they rounded the last corner before Snape's office. He didn't like those odds, and if he did die, his chance of getting a Resurrection seemed slim. These wizards couldn't bring back the dead, and his party members back home wouldn't know he'd died. It was more than likely, he realized, that death here would be permanent.

Gulp.

Snape opened the heavy wooden door to his office and led Milo in.

"I've noticed that you've been falling behind in Potions lessons," Snape said slowly to Milo. "And it seemed to me that you could use some... extra help."

So, Snape was going to kill Milo during a remedial Potions lesson and what, make it look like an accident? Milo wondered why the pretense was even necessary. It wasn't as if there were any witnesses.

"I, ah, just don't seem to have a knack for it," Milo admitted.

"Indeed," Snape grinned slightly. "So, why don't we start with something extremely basic? One that it is quite impossible for anyone with a drop of magical blood to fail at?"

"Sure, sure," Milo said distractedly. He was anxiously examining the room for hidden traps, and felt a brief pang of homesickness. Wellby, their Rogue, never missed a trap—or, more accurately, the traps never missed him. But at least they were always detected, one way or the other.

"So, why don't we begin?" Snape asked, and with a flourish of his wand, a pewter cauldron drifted slowly towards him from the side of the room. So, Milo noticed, Snape has Silent Spell. But why did he show me this? As intimidation? "All you have to do is pour in three ladles of ordinary water, one teaspoon of Flobberworm mucous, and one teaspoon of ordinary glycerol; then stir counterclockwise once. It is, literally, the simplest potion in existence. A newborn could accomplish it. It makes bubbles, and nothing else."

"Okay," Milo said. Maybe Snape's idea is to keep my hands busy measuring so I can't go for my wand? Surely he knows by now that I don't really need it? It will make my Somatic components somewhat more difficult, however, although dropping an item is a free action. I'll play along, for now. Milo carefully measured water out of a glass beaker and poured it into the cauldron, then reached for the Flobberworm mucous.

"Of course," Snape said as Milo worked, "a Muggle attempting to create the potion would experience an... unfortunate side effect."

Milo's hand froze over the vial of mucous.

"R-really?"

o—o—o—o

Sprout sighed as she tried yet another spell to try to disenchant the singing pumpkin. Someone (well, clearly, it was the Weasley Twins, but without proof, they remained an as-yet unidentified "someone") had bewitched all of the decorative pumpkins on the second floor to sing "The Wheels on the Bus Go Round-and-Round," all at different keys and tempos. The consequent cucurbita cacophony was enough to drive even Peeves away.

"Finite Incantatem!" she cast vainly. The vegetables were surprisingly resilient to any attempts at dispelling them. If only those boys used their skills for something productive, she thought, the world would be better for it.

She smelled it well before she saw anything. It wasn't so much that the smell was bad, exactly—though it was that—it was just overpowering. The smell was huge, one could almost say...

...Giant.

There was a roar so loud that when it ended, Sprout couldn't even hear the pumpkins' song.

"EXPECTO PATRONUM!" she screamed.

o—o—o—o

"I'm beginning to worry about Milo," McGonagall told the Headmaster. "I can't help but wonder if you weren't wrong about his magic being an unusual form of a child's accidental magic."

"So, you think he's telling the truth about being a... different wizard?" Dumbledore asked.

"I... I really don't know. But his development in Transfiguration has been so remarkably stunted that I can't tell if he's improved in any way whatsoever since his first day off the boats," the Deputy Headmistress said. "And I'm not even certain that what he's doing is really Transfiguration at all. He's changing the matchstick's colour, to be certain, but... something seems off about it."

"Not everyone can wrap their head around Transfiguration. Why, Filius says his Hover Charm is worthy of a Seventh Year student, and Quirinus has nothing but praise for him. And you heard Ollivander's report about the what happened when he touched his wand the first time."

"Nevertheless," McGonagall pressed, "I think he may, in fact be... he might be a Squib, Headmaster. Why, I was just speaking to Severus, and he says that the boy is so hopeless at Potions that he actually believes him to be a Muggle, here by accident somehow."

"You mean to say that you and Severus actually agree on something?" Dumbledore asked.

"Perhaps. We'll know this afternoon, I believe, as Severus said he had developed some sort of test, and I for one—"

"Headmaster! There's a Troll loose on the second floor!" a small, cheerful voice said from behind McGonagall's head. The Deputy Headmistress turned around, and saw Sprout's Patronus floating behind her. Dumbledore and McGonagall stared at each other for a moment, then sprang into action.

"I'll start clearing the area of students—" McGonagall said, reaching for her wand.

"—and I'll contact the other Heads of Houses," Dumbledore said, standing up so fast that he knocked his chair over.

o—o—o—o

By the time the smoke cleared, Milo's hearing had mostly returned. His robe was in tatters, and he was covered in soot and dust.

"Wh-wh-what was that?" he asked.

"A Muggle chemist, if a Muggle chemist had ever analyzed Flobberworm mucous, would tell you that it reacts with the glycerol to form nitroglycerin."

Milo blinked blankly.

"Nitroglycerin is a volatile explosive," Snape said.

"And you let newborns do this?"

"No. A wizard's inborn magic prevents the chemical reaction from occurring, as it is superceded by a magical one."

"Then why did it... ah," said Milo. One could practically hear the copper piece drop.

Milo looked at Snape.

Snape looked at Milo.

Not a word was said, until...

"Severus! There's a Troll on the second floor—thought you ought to know," said a translucent silvery Phoenix that Milo could swear hadn't been there a moment before.

"HolycrapghostPhoenix!" a living Phoenix was CR 24, and being a ghost only made it more powerful. Fortunately, they were Good-aligned. A Phoenix's fire could deal up to 40d6 damage, although Milo was pretty sure Phoenixes were generally somewhat larger than a horse—this one was rather a lot smaller. A baby, perhaps?

"Get up, boy, and come with me—now!" said Snape. Milo wasn't about to refuse a direct command from a man who a Phoenix had apparently asked for help, and followed. After leaving his office, Snape broke into a dead run towards the stairs.

"Are we going after the Troll?" asked Milo as they ran up the spiraling staircase. Judging by the dull look in the monster's eyes, Milo was fairly confident its Will save was low enough that it would fail to Glitterdust for certain.

Snape paused for a moment.

"Boy, look at me," he commanded. Milo shrugged and complied. "Now, what were you and Quirrell talking about before I arrived?"

"Troll feeding and grooming," Milo lied blandly. Snape stared at him in the eyes for a moment.

"Very well, we've delayed too long," he said, and started climbing again at a hustle. Well, that was weird, Milo thought.

"Professor," Milo said as they continued climbing the stairs, "we missed the second floor. This is the third floor," but Snape said nothing as they rounded the corner to the forbidden third floor corridor.

Snape stopped at the door and waited, still without an explanation.

"Professor," Milo pressed, "I think I deserve an explanation now. What are we doing in front of the corridor of 'Die a horrible and painful death?'"

"Stop questioning me and be silent," Snape snapped.

"What, do you expect me to be able to simply Detect Thoughts or something? I won't be able to understand what's happening and act appropriately unless you tell me," Milo said, swapping out Invisibility. Detect Thoughts was a 2nd-level Wizard spell that allowed one to listen to the surface thoughts of another. Milo didn't really expect it to beat Snape's Will bonus, but everyone rolls a 1 once in a while. For once, it appeared, it was Milo's turn to be lucky. Snape turned around, catching Milo's eye.

"Five points from Gryffindor, and five more if you don't stop talking," the Professor said.

Fortunately, it appears I got here before Quirrell, Snape thought.

Why is beating Quirrell so important? Milo wondered.

The boy suspects we were racing Quirrell here. Well, it wasn't too hard to figure out, I suppose, Snape thought to himself (or so he thought). When he goes for the Stone, I'll be ready.

Is Quirrell going for the Stone? Milo wondered. That makes no sense at all, unless... Something's going on here I don't know about. Maybe Quirrell is trying to prevent Snape from getting the Stone? Or they're both going for it? Or Snape knows I'm reading his mind and—

The boy is a Legilimens? Snape thought sharply. There was a sudden pain in Milo's temple, and he felt a sudden sense of vertigo that knocked him to his knees.

"H-how did you... what was... what just happened?" Milo asked, clutching his head. His nose had started running, and he brushed it with his sleeve. The Detect Thoughts spell no longer even registered Snape as an intelligent being, it was like he wasn't even there.

"Answer me truthfully;I'll know if you're lying," Snape said imperiously. "Are you a Legilimens?"

"Ah," Milo said, "No?"

Snape frowned. He's telling the truth, Snape thought to himself (and, this time, only to himself), and yet... he must be lying somehow. Could he be an Occlumens as well? At eleven? No. He's not even a wizard. He must have some other powers, similar to Legilimancy in effect, but called something else.

"Can you read minds?"

"Ah. Um. No," Milo lied.

Snape grinned. It faded quickly.

"Tell me," he said oddly, "do you smell something?"

"As a general rule, no," Milo said. "But now that you mention it..."

The silence was only broken by a particularly large spider scurrying across the floor, and then a quick flash of emotion from Mordenkainen. FEAR, DISTRESS, HORROR.

And then the wall exploded.

Chapter 14: Talking is a Free Action

Author's Notes: To my knowledge, Rowling doesn't ever say exactly how large a gold galleon is, but the Harry Potter Wiki said that the ones used in the movies were the same size as an American Silver Eagle (57.2g if it were gold). Gold pieces are 1/50th of a pound (9.071g) each, so some number crunching gave me an exchange rate of 6.30854106 gp per galleon, assuming both have equivalent gold purities.

P.S: the short break, o—o, denotes a flash between simultaneous events in one location and another rather than a full scene break. You'll see what I mean.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Snape was decidedly more unpleasant towards Milo (and Gryffindor as a whole) in Potions on Monday, presumably because of Milo's near-escape from Snape's test over the weekend.

"You're holding your knife upside-down," Snape sneered at Milo as he sat chopping Knarl tail. "Fifteen points from Gryffindor."

Milo looked down at the knife. He was no expert on weapons (he left that to Fighters and other use-impaired character classes), but the knife's blade was sort of triangular and, by any account, perfectly symmetrical. Personally, he didn't much care, at least now Harry was suffering proportionally less abuse. As soon as Snape's back was turned, Milo siphoned off several potion ingredients into his Belt of Hidden Pouches. He figured he could cut his research and development costs somewhat using pilfered supplies.

It was with an intense feeling of relief that they left the dungeon.

"Oh," Milo remembered suddenly. "I should go see McGonagall, she asked me to see her on Friday but I got mauled by a 'Troll' instead."

"You... you put off seeing McGonagall just because of a Troll?" Ron asked, his face pale with horror.

"Run!" Hermione said, panicked.

Fortunately, their stern Head of House did not seem to mind as much as Ron and Hermione had feared she would that Milo had missed their appointment for frivolous reasons.

"So, erm, you wanted to talk to me about Transfigurations?" Milo asked her nervously.

"Well, I have to admit I was worried that Professor Snape might have been right about you," McGonagall said apologetically, "but, fortunately, you're just as much a wizard as he is—meaning, of course, that there's absolutely no reason that you can't succeed in Transfiguration."

Milo swallowed nervously.

"So, I believe the best thing for you would be to receive some extra help. With this in mind, I've requested that Professor Snape allow you to serve some of your further detentions with me twice a week so I can give you remedial lessons."

"Th-that doesn't sound so bad," Milo lied. Remedial Transfiguration? He would certainly forget to tell this to Hermione. "Thank you, Professor."

"Come to the Transfigurations classroom promptly at seven o'clock every Tuesday and Thursday," she said seriously, "and I'll eat my hat if we don't see some improvement." McGonagall glanced at the clock on her wall. "Well, you'd best be leaving if you don't want to be late for History of Magic."

As Milo walked to Binns' classroom, he decided fervently that the first spell he was going to research would be one that turned his matchstick into a pin. The only problem was that he couldn't think of any spells he'd ever heard of at his level that could even come close to doing that.

The reason for Dumbledore's odd request that Milo sleep in the hospital wing became immediately apparent upon his return to the Gryffindor Common Room Monday afternoon.

"All hail the conquering Troll slayers!" Fred cried as Milo, Hermione, Harry, and Ron climbed through the portal after their last class.

"No part of that sentence is accurate," Milo tried to say, but nobody heard him over the sudden tumultuous roar. It seemed the entire Gryffindor house had turned out to congratulate them for... not quite defeating a 'Troll'. Fred and George had procured food (read: cakes and sweets) and drinks (read: butterbeer) from somewhere.

"Harry and Ron insisted we wait for you two to get out of the hospital wing before celebrating," said George. "Insisted you two did the real work."

"Dumbledore tipped us off that you'd be out today," said Fred.

Well, Milo thought, that solves the Mystery of Dumbledore Asking Me to Wait a Day. If only the Mystery of Who Killed the Acromantula were so simple.

Someone had drawn a surprisingly good (if somewhat over-dramatic) scene of Hermione casting the Gust Jinx on the Troll on a banner hanging from the wall. They'd even bewitched it to move, complete with massive explosion as a grand finale. Hermione turned slightly pink; Milo didn't think she was used to being the centre of attention.

"'Course, the Hufflepuffs are all likely permanently scarred," Fred said.

"Yeah, having a Troll get blasted through your bedroom is likely to do that," said his twin.

"Putting a tree in their common room likely didn't help much, also."

"That said, even they're willing to admit it was pretty awesome."

"Sprout was furious—but only until she got a good look at the tree, mind."

While the twins were talking, Hermione and Milo were lifted up by a crowd of NPCs and passed around.

This is... unusual, Milo thought. He was more used to being presented with bags of gold or magic items as a reward for defeating a monster, but... well, having the Gryffindors throw a party for his party wasn't entirely unpleasant. He could definitely get used to this.

"They're teaching 'The Hermione' in magical self-defence courses around Britain," said Fred. "Some handsome devil leaked it to the Daily Prophet."

"Why, thank you," said George.

"But it was Harry's idea," Hermione protested, but nobody paid her any mind. The Boy-Who-Lived, it appeared, was more than happy to step out of the limelight for once.

"And to think," Lavender said to Parvati, "I always thought she was just an insufferable know-it-all!"

When the party finally wrapped up (well after a reasonable hour) and the Gryffindors trudged off to bed, Milo realized that he hadn't been so happy in ages.

o—o—o—o

The entirety of Gryffindor house, and to a lesser extent the Hogwarts student body as a whole, became increasingly excited as the first Quidditch match of the season loomed. Milo was surprised to find that, against all narrative convention, the tournament was to be opened with Gryffindor playing Slytherin on Friday.

"It's just wrong," Milo said to Harry after the black-haired boy returned, covered in mud, from last-minute practice on Tuesday. "You can't play Slytherin on your first match."

"Don't need to tell me twice," Harry said nervously. He'd seen their team captain a few days prior. Flint (Slytherin's team captain), Harry thought, could have been a distant cousin or nephew of the Hallowe'en Troll.

"You should be fighting them last," Milo pressed. "After a series of ever more difficult games that proportionally match your Quidditch skills. This just doesn't jive."

"Wouldn't that be something," Harry muttered tiredly. He flopped lazily onto one of the Common Room's overstuffed armchairs. Between Gryffindor's communal detentions, his homework (Snape seemed to be assigning the whole class extra work solely to keep Harry occupied before the match) and Wood's frantic Quidditch practice sessions, he'd hardly had any time to relax since his release from the hospital wing. Milo, as usual, had his nose buried in his spellbook, proving about as indefatigable as Hermione when it came to studying—although the similarities broke down shortly after that. While Hermione was practically obsessed with her homework, she was scandalized by how little Milo cared about his school-related studies when, on Wednesday, Milo turned in his assignment for Defence Against the Dark Arts (eighteen inches of parchment on Vampires), which was revealed to be a page full of weird numbers and data, seemingly filled in at random.

"So, about this match tomorrow—" Milo began.

"Don't mention it," said Harry. "Please."

"Oh, okay," Milo said, sounding somewhat hurt. "I was just going to say that I think I can keep you from getting grievously injured by Bludgers. No big deal, though."

Harry paused. There was a short, but noticeable, glint in his eye.

"Really, now?" he asked.

"Mage Armour," Milo muttered. "There. You're surrounded by an invisible force field."

"You're just putting me on, aren't you," said Harry suspiciously.

"No, it's true. Watch this," Milo said, and threw a nearby mug at Harry.

"Ow!" Harry said, as the ceramic cup hit him in the chest. "That really hurt!" (in the background, ignored by everyone, was a quiet "Hey! That was my mug!" from Neville).

"Uh," said Milo. "Look, nobody can predict rolling a 20, okay? Happens to the best of us. Let me try again." Milo picked up a Sickle (the silver coin, not the Simple Weapon).

"No!" Harry said, raising his arms to cover his head. "I'll just... I'll just trust you on this one, okay? I'm protected by an invisible force field that will help against speeding Bludgers but can't stop small ceramic cocoa mugs. I'm going to bed."

Harry started climbing the staircase to the tower that held their dorm room.

"Oh, wait," Milo said suddenly, "I'd been meaning to ask you something."

"Sure, what's up?" Harry asked sleepily.

"Well, you've got all these piles and piles of gold, right?"

"Look," said Harry seriously. "I didn't ask for them, right? I can't help being rich—"

"No, it's not that at all. The thing is, well, I need your help."

Harry frowned, all trace of exhaustion gone.

"Sure. What can I do?"

"Well," said Milo, feeling somewhat awkward about asking a friend for money, "you've probably noticed that I tend to use the same spells a lot."

"Uh, yeah, I guess."

"That's because where I come from, Wizards mostly learn spells from other Wizards. But there aren't any of those here," ("Hey!" said Neville) "so I have to develop all of my spells myself."

"But I'm rubbish with spells," Harry said. "You should ask Hermione for help."

"I don't, er, need your, um, expertise, exactly. You see, I get two free spells per level, but to get any others I need weeks of research and access to expensive materials."

"Oh," said Harry. "So you need money."

"...Yeah. But it's for a good cause—you know, fighting Evil and stuff."

"Sure, how much?"

"And I know of numerous ways in which I can turn 3rd-level spells into a way to make us phenomenal amounts of gold—"

"No, look, really, it's okay."

"—so I'll be able to pay you back when I get some free time, probably over the holidays."

"I don't mind, it's not like I'm using it for anything."

"Oh. You mean, you'll really share the loot?"

"'Course, we're friends. Although I sort of object to calling my parents' money loot—"

"Swag, then."

Harry sighed, but decided to ignore it.

"How much do you need?"

"You're not going to like it."

"Just tell me."

Milo told him. Harry didn't like it.

"A thousand galleons?" Harry spluttered.

"No, a thousand gold pieces. Galleons are quite a lot wider and thicker than your standard gp," Milo explained. "There's closer to six and a third gold pieces per galleon."

"So..." Harry said blankly.

"158 galleons, 12 sickles, and 12 knuts. Per week, that is."

Harry choked.

"Half that much again every day and I can make magic items, too."

"You know what? I don't even want to know," said Harry. Milo's hopes deflated. It looked like he'd be stuck here without any spells or magic items after all. "I'll write to Gringotts," Harry said, however. "I dunno exactly what the procedure is for transporting great heaps of gold halfway across Britain, but I'm sure the goblins will think of something."

Milo grinned.

"Thank you. I mean it. We're talking direct money-to-power translation, here. I'll pay you back in a few levels."

Milo climbed into his four-poster bed feeling like he was on top of the world.

o—o—o—o

"We have to kill Milo," Draco announced to Crabbe and Goyle Tuesday morning.

"Yeah boss, kill him!" said Crabbe.

"Sure boss, uh..." faltered Goyle.

"Try murder," Malfoy suggested wearily, "or dispatch."

"Sure boss, murder him!" said Goyle, who had never used the word dispatch before and was frightened to try.

o—o

"We have to kill Malfoy," Milo announced to his party Tuesday morning.

"Hear, hear!" Ron voiced his agreement. "S'what I've been saying for ages."

"Wait," said Harry slowly. "When you say kill..."

"What'd he do this time?" Hermione asked with a yawn.

o—o

"Thus summer, he broke into my father's summer home," said Malfoy imperiously, "and made off with the prototype Nimbus Two Thousand and One that Father had. It can't have been a random act of burglary because it was all done up like a regular Two Thousand—he'd have to have known it was there. I mean, how unlikely would it be that he just so happened to grab the one test Nimbus Two Thousand and One in all of England? There is only one possible conclusion," Malfoy paused dramatically.

o—o

"This Hallowe'en," Milo said theatrically, "he boasted about the Cuddly Cannons defeating the Wigtown Whatevers at that big game thing" (adventurers are notoriously bad about getting long names right) "admitting he was behind it. Now, I thought, 'what could a Quidditch match possibly have anything to do with anything?' when it hit me: the Nimbus Two Thousand. I grabbed one off a Death Eater once, and Harry got one in the mail, and thus it is on our list and therefore of relevance to the plot. The Cannons were all riding Nimbuses donated by Lucius Malfoy, who has connections to the Nimbus corporation. There is only one possible conclusion," Milo paused dramatically.

o—o

"Milo is working for Firebolt."

o—o

"Malfoy is working for the Dark Lord."

o—o

"What's Firebolt?" Crabbe asked, his forehead wrinkled in a gruesome imitation of human thought.

Malfoy sighed.

"A wreck of a broomstick manufacturer; everything they make is a total disaster. Remember? The guys who made the brooms the Wanderers were testing?"

Crabbe stared at Malfoy blankly.

"You're hopeless, Goyle," Malfoy muttered to Crabbe.

"Yeah, you're hopeless, Goyle," Goyle said to Crabbe.

"Yeah, I'm helpless, Crabbe," Crabbe said to Goyle.

"Anyways. The guys working for my father at Nimbus are the best in the world. The Two Thousand is only a few months old but it's already a hopeless antique compared to what they've got planned for the next one. Firebolt would kill to get their hands on it and learn its secrets. We can't let that happen."

o—o

"Seems a bit of a stretch, don't it?" Ron asked.

With a showy gesture, a massive chart appeared in the air behind Milo (in actuality, it was a Silent Image that Milo had cast several minutes prior and had been concentrating on it the whole time while his partymembers woke up. Yes, it would have been easier to just cast it then (or simply used a chart) but he felt this was more impressive).

There was a brief pause.

"Blimey," Ron said, though Milo had yet to figure out, exactly, what that word meant.

"What are we looking at?" Harry asked. Milo's hovering chart had a variety of names and events (such as Lucius Malfoy, Snape, the Stone, You-Know-Who, Poisoning and the Troll) written neatly, connected by lines and arrows of various colours.

"This," Milo explained, "is the plot. On the right are the villains in order of ascending level: Draco, who is Lucius' son and is working with his head of house, Snape; Snape, who is secretly the minion of Lucius Malfoy; Lucius who is an ex-Death Eater and loyal minion of You-Know-Who."

"Er," Hermione said cautiously. "What, exactly, do you mean by level?"

"Uh," Milo faltered. "Power. Importance. You know, the order in which we'll face them. Further left are the suspicious camps of unsorted villainy: the elves and their goblin servants, the Death Eaters, the Cuddly Cannons, and Fudge"

Ron and Harry were silent. Hermione simply sighed, shaking her head and muttering quietly to herself.

o—o

"So... what's Milo doing at Hogwarts, then?" Goyle asked. Malfoy shuddered inwardly at the amount of effort that sentence must have cost him.

"Isn't it obvious? Milo's here to secretly befriend Potter" (Malfoy said the last word with a contemptuous sneer) "who just so happened to get a Nimbus Two Thousand in the mail shortly after arriving here."

Crabbe and Goyle both blankly blinked back in unison.

"It's the prototype!" Malfoy shrieked at them. "Someone recently handed a perfectly ordinary-looking Two Thousand over to the DMLE in September and then days later Potter gets one in the mail and, with it, stunning new flying talents despite never having ridden a broomstick before. They've switched them! What else could explain Potter's little stunt with the Remembrall?"

"Maybe he's just really good at flying?" Crabbe suggested.

"Yeah boss, maybe he's just, despite his young age, so unbelievably talented at—"

"Shut up!" Malfoy commanded. "And then he just so happens to be allowed onto the Quidditch team despite being too young? It's all a conspiracy! McGonagall or someone somehow managed to get Milo's stolen broom from him and gave it to Potter so Gryffindor would have a chance at the cup. Then she went out and bought a Nimbus—I checked, they have it on record at Diagon Alley—and turned that in to the Ministry hoping nobody would notice."

o—o

"So, let's go through this chronologically. I was attacked in the Forbidden Forest by an Acromantula under highly suspicious circumstances, and the evidence suggests that someone iced the thing with a Killing Curse—highly advanced dark magic. The only people nearby were Quirrell, Hagrid, and Harry. As Hagrid can't do magic and we can obviously rule out Harry, that points to Quirrell—" (Milo traced a blue line from Quirrell to Acromantula on his chart).

"That can't be your only reason for ruling out Hagrid," Harry said, offended.

"—but that's no reason to believe it wasn't Snape, hiding somewhere in the forest," (Milo traced a line to Snape) "which kicks things up the ladder to Lucius, as, thanks to my furry friend, we now know is Snape's secret master, and eventually Lord Voldewhatsit.

"Next," Milo continued over Hermione's objections, "someone tried to poison my breakfast and missed. This poisoning was facilitated by the elves in the kitchen staff; nobody else could have got close to the food" (Milo pointed at their name on the chart, "under instructions from Draco, Snape, or Lucius during Draco's Quidditch distraction.)

"But I thought you said—" Ron said, but was cut off.

"While it is true that I did confront Draco about this and decided it wasn't him, my view changed when I found out that his father, Lucius, was having covert meetings with Snape in the Forbidden Forest. Lucius ordered Snape to have me expelled, presumably so Lucius can kill me while I'm no longer protected by the wards and Dumbledore. 'Maybe,' I realized, 'it's time we stopped ignoring Draco as a legitimate threat.' I'd bet—no, in fact, I'm certain of the fact that Draco's up to something devious, and likely highly dangerous, as we speak."

o—o

"So, I wrote Father and asked him to ensure that there was a Cannons victory on Hallowe'en—he, of course, did so without question or hesitation—to make Firebolt look bad and make Milo crack. And Merlin did it ever work!" Draco said exuberantly. "The nutter tried to end things for himself by the tried-and-true suicide by Troll method. Shame Snape was there to save him; really, I'd have thought better of him."

Draco paused to catch his breath.

"So," he said with a hint of finality, "we need to act, fast, before he can recover. Milo's had far too long with Potter to study the prototype for my liking. We need to stop that now. The Friday Quidditch match with Gryffindor is the perfect opportunity."

o—o

"And then," Milo continued, "someone released a Troll on Hallowe'en. While this would point pretty clearly to Quirrell, who seems to be a bit of an expert on Trolls, it just doesn't fit. Why would Quirrell release one right after teaching us all how to defend ourselves against Trolls? And besides," he added, "Snape's behaviour was more than suspicious. As soon as he heard about the Troll, he rushed, not to the second floor, where the Troll was supposed to be, but to the third floor, where we suspect they're hiding the Philosopher's Stone."

Even Hermione frowned at that.

"That is a little odd," she said at last. "You don't think... you don't think Professor Snape is trying to get the Stone?"

"A bit slow on the uptake, are we?" Milo asked. Hermione turned a bit pink. "Snape used the Troll as a distraction to get to the Stone and, likely, to kill me. He nearly succeeded on both counts."

Milo traced a line from the Troll to Snape to the Stone.

"Snape's backup plan, however, was already in the works. He'd devised a potion to oust me as a different type of wizard and have me expelled from Hogwarts which is when I met Fudge, your Minister for Magic. At first, I couldn't tell if he was pawn or chessmaster, but eventually it became clear. He really wanted me expelled, which means he's either got an agenda of his own, or he's working with Lucius. Now, he's not on Harry's list, meaning he was introduced too late to be a new, independent party. That means he was working on behalf of Lucius—but, fortunately, the whole Ministry's probably not in on it, or there would be all sorts of signs: wrongful imprisonment of sympathetic characters, horrific beings of death and fear in their employ, mysterious rooms in their basement full of gateways to evil dimensions, disagreements with Dumbledore, that kind of thing. Also, probably spikes on the Ministry roof—hey, Ron, your dad works there; has he ever mentioned spikes on the Ministry roof?"

"Nope," Ron said. "He says the desk corners are pretty pointy, mind."

"Hmmm. I don't think that's quite enough. So I'm putting them down for blatant corruption and incompetence rather than outright Evilness. Incidentally, this is probably why obviously Evil wizards like Snape and, frankly, the parents of the entire Slytherin house are so rarely raided by Aurors. Which brings me back to Snape: he is clearly trying to get the Stone for Lucius, who will present it to You-Know-Who in return for a position of power in the new world order. But his well-laid plans were foiled by you three and Quirrell. So," Milo paused to catch his breath, "we need to act, fast, before he can recover. The Friday Quidditch match with Slytherin is the perfect opportunity."

o—o

"I've got it all planned out," Malfoy said confidently. "I'll ask Father to anonymously donate a team's set of Nimbus Two Thousands to Slytherin, but they'll all have the names filed off and we'll leak to the Daily Prophet that the Slytherin team is testing a new Firebolt design."

"But," said Crabbe, "I thought you just said they'd be Nimbus Two—"

"Yes, yes, but they're in disguise. So it'll be a big thing, because everyone wants to see Firebolt's answer to the Two Thousand, so the Prophet and Which Broomstick and all of them will have people at the game to see how well it does. And here," Malfoy said modestly, "is where it gets really clever. Milo will have no choice but to try and rig the game so Gryffindor loses, or else his secret master, Firebolt, will look bad."

Goyle frowned.

"But, I thought he was friends with—"

"But, I thought we want Firebolt to look—"

"Oh, he cares about as much about Potter as I care about you two oafs!" Malfoy said angrily. "And once we can tell Milo's rigged the game and it's a shoo-in—or, should I say,—slither-in for Slytherin, then we'll have some of our players lose control of their brooms, crash, and blame it all on Firebolt. Slytherin wins the match, Potter never forgives his friend so Milo can't examine the prototype anymore, and Firebolt will be ruined."

Crabbe and Goyle were silent, staring in awe up at their boss.

o—o

"I've got it all planned out," Milo said confidently. "I'll break into Snape's office on Friday right before the game and steal some Veritaserum. While Harry is dazzling the school with his flying prowess, Hermione, Ron and I will sneak some into Draco's water. Then we kidnap him, tie him to a tree in the Forbidden Forest and beat him savagely until he tells us everything. We can bury his body where the Acromantulas will find him, then go back and watch the rest of the match."

Harry spat out the water he was drinking.

"We could be sent to prison for that," he exclaimed.

"Or worse," Hermione said, her face pale. "Expelled."

"Might be worth it, though," Ron said with a dreamy expression on his face.

"Fine, fine," Milo said. "Veritaserum is totally tasteless—rather like that Umbridge woman, actually. Malfoy will never know he's been drugged, and we can just ask him in the hall what his evil scheme is and he'll spill the beans without ever knowing why. We can deal with Malfoy later when it's more convenient."

"Let me get this straight," said Ron. "You are going to break into Snape's office."

"Yeah."

"Do we know any other Snapes?" Ron asked.

"Not to my knowledge."

"So... you're going to break into Professor Snape's office."

"Yeah."

Ron stared at him with a mix of fear and respect.

"You're mad, mate."

"There's no other choice," Milo insisted. "It's time we go on the offensive; we can't just keep waiting here for the next 'Troll' or giant spider or whatever. I mean, what's next, dragons?"

"Don't be ridiculous," said Hermione sharply. "Nobody would dare try and bring a dragon into Hogwarts, not while Dumbledore's here."

"Yeah, Dumbledore'd go nuts," Ron agreed.

"So," Milo pressed, "are we all in?"

"Yeah," said Ron. "Anything to get one over Malfoy."

"I don't see that there's much I can do," said Harry, "seeing as how I'll be playing Quidditch. But... yeah, I'm in."

Everyone turned to look at Hermione, who remained silent, looking troubled.

"We did have a deal," Ron said. "Remember? Milo found proof that Snape's evil, though I think his treatment of Harry should have made that clear enough."

"Oh, fine," she eventually snapped. "But only because you lot are hopeless without me."

o—o

Snape lay back in his worn leather office chair, thinking in silence. He couldn't imagine how the Headmaster managed to get anything done surrounded by those accursed ticking silver machines.

Quirinus Quirrell was trying to get the Stone. That much was obvious. The nervous Professor's sudden change in personality was highly suspicious, but the Headmaster refused to listen to Snape's warnings. Dumbledore, Snape decided, could be far too trusting for his own good. Snape would have to take matters into his own hands.

But... what of the boy? What's Milo's role in all of this? If Snape had thought Quirrell seemed attached to the boy earlier, Hallowe'en had confirmed that. Quirrell had tried to get Milo out of detention with Snape...

Snape frowned.

That wasn't all he'd been trying to do. Milo had been helping the Defence Professor with the Troll, so...

Snape blinked.

Milo was helping Quirrell steal the Stone. That must be why Malfoy wanted him thrown out of Hogwarts, realized Snape.

So. Lucius knows about the Stone.

Snape ran his hands through his greasy hair. He had a fine line to walk: he had to protect Potter without anyone realizing it, protect the Stone, help Lucius have Milo expelled to maintain his cover with the Death Eaters, and, now, also keep Lucius from getting his hands on the Stone—without Lucius realizing he was trying to do so. It was only a matter of time before Lucius commanded him to steal Flamel's Stone.

Snape's next move, obviously, was to discover everything he could about Quirrell. For whom was he working? What, exactly, was his relationship with Milo? What really happened to him over the summer?

Unfortunately, it wasn't as if Snape could just ask him these questions—and if Quirrell was ready to play the game at this level, he'd be too clever to let anything slip accidentally. Even dosing him with Veritaserum would be unlikely to succeed. Snape, for one, always carried the antidote in a small flask on his person and drank it whenever he began feeling particularly honest (a rare enough feeling to be immediately suspicious); there was no reason to believe Quirrell did not do so as well.

Fortunately, Snape had a plan. There were potions other than Veritaserum for learning what others wanted kept secret. It took a month to brew, but was useful enough that Snape always kept some on hand.

All I have to do now, he thought to himself, is get the boy alone.

Snape smiled. There was no trace of humour whatsoever in it.

Chapter 16: Be Good For Goodness' Sake

Author's Notes: Here's your Sunday bonus chapter, as promised—but wait, there's more! I don't know what's wrong with me, but I'm on a roll lately. I wrote an entire chapter yesterday, and it wasn't this one. I'll put the finishing touches on it today, and tomorrow, you, my faithful readers, get Bonus Chapter 2: Revenge of the this Time it's Personal Strikes Back. Also, I decided to rename the Hallowe'en chapters from the rather boring Part 1, 2, 3, and 4 to be Sidequests, Hallowe'en, Odds of Survival, and The Troll and the Dementor, respectively.

So: Chapter Seventeen will go up tomorrow, and Chapter Eighteen will go up on Saturday, as usual. (Who knows, maybe Nineteen will be on Sunday?)

Anyways, on with the story! I hope nobody is deterred by the flood of chapters! And if you like it, review it!

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

"Sit," McGonagall commanded. Milo was in the hard leather chair in her office before she'd finished saying the one-syllable word. "Your behaviour today was cowardly, treacherous, sickening, and unbecoming of a Hogwarts student, much less a member of my house. I have half a mind to expel you this very minute. What do you have to say for yourself?"

"Well," said Milo, "in my defence, he sort of had it coming. I mean, look at him."

"You will explain to me, right now, clearly and succinctly, how you could possibly think that such a poor, sweet, innocent boy who has already suffered so much had—what was it you said? Oh yes, how he had it coming. If I find your explanation is in any way unsatisfactory, you'll be out of here faster than you can say Mimbulus Mimbletonia."

"He's obviously working for You-Know-Who."

McGonagall sat down heavily in her office chair, stammering and apparently at a complete loss for words.

"Of all the ridiculous—impossible—why, he would be the last person to ever—in any case, You-Know-Who's long gone—I was a friend of his parents, I won't listen to such unfounded accusations!"

"Oh, so you're in his father's pocket as well?" Milo asked, disappointed. "Seems like the whole wizarding world is convinced he's such a great guy when he's really, clearly, obviously evil. It's like you're all blind, I swear!"

"Evil? A tad arrogant, when he was younger, and I suppose he had an unfortunate and blatant disregard for any rules he found inconvenient, but never evil. There are places in this country—and right now, I'm debating if you're sitting in one as we speak—where statements like that would be responded to with challenges to duels."

"I always had you figured as being on our side, Professor. I can see that my trust was misplaced."

"And what, exactly, is your side, then, boy?" McGonagall asked, her face flushed with anger. Milo was starting to wonder if she hadn't multiclassed into Barbarian for some mysterious reason.

"The good guys, Professor," Milo said as if it were the most obvious thing in the world.

"How dare you—"

"If you're of a mind to call Draco Malfoy a poor sweet, innocent boy then," Milo said with a hint of finality, "I think we're through anyways."

McGonagall stared at him as if he had just said the sky was green.

"I—you—Draco..." she stopped talking and simply breathed steadily for several moments, evidently trying to calm down. "Who did you think we were talking about?"

"Who did you think we were talking about?"

"Harry James Potter," McGonagall said. "The boy you nearly killed today."

"Oh," Milo said. What was it Quirrell mentioned about the Polyjuice potion? "That."

"Yes. That."

o—o—o—o

"There must be a change of plans... my family are still loyal... more than I can say for some..."

"Y-yes, my l-lord, of c-c-course, my lord, but I have always b-been your most d-devout—"

"Interesting, isn't it, that, when asked, all my servants profess to be my most devout, my most faithful... paradoxical, it seems..."

"W-we've had setbacks, I-I'll admit t-t-to that, my l-lord, b-but—"

"Indeed we have had... setbacks. Perhaps I should turn to Lucius instead.. one of my other most faithful servants..."

"B-but my l-lord, w-we are weak—f-forgive me, b-but y-y-you know it to b-be true—w-what is to stop him f-from s-simply killing us and c-c-continuing to rule in y-your stead?"

"Killing you, you mean... for I am far beyond the reach of even Lucius Malfoy..."

"Yes, of c-course, my lord, what I m-meant was that you w-would be as I f-f-found you. S-surely, a s-significant s-s-setback even for one such as—"

"Yes, yes, I know what you mean... ought to be more concise... takes ages to say anything with your st-st-stutter..."

"S-so my l-l-lord, w-what shall we d-d-do? C-continue to t-try for the St-Stone or for the b-b-boy?"

"I see no reason we cannot do both... for if one fails, and knowing you, one will fail, we will have the other... simply prudent..."

"B-but he claims he c-c-cannot cast the spell yet."

"But his power grows with violence... provide him with violence, Quirrell, violence at all levels..."

"A-at all levels, m-my lord?"

"Violence he can overcome, but... violence where he fears for his life... for the lives of others...
at all times, Quirrell, all times... he must never know safety again... but keep him alive... yes, always
alive..."

"It w-w-will take t-time m-m-my lord, a-as with the Acr—"

"SILENCE. You are never to mention that to me again!"

"I-I'm sorry, my lord, have m-m-mercy... the p-p-p-pain..."

"Mercy?"

"Y-yes, my lord, please, my lord, I b-b-beg—"

"Very well... Am I not merciful, Quirrell? You are granted reprieve from your sufferings... for the moment..."

"Th-th-thank you, m-my—"

"Cease... no time to waste on your incomprehensible stammering... we must plan carefully..."

"My lord, w-what if—"

"I meant 'we' figuratively... I, of course, shall plan carefully... you shall listen, and you shall act..."

"Of c-course, my lord."

"You are their hero, now, are you not? Saved the mudblood from the monster... we must use this..."

"H-how, my l-l-lord?"

"This is what you must do..."

o—o—o—o

"—so you see, it wasn't me at all who cast the hex or whatever it was," Milo explained reasonably, "but, in fact, Professor Snape, polyjuiced to look exactly like me."

"And you seriously expect me to believe this load of tripe?" McGonagall snapped.

"Snape's—"

"Professor Snape," McGonagall corrected sharply.

"Right, Professor Snape's had it out for Potter since he first set foot in this castle. Everyone knows it."

"Be that as it may," McGonagall said. Milo was somewhat astonished that she didn't contest the point, "the notion that he would use Polyjuice to facilitate assaulting one of our students is completely out of the question. Now, are you quite ready to tell me the truth, or would you rather I have you thrown out the front gates immediately?"

"Truth! Of course. Professor, dose me with Veritaserum and you'll be able to tell that I'm being completely honest!"

"Regrettably, the use of Veritaserum is strictly controlled by the Ministry," McGonagall said, "and is not used in the investigations of school rule infractions."

"Then, doesn't the fact that I was going to volunteer to take it count towards me?"

"Not if you were already aware of these regulations, Mr. Amastacia-Liadon."

Milo stared at her, fear rising. He couldn't believe he was about to be expelled for something that happened offstage.

"You can't just expel me without any proof!" he protested.

"I have twenty-six eyewitness reports that say you brazenly used the Hurling Hex on Mr. Potter in the middle of a Quidditch match in plain sight!"

"But—but I didn't!" Milo was appalled that that was the best argument he could think of.

"You will pack your school trunk in your dormitory, where you will remain until morning when you will be taken to the Ministry to have your wand destroyed—"

"My wand!" Milo said with sudden inspiration. "Here, look—" Milo drew his wand from his pocket.

"I don't have time for this foolishness," McGonagall muttered.

"But—look at it, Professor! I had it on me the whole time, what wand did I allegedly use to hex Harry? Was it chestnut, thirteen inches, with dragon heartstring core? No! It can't have been because all wands are unique."

"It only would have been visible for a few seconds," McGonagall said, "nobody reported what wand you used."

Milo's hopes deflated. That was his last hope. He couldn't believe he was going to be thrown out of Hogwarts because a crowd of NPCs failed their Spot checks to see something he wasn't even there for.

"So..." Milo said hesitantly. "What happens now? Where will I go?"

"After the Ministry?" McGonagall said. For an almost imperceptible moment, her gaze seemed to soften. "After your wand has been destroyed, it's quite up to you."

"Very well, Professor. I'll head to my dormitory now." Milo walked back to the familiar sights of the Gryffindor Common Room in a daze.

o—o—o—o

"And then I hit him with a water balloon and said 'Hey, Malfoy, think fast!'" Ron said exuberantly, causing Hermione to snort in a most unladylike fashion. "How'd everything go with Grabbe and Coyle?"

"Oh, it was no trouble at all. I just walked up to them and said, 'oh no, I'm just a poor defenceless Muggleborn girl who misplaced her wand, whatever shall I do?'" Hermione said with a wicked grin. "Took them about five seconds to try and hex me. Anything I did after that was purely self-defence, you understand."

The pair of them were waiting outside Pomfrey's hospital wing for the strict witch to declare Harry fit for visitors.

Eventually, the heavy doors opened.

"Oh," Pomfrey said wearily. "It's you lot again. Well, come in, come in," she ushered the pair into the ward.

"Visitors!" Neville said happily, his nose just poking out between thick bandages. "I never get visitors!"

"Nah, we're here for Harry," said Ron, ignoring a sharp look from Hermione.

"Hey," said Harry. Injuries notwithstanding, he seemed to be in high spirits. "Did you hear? Or see? I caught it! Looks like I'm not rubbish after all!"

"To tell the truth, I only caught the first bit," Ron admitted, looking apologetic. "But that's only because our plan worked. Can you believe it? Malfoy told me everything!"

As he happily told Harry about Malfoy's crackpot scheme involving the Firebolts and the Nimbuses, Harry burst out laughing, clutching his sides.

"So when they saw me lose control of my broom," he asked when he could finally breathe, "they thought Milo hexed me?"

"Nutty, isn't it?"

"Where is he, by the way?" Harry asked, looking around.

"Dunno," said Ron. "Good question. Haven't seen him since before the match. You don't... you don't think Snape caught him, do you?"

"Can't have," Neville said. Harry, Ron, and Hermione turned to him, somewhat surprised that he'd spoken. "He was at the Quidditch game."

"What, really?" Ron asked. "He could have helped with Malfoy, then."

"Can't have," Neville said, his face (well, the visible parts anyways) uncharacteristically grim. "He was too busy hexing Harry's broomstick."

"You mean Malfoy was right?" Ron asked, alarmed. "Merlin's pants! That turncoat!"

"Looks like," Neville said sullenly.

"No," said Harry firmly. "I don't believe it. He was set up."

"I saw it myself! He just stood up, pulled out his wand, and hexed you! Right in plain sight!"

There was a brief silence.

"Did you say wand?" Harry asked.

o—o—o—o

"Password?" asked the Fat Lady.

"Squeak," Milo replied, and the portrait swung open. Stupid password, he thought to himself. The 'ultra-secure' Common Room can be infiltrated by a Fighter in heavy armour after a rainy day.

As soon as Milo entered the Common Room, he wished he still had Invisibility prepared. The sounds of partying cut off immediately when he came into sight, and everyone simply stared at him silently. Milo walked directly to the dorm, and the crowd parted slightly around him—it seemed that nobody wanted to touch him. Milo was surprised at how much their shocked disapproval hurt him—they were only NPCs, after all.

He collapsed onto his four-poster bed, exhausted. He knew he should be thinking of a plan, some clever scheme, to get out of this, but he just felt too tired. He'd been defeated, that was all there was to it.

He was going to be expelled. Lucius had won.

o—o—o—o

"Professor!" Hermione practically shouted, knocking sharply on the office door. There was no reply. "She must be out somewhere!" she moaned.

"Maybe—maybe she's in the staff room?" Ron suggested, "or the Great Hall?"

"Or she's patrolling the corridors," Hermione said, despair growing. "Or visiting another teacher's office. Or overseeing detention. Or she's out of the castle. She could even be—"

Hermione gasped.

"What?" Ron asked, alarmed.

"You don't think she—could it be? She wouldn't, would she?"

"One day," Ron said, "you're going to give me a straight answer. And on that day, I'm going to buy a lottery ticket and win a thousand Galleons."

"She might be—"

"And then I'll be selected for Head Boy."

"Ron, listen, she—"

"And named Minister for Magic."

"Ron—"

"Then Snape will apologize for being a git and stick his head in a cauldron. Oh, and he'll pull Malfoy in after him. To round it off, the Chudley Cannons will ask me over for tea to give them a few pointers on Quaffle handling. And then I'll go to bed early in my solid gold, king-sized bed stuffed with unicorn's hair in my floating palace." Abruptly, Ron realized Hermione had stopped interrupting him.

"Are you quite done?" Hermione asked testily.

"I was going to mention the butterbeer fountains, marble statues, and how it can travel to Jupiter, but that seems somehow unnecessary now."

"I was going to say, before you so rudely cut me off, that she might already be at the Ministry!"

Ron stared at her blankly.

"Why would she be at the Ministry?" he asked.

"Because," Hermione explained wearily, "when a student is to be expelled, the DMLE and the Improper Use of Magic Office in particular have to be informed."

Ron continued to stare at her without comprehension.

"So that they can destroy the student's wand," Hermione said, fighting down the urge to add 'Duh.'

"Blimey," Ron said. "Who do you think is getting the axe?"

Hermione stared at him with genuine surprise on her face.

"Milo, of course! Honestly, is there anything between those ears of yours?"

Ron paled.

"We have to find McGonagall before that happens!" he said.

"Yes, Ron," Hermione said, her voice commendably, under the circumstances, both level and patient. "That's why we're here. Knocking on her office door." Hermione paused for a moment, willing herself not to say it, but even her doughty willpower could break under sufficient strain. "Duh."

o—o—o—o

Neville, who for one reason or another had been living in the hospital wing for the past two months (when he was lucky, that is—the rest of the time, he was at St. Mungo's) had a few special concessions from Madam Pomfrey that most short-term patients didn't get. They were little things, like a reading lamp (Neville always had trouble with Lumos), a few extra pillows, the blanket that smelled the least of cats, a bedside table with a pair of drawers for keeping his clothes in, and the cot next to the window.

It was due to this last fact that, on Friday evening, he saw a tall, thin figure striding confidently up to the Hogwarts gates.

"Hey, Harry," Neville said.

"What's up, Nev?" Harry asked sleepily.

"Well, Ron and Hermione went out to find McGonagall, right?"

"Sure."

"And that was four hours ago, right?"

"Was it?" Harry asked. He must have drifted off at some point, he realized.

"Yeah, it was. So they must not have found her."

"Guess not."

"Well, she's right outside."

"She is?" Harry asked, all trace of drowsiness gone. He looked around for Madam Pomfrey, but she seemed to be out somewhere. Well, there was nothing else for it. Agonizingly, he stood up and limped towards the door.

o—o—o—o

"Well, we've searched the staff room, the Common Room, every teacher's office, all known corridors of Hogwarts, Hagrid's Hut, the dungeons, the Great Hall, the lake, the Quidditch Pitch, the astronomy tower, and most of the empty classrooms, but there's been no sign of her," Ron moaned in despair. He and Hermione were standing in the entrance hall trying to decide where to look next.

"Sign of whom?" asked a familiar voice. The pair turned to see Professor McGonagall standing at the entrance, taking off her coat and looking curious.

"Professor!" Hermione said with relief. "We finally found you!"

"Me?" McGonagall asked in surprise. "Is Peeves acting up again?"

"No," Hermione said at the same time that Ron said "Probably."

"Well, than what can I help you with?"

"It's about Milo," Hermione said. "He's innocent!"

McGonagall's face hardened.

"I understand he's your friend, but there were dozens of witnesses. I'm sorry, but I have no choice but to expel him."

"No, Professor, you don't understand. You see—" Hermione froze. She was about to say, 'you see, he was seen using a wand and Milo's magic doesn't need wands,' but she realized that that would just get him expelled for a different reason. She began to realize that maybe, this time, she hadn't thought their plan all the way through. "He wouldn't do something like that," she finished lamely.

"Yeah," said Ron. "I mean, he's a bit of a nutter, mind, but he's Harry's mate. He wouldn't hex him like that."

"I'm sorry," McGonagall said. "But without something a bit more than your gut feelings, the case is open and shut. Now, if you'll excuse me, I have a great deal of paperwork to do. Unless one of you has something concrete?"

"I asked him to," said a voice. Hermione turned in surprise to see Harry, wrapped in bandages and casts, leaning weakly against a doorway on the upper level.

"Harry, what—" Hermione asked.

"I asked him to pretend to hex me," Harry said. "We found out that Malfoy had concocted a some nutty plan to rig the Quidditch match and make Firebolt look bad, and he thought for some reason that Milo would hex me to protect the reputation of the broomstick company. Can't imagine why. So I asked Milo to pretend to go along with it, and faked the whole thing. Malfoy thought his plan had worked, and his team pretended to lose control of their brooms. It was all faked. Milo never really hexed me."

McGonagall, Ron, and Hermione stared at him, shock evident on their faces.

McGonagall's mouth moved a few times, as if she were about to speak, but couldn't quite find the words. Harry, Ron, and Hermione stared at her in hopeful silence. Eventually, she rallied somewhat.

"Of all the—not even Fred and George would have—okay, maybe Fred and George—but... how did you discover this alleged plan?"

"Oh," said Ron, "that was me. He just bragged to me about it, right to my face, during... er, just before the match. Can't imagine why."

"He told you?" McGonagall said. "But why... I spoke to Milo earlier, he came up with some preposterous tale about Professor Snape and Polyjuice... why didn't he just tell me the truth?"

"Because he's only eleven and was scared?" Hermione suggested hopefully.

McGonagall sighed.

"Well, I'll have to owl the Ministry immediately and tell them to cancel the hearing... of all the crackpot schemes, this one has to take the cake."

"So..." Hermione said, hope rising on her face like the sun, "so he's cleared? He won't be expelled?"

"No," McGonagall said, "but this was, nonetheless, an underhanded move unworthy of our House. And Mister Potter, I thought better of you. Twenty points from Gryffindor from you and Milo each, and detention every Saturday for the rest of November. And December. At least. And you two—" McGonagall turned to Ron and Hermione "—were you involved in this as well?"

"No, not involved in any way whatsoever, Ma'am." Ron said smoothly, his years of living in the same house as the twins paying off.

"Us? Involved? Hah. He. Hahaha. Nope," Hermione said nervously. McGonagall eyed them suspiciously, but instead of giving them detention, just turned and walked up the stairs to her office, muttering to herself about needing a Firewhiskey.

There were a few blessed seconds of relief for the three friends as they savoured their triumph. It was interrupted, however, by a fell shriek that could have raised the dead (in a manner of speaking, it did—the ghost of Nearly Headless Nick, hovering nearby, was so startled that he (nearly) lost his head).

"What are you doing out of bed, young man?" came the terrible voice of a wrathful Madam Pomfrey. Harry turned around in terror, while Hermione and Ron simply fled.

o—o—o—o

When word got around that Milo's surprise attack on the Boy-Who-Lived was not, as had been generally believed, treachery most foul, but rather a component in a circuitous gambit to sabotage the Slytherin Quidditch team and guarantee a Gryffindor win, there was much shuffling of feet and making of sheepish glances in the Gryffindor Common Room.

"So, really, when it comes down to it, we're sorry, mate," said an NPC (Seamus Finnigan, not that Milo knew or particularly cared).

"Why the sudden reversal of opinion?" Milo asked.

"Well, you see, Hermione came into the Common Room about an hour ago," said Fred.

"—And she stood up on the table, right in the centre of the room—"continued George.

"It was horrible," said another NPC (Dean Thomas). "like a banshee of wrath..."

"—And she started speaking, and the walls shook—"

"—Only, see, nobody saw her cast Sonorus, so it was all her—"

"—And she calmly told us about judging people before fully understanding the situation—"

"—Oh, yes, definitely calm. Level-headed, she was. The windows shattered of their own accord—"

"—And, if she asks, we didn't even hint otherwise—"

"—And thus, we were enlightened to the errors of our ways," finished George.

"Frankly, I'm surprised you didn't hear it, mate," said Dean. Milo noticed that they were calling him 'mate' a lot.

"Hermione must have put up some kinda Charm to keep teachers in the halls from storming in to see what all the screaming was about," Milo shrugged. "She's careful like that." In truth, he'd heard every word, but wanted to hear them explain it anyways. It was more fun that way.

"I thought you were innocent the whole time," said Hannah.

"Isn't this the boys' dorm?" asked Dean. Hannah coloured slightly.

"So," Seamus said, somewhat nervously. "Want to come down and have some butterbeer? There's not much left, but it's really good. How Fred and George get this stuff, I'll never know."

"And we'll never tell," Fred winked.

"Yeah," said Milo. "I think I'd like that."

The whole room gave a collective sigh of relief.

"So," he said on the way down the stairs into the Common Room, "what's your excuse going to be next week?"

"Sorry, mate?" asked George.

"For a party. Seems like a weekly tradition 'round here."

"It isn't," said Fred slowly.

"But it should be," said George, whose forehead wrinkled in thought for a moment. "We'll think of something," he said finally. "Trust us."

"And drink this," Fred said, pushing a heavy tankard of butterbeer into Milo's hands. Milo sipped it cautiously, and suddenly grinned. The stuff wasn't ale (the preferred method of hydration for adventurers everywhere), but it was pretty fantastic. And before you cry, "But he's only eleven! He's far too young for ale!" you should be advised that there are, in fact, no rules for intoxication from alcohol anywhere to be found. It can therefore be concluded, via strict interpretation of the holy Rules-As-Written, that one can drink gallons of tequila like water.

"Shouldn't we have waited for Harry to get out of the hospital?" Milo asked suddenly.

"That's what we thought," said Fred (maybe), "but he gave us permission to celebrate without him in future events such as this, so long as we save him some of the provender."

"Speaking of which, hands off the last of the Every Flavoured Beans, you greedy git!" George said, glaring at Ron.

The Quidditch victory party concluded a little after midnight when a sleepy McGonagall made them all go to bed.

o—o—o—o

Despite Fred and George's promise, the next few weeks were surprisingly uneventful (not that that prevented them from finding excuses for celebration, as their "Happy November the 22nd Day!" festivities attested to). Milo's time was taken up by almost constant detentions (both for McGonagall and Snape, now) and lessons with McGonagall, but he found enough time in to research Benign Transposition, Disguise Self, Nerveskitter, and Resist Energy. If Snape had any reaction to his latest plot to expel Milo, it went unnoticed among his usual horribleness. Quirrell started a unit on vampires, which sent Hermione into a panic because it wasn't on the original reading list.

It was on a cold December afternoon when Milo returned to the Common Room to find a small crowd gathered around the bulletin board.

"What's going on?" Milo asked.

"It's Quirrell," said Lee. Fear gripped Milo's heart. Had Snape finally gotten the better of the enigmatic Defence Professor?

"What happened to him?"

"Nothin'," said Lee. "Only he's started a Duelling Club."

The bulletin had a large parchment poster pinned to it, reading SUNDAY DUELLING CLUB SIGN-UP on it, with a number of lines for people to write their names in. The lines were already all taken, and several people had scrawled their names haphazardly in the margins.

Milo grinned. Sundays were his remaining free day, so there was nothing to stop him from attending Quirrell's club and stomping some of the local 'wizards' for fun and XP. What were they going to do, shoot sparks at him?

The poster said the club meetings would start after the holiday break.

"Hey, Ron," Milo asked, picking his partymember out from the crowd. "What's a holiday break?"

"You don't even know what a holiday break is?" Ron asked, flabbergasted. "Everyone—"

Hermione coughed pointedly.

"—here would like nothing more than to illuminate you on this subject," Ron finished smoothly.

"Everyone gets to go home for Christmas," Hermione explained.

"Do we have to?" Milo and Harry asked simultaneously.

"Jinx," muttered Harry.

"What? Where?" Milo asked, looking around warily.

"Nevermind," said Harry. "It's a Muggle thing."

"No," Hermione said. "You can stay for the holidays, but almost nobody does."

"Cool," said Milo.

"Also, what's Christmas?" Milo asked. Hermione, who had the bad timing to be drinking from a glass of water right then, snorted her drink from her nose.

"What's Christmas?" she asked. "Everyone knows... ah. Ahem. It's a holiday that happens once a year on December 25th where people give each other presents."

"Do I need a costume again?"

"No. Costumes on Christmas are strictly optional."

"Will there be Trolls?"

"No, there's just Father Christmas and his elves," Hermione said, regretting it instantly.

"Elves again, eh?" Milo asked, rubbing his hands together. "Harry, put them on the list. These elves have come up enough now that I'm sure they must be relevant to something... what sort of elf are they, these ones that work for this 'Father Christmas?'"

"Christmas elves," Hermione said in a quiet voice.

"Must be an obscure, non-core subrace. I'll keep an eye out for them. What's Father Christmas?"

"He... children believe he travels to everyone's house at night on a flying sleigh and delivers presents on Christmas," Hermione explained. "But nobody really thinks he's real. People also call him Santa Claus."

"Santa Claws? This just keeps getting worse and worse!" Milo said. "He must be an exceptionally powerful caster to be able to cast enough Time Stops to get all the way around the world in a single night... unless he has a use-activated Magic Item... wow, that would be worth a fortune."

"But—he's not really real," Hermione insisted.

"I can't tell you how many times I've heard that before," Milo snorted. "'there are tales—unfounded, of course—of a fell monster in the woods...' or 'they speak, in whispered voices, of a wolf that walks among men... I'm sure it's just rumour, though.' Hermione," Milo said, in the tone of someone talking to a small, ignorant child, "if there's one thing I'm surprised you haven't learned by now, it's that all rumours are true."

"But Father Christmas isn't real," she insisted.

"Oh, really?" Milo asked. "Harry once told me that Muggles don't believe in dragons, magic, elves, or goblins," Milo scoffed. "And all of those things are real."

"That's no reason to think—"

"Hermione, how many of the things you believed as a small child, only to find out as a medium child were make-believe, turned out to be real when, as a large child, you discovered you were a witch?"

There was a brief silence as Hermione did some mental arithmetic.

"Most of them," Hermione admitted with a frown. "But come on. Father Christmas? Not even wizards believe in him—right, Ron?" Ron didn't respond. "Ron?"

"F-Father Christmas isn't real?" he asked, stunned. "Fred and George said they saw him, once..."

"Oh, he's real alright," Milo said grimly. "And worse: he's in league with the elves."

With that, Milo strode off to his favourite armchair (one in the corner which presented him with a clear view of the room, while also being close enough to the window that he could dive out and Feather Fall in an emergency), pulling materials out of his Belt of Hidden Pouches.

"Where are you going?" Harry asked.

"I have to put the finishing touches on my Robe of Arcane Might," Milo said. "I might be needing it, soon." He had to find a way to get out of his detentions, they were cutting into his crafting time. Maybe if he could slay Santa Claws and take his magic Item of Time Stop...

Milo wasn't sure exactly what this Father Christmas's connection was to the drow in the kitchen that tried to poison him, but one thing was for sure:

If Santa—or any of his little elves—tried anything on or about Christmas, they weren't going to just walk away from it.

Chapter 17: White Christmas

Author's Notes: To anyone who didn't check yesterday (Sunday), and it confused, this is the second bonus chapter this week. If the last thing you remember in the story is an angry McGonagall pulling Milo from a meeting with Quirrell, you need to go back a chapter.

Also, to my absolute horror, as The Lost Hibiki pointed out, I've been reading the requirements on Spontaneous Divination wrongly this whole time. I am so, so sorry—my intent from the very beginning was to have Milo stay strictly within the confines of the Rules as Written (RAW) in order to poke fun at some of the quirks and inconsistencies in D&D, and also so that D&D fans would have a very clear understanding of Milo's abilities (making it all the more fun to try to figure out how he's going to get out of a tough position). As it turns out, Spontaneous Divination requires substitution of one of a Wizard's bonus feats other than Scribe Scroll, meaning it isn't available for Milo until level five (meaning he can't have used it before his battle with the Troll). Normally, for an error like that, I would go back and edit the previous chapters to fix it, but in this case Milo's use of Spontaneous Divination is too deeply interwoven within the plot to pull it out. I hope the hardcore D&D fans out there aren't too put off by my mistake!

The best I can do is apologize, and say that either Milo comes from a campaign world run by a DM who house-ruled Spontaneous Divination's prereqs, or alternatively, Milo is such a munchkin that he figured out how to get it early even though I never could.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

"Hey, Harry!" said Milo excitedly, running up to his partymember in their dorm room. It was the day before the holiday, and everyone was eagerly awaiting two weeks at home—everyone, that is, except Harry and Milo, who were staying.

"What's up?" Harry asked.

"Check this out," he said, holding up an ordinary-looking Hogwarts school uniform.

"You finally done tinkering with that thing?" Harry asked. "You said it would be done weeks ago."

"Yeah, well," Milo said, "feature creep, you know. And then there's all the detentions. Anyways, take this," Milo said, passing Harry the Cold Iron dagger that he kept in his magic belt.

"Why do you have a knife?"

"Okay," Milo said, practically bursting with excitement. "Now, stab it!"

"This is a pretty serious-looking knife."

"Never mind that, stab! Stabbity stab!"

"You carry this around all the time? I think that's against school rules."

"Oh, come on! Those wands are lethal weapons and they give them to eleven-year-olds, what's a Masterwork shiv here and there? Now stab!" Milo was bouncing on his heels.

"Is this like the time you threw a mug at me?"

"Exactly like that! This robe is practically made of Mage Armour!"

"Really?" Harry asked skeptically.

"No, not really. That's not how it works. But it's a simple enough lie that your unenlightened brain can handle it, now stab the robes!"

"Fine!" Harry stabbed them. Much to his surprise, the knife simply glanced off the garment as if it were made of hardened steel. Harry frowned, and stared at the knife.

"Eh? Eh?" Milo said. "What do you think? Cool, no? Totally ordinary Hogwarts uniform until Blam! I get attacked, and guess what? It's godsdamn invincible!"

"This must not be a very good knife," Harry said, ignoring Milo completely and staring at the dagger in his hand.

"And that's not all!" Milo said. "It gives me +1 Caster Level to Conjuration spells!"

"I mean, it can't even cut through an ordinary school uniform."

"That means a whole six more seconds of Hippogriff!"

"It looks sharp. I wonder if it's some sort of trick dagger?"

"Or ten feet more range to Glitterdust!"

"Or maybe you had a metal plate hidden in that robe?"

"That's a whole 20% more Caster Levels!"

"No, then I'd have still cut the robe... must be the knife."

"Or 60% more with the Arcanist's Gloves!"

"Maybe I should try and cut something else with it. That would tell me for sure if it was the knife or the robe."

"And that's not all! I added in Fire Resistance 5 as a custom bonus feature."

"I'll go test it on the curtain of my bed, maybe."

"So now it, and by extension, I, am fire-proof!"

"Well, it works on the bed, that's for sure."

"Well, maybe not fire-proof. More like fire resistant."

"Maybe I should test it on Ron's bed, too, just to be sure."

"But it's more than enough to make me very nearly safe against conventional fire! With this, I can walk into a burning building for up to, on average, six minutes! Or if the dice are against me, only seventy-two seconds before burning to death. But that's still pretty good!"

"Works on Ron's bed just as well as mine. Maybe the knife is exceptionally good at cutting curtains, but suboptimal on cutting robes. There's only one way to be sure."

"You know, I think, somehow, that I'm not getting through to you here."

"Well, it certainly seems capable of cutting Ron's spare robes."

"I'll go show Hermione," Milo said dejectedly. "She knows how to appreciate proper magic when she sees it."

"Fine, fine," Harry said distractedly. "I'll go visit Hagrid," Harry said finally. "He's been a bit down ever since Quirrell killed his dog."

To say that Hagrid was 'a bit down' was rather like saying the Elemental Plane of Water was 'a bit damp.' He'd been aimlessly wandering the halls in tears since Hallowe'en, bemoaning the loss of his beloved omnicidal tricephalous monstrosity. Milo shrugged and walked down the stairs into the Common Room.

True to form, Hermione was curled up on an armchair reading a thick, dusty old tome.

"Hey," said Milo. "Can I see that?"

"Hmmm?" Hermione asked absently, not looking up.

"Scholar's Touch," Milo muttered, tapping the book quickly.

"Hey!" Hermione said, pulling it away from him.

"Interesting," Milo said. "But, no matter how knowledgeable she is on the history of Goblin uprisings in Central Europe, she uses the word 'irregardless' twenty-four times. Just toss it in the fire like the kindling it is, would you?"

"Did you just come here to show off, or was there something else?" Hermione snapped.

"Actually, there was something. I need you to—hang on," Milo said, pulling on his robes. "Okay. I need you to light me on fire. See, my robes are—"

"Incendio," Hermione said, waving her wand in a complicated little pattern. A bright little jet of fire shot out of the tip of Hermione's wand, but dissipated as soon as it touched Milo's robes.

"I'm going to pretend that you waited for me to say 'my robes make me fire resistant' before you tried to immolate me," Milo said.

"I figured it was something like that," Hermione said absently. "Although, I had hoped otherwise. Don't touch my books."

"I'll try to keep that in mind."

Milo saw Hannah sitting in the corner, looking at him for some reason. As soon as he noticed her, she abruptly looked away. Well, there's weirdoes all over.

"Hey," Milo said, walking over to her. "Whatcha up to?"

"Just, uh, reading the Tales of Beedle the Bard," she said.

"It's upside-down," Milo said.

"What, really?" Hannah asked in alarm, glancing down at it. "No, it's not!"

"Nah, but you checked. Anyways, look, there was something I'd been meaning to ask you for a while, now," Milo said. He wasn't quite sure how to go about this.

"Yes?" Hannah asked, her heart beating rapidly.

"Well, it's about something I've sort of been wondering about with regards to you," he said. "Something I just can't figure out."

"Mmhmm?" Hannah said, not trusting herself to speak.

"I was wondering—you remember that day in September, the first time we all had detention for Snape? We were cleaning statues, watched by the Baron?"

Hannah nodded quickly.

"Then you vanished, and I lead the search to find you," (Hannah felt like she was about to burst) "and eventually had to enlist the aid of the Defence Professor and most of Hogwarts' portraits," Milo continued. "But eventually, we found you." Hannah just nodded again. "You were in the lake."

"What?" Hannah asked.

"The lake. We found you in the Hogwarts lake. What on Earth were you doing there?"

"You came here to ask me about the lake." said Hannah flatly.

"Yup," said Milo cheerfully.

"Oh, look at the time, I really must be going now, things to do, people to see, lakes to fall into, gotta run, cheerio, bye." Hannah gathered up her stuff and strode out of the Common Room like a woman with a purpose.

"She went down one of Hogwarts' trick corridors," Hermione said idly, not looking up from her book. "It turned into a slide and she came out right into the lake. If not for the giant squid, I think we'd all be doing it on hot days. And that was a mean thing you just did."

"What, asking her how she got laked? I can't figure how you could put any malicious intent into that."

"Until you did right in front of me, neither could I," Hermione said, turning a page.

"Should I go find her and apologize?"

"No. Absolutely not. Believe me, in this case, it's better to feign ignorance."

"People are weird," Milo said under his breath, staring out the window. Being the middle of winter in Northern Scotland, what he saw was mostly white. He could only see a few yards because snowstorms give a -1 to Spot every 2.5 feet. Milo resisted (barely) the urge to say, 'I'm sure everything's all white.'

"You know," Milo said idly. "If I could take the covers off all the books in the library and stitched them together" (Hermione looked up at him in horror) "then I could read the whole lot with a single Scholar's Touch."

"I think Madam Pince would have the books rebound with your skin as a warning to the rest of us," Hermione said. "And I'd be right there holding you down while she did. Don't—"

"Touch your books, yeah, I remember."

"Why don't you go make some more magic doodads or something?" Hermione asked testily.

"Can't," Milo said. "You can only work on a Magic Item up to eight hours a day."

"Where on Earth did you find eight hours already today? We only got out of class an hour ago!"

"Well, what do you do in History of Magic?"

"I take notes, of course!"

"That's what Mordenkainen's for," Milo grinned.

"You trust your rat," Hermione said, aghast, "to listen in class for you?"

"'Course. He wasn't doing anything else at the time."

"How can your rat write?"

"Easy. He can speak to me in a sort of unique little language. The rules clearly state that 'A literate character (anyone but a Barbarian who has not spent skill points to become literate) can read and write any language she speaks. Each language has an alphabet, though sometimes several spoken languages share a single alphabet.' Mordenkainen is, obviously, not a Barbarian; he can therefore write in an undecipherable code that only I can read, which, incidentally, looks a lot like Elvish."

Hermione frowned.

"That's a pretty shaky read of the rules, and—wait, what rules?"

Milo snorted.

"When you people are taught to count," Milo said, "we're taught to abuse poorly thought-out rules."

"You were in lessons as a child to abuse rules?" Hermione was horrified.

"Nah, skipped 'em all to fight kobolds in the sewers. Myra (cityoflight!cityofmagic!) city law states that 'children under the age of twelve must attend school,' but it never said they had to 'attend school' more than once."

Hermione's mouth moved, but no words came out.

"It's funny, I got an A in my Munchkinry course without ever showing up past the first lesson. All the students that showed up failed."

"Out!" Hermione said, throwing a cushion at him. "Just let me read in peace!" She reached for another cushion.

Milo, despite having faced down an Acromantula, a Troll, dozens of Skeletons, and Kobolds and Goblins beyond measure, was disinclined to face a wrathful Hermione, and promptly utilized a strategic manoeuvre to leave the Common Room.

"I'm bored," Milo declared proudly as he exited the portal.

"That's nice," said the Fat Lady. "You should try hanging on a wall for several hundred years."

Boredom was a state so rare for an adventurer that decided to savour it for as long as he could. Being boredom, of course, this only lasted for about a microsecond before he was dying for something to do.

"Hey," Milo said suddenly. "You know about this world's quaint little culture, right?"

"I know anything and everything that can be discovered by hanging on a wall, watching students walk past, and pretending not to hide a secret passageway. So, yes."

"This Christmas thing," Milo said. "I'm led to understand that people give each other presents."

"Correct," said the Fat Lady.

"Now, when they say 'people'—"

"—that includes you, yes."

"Crap."

"Indeed."

"And if, say, someone were to hypothetically upset a friend of theirs in the days leading up to this gift-giving holiday, and were, for some reason, recommended against direct apology—"

"Is this friend female?"

"Yes."

"Then the gift had better be damn special."

"Crap."

"Indeed."

"I have, what, eight days?"

"Seven."

"I'd best get started, then."

"Correct."

o—o—o—o

The vast majority of Hogwarts' students went home over the holidays, and for those who remained, the two week break was a time to lie around in their respective Common Rooms, playing Exploding Snap and (for the less danger-inclined) wizarding chess.

Not so for Milo, who spent day and night working on Christmas presents, researching spells, and 'resting,' (really, planning and setting traps for the arrival of the dreaded Santa Claws) each in exactly 8 hour increments per day. When Christmas Eve rolled around, Ron and Harry were surprised to see Milo, weary and exhausted, trudge zombie-like into their dormitory.

"Blimey," said Ron, who was staying at the castle because his parents went to visit his brother Charlie in Romania, "we thought you'd gone home for the holidays."

"Where have you been?" Harry asked. "Nobody's seen you at mealtimes, in the Common Room, or even in bed."

"Christmas," Milo slurred.

"When was the last time you slept?" asked Harry, looking equal parts concerned and amused.

"Over a hundred thousand, eight hundred rounds ago," Milo said. People, from where he was from, were very good at telling time—but only in rounds, a unit of six seconds.

"What are you carrying, there?" Ron asked, pointing at a heavy bag Milo had slung over his shoulder.

"Christmas," Milo repeated, and slipped into unconsciousness in his four-poster bed.

"Nutter," Ron said. "But at least he's on our side."

The residents of Gryffindor Tower awoke to an unpleasant surprise on Christmas morning.

"Glitterdust! Obscuring Mist! Summon 1d4+1 Celestial Giant Fire Beetles!"

"Ah! Gerroff!"

"I've gone blind!"

"He was here! Father Christmas was here! While I slept! Oh, why did I sleep? Who let me sleep? We didn't post any sentries! Grease!" Milo was standing in the middle of the dorm, casting offensive spells at random. The room was full of dense fog, concealing everything except for blindingly bright sparkling gold particles of magic and the red, glowing eyes of four giant beetles that were skittering about, clicking loudly. "We'll all be killed!"

Fortunately, Milo ran out of spells in about a minute, and the protesting struggles of Ron and Harry managed to convince him that Santa "Claws" wasn't about to jump out from under a bed and kill him.

"And that," said Ron, "is why you need to sleep more than once every eight nights. Happy Christmas, by the way."

"I've got some presents!" Harry said in surprise, the small pile of wrapped gifts visible now that the dust had cleared and the noise had stopped.

"What were you expe—" Ron began, but Milo cut him off.

"—You don't normally get presents?" Milo asked.

"Nah," said Harry. "This is the first time!"

"So... so... they're not mandatory? I didn't have to get you anything?"

"Blimey," said Ron, "I don't think you've quite grasped the meaning of Christmas."

Harry groaned.

"If anyone suggests we go on an adventure to discover the true meaning of Christmas," he said, "I'm going to have to put my foot down."

"An adventure, eh?" Milo asked, his eyes alight.

"No. No. No adventures," insisted Ron firmly. "We open presents. We have Christmas Dinner. We play games. We have fun with friends and family. That's it."

"Oh," said Milo, looking downcast.

The first package opened was by Harry from his aunt and uncle. It contained something Milo had never seen before, something... unnatural.

"What is it?" Milo asked, looking fascinated.

"I dunno," said Ron. "Look at the shape!"

"It's a fifty-pence piece," Harry said, biting down laughter.

"Well, where's the rest of it?" Milo asked.

"That's all they sent."

"So, if this is a piece of the Fifty Pence," Milo said thoughtfully, "what happens when we combine all seven shards—there are seven, right? It's usually either seven or three—do we become masters of the Fifty Pence?"

Harry doubled over with laughter.

"No, mate, I heard my dad talking about this once," Ron said in hushed tones. "It's what Muggles use for money!"

"What, this?" Milo asked. "It's not made of gold, platinum, silver, or even copper! How do they know how much it's worth?"

"My dad couldn't figure it out, either," Ron said. "He theorizes that Muggles have a sense that wizards lack that tells them how much their money is worth, and my dad's a professional."

"I guess they'd have to have something to balance out their lack of magic," Milo mused.

Harry was in real danger of dying due to lack of air, he was laughing so hard.

"I don't trust it," Ron said. "If it's not made of precious metals, what's to stop people from just Transfiguring more of it?"

Milo gasped.

"They don't have any magic at all! They can't just Transmute or Transfigure money!" Milo was amazed.

"Whoa," said Ron. "That's mindblowing. They can use anything as money, then. I should write my dad about this."

In the end, Harry let Ron keep the coin to show Mr Weasley, and turned to his other presents.

"You got me new spectacles, Milo?" Harry asked when he opened Milo's gift. "They... look exactly my current ones."

"So nobody will know the difference," Milo said, tapping the side of his nose in a conspiratorial way.

"Er... thank you? I suppose a spare will come in handy," Harry said dubiously.

"Put them on," Milo insisted. Harry, obligingly, slipped off his current pair and put on Milo's new ones.

"Blimey!" Harry gasped.

"They look like ordinary specs," Milo said, "but they're really Eyes of the Eagle. They give +5 to Spot—that means you can see things fifty feet away with the same level of detail as you could see something right in front of your nose without them—and, because they're enchanted using my form of magic, none of your wizards can tell that they're anything out of the ordinary."

Harry stared at Milo for a moment, then his face broke into a wide grin.

"So I can wear them during Quidditch without breaking any rules!" he said. "Or at least, without getting caught. Thanks, Milo! These are awesome."

"You'll have to get a proper eye doctor to have the lenses done in your prescription, though," said Milo, who had asked Hermione earlier about how glasses worked. "Until then, the -2 penalty you incur will counter out some of the bonus."

"Shouldn't be too much of a problem," Harry said.

"Hope you like them," Milo said. "You did pay for them, after all."

Ron, who was staring at Harry's gift enviously, sifted through his (rather large; he has a big family) pile of presents to find Milo's. Unwrapping it revealed an ordinary looking quill.

"What's it do?" Ron asked eagerly.

"It writes words," Milo said.

"That's all?" Ron asked, sounding disappointed.

"Yeah... but it does it all by itself. I made this one custom, it's my own invention. See, what you do is, you just tap it to a piece of paper or parchment or whatever to activate it. It'll immediately start copying whatever you were looking at when it started, and won't stop till it's done or after 2,500 words, whichever comes first. I figure it'll come in dead handy when you're copying Hermione's notes," Milo explained. "It'll even turn the page and keep going on the next one when necessary."

"Blimey," Ron gasped, holding the quill like it was a long-lost family member. "That's bloody brilliant."

"Only works once a day, though, so keep it away from parchment so you don't trigger it by accident. I call it the Pen of Plagiarism +5."

"Plus five what?" Ron asked.

"Nothing," Milo said unabashedly, "but where I come from, you can charge exponentially more for stuff if it's plus something."

Milo turned to his presents, which, as it turned out, were (as far as he was concerned) even better than minor magic items. Each of Neville, Harry, Ron, and Hermione had decided independently to get him a huge package of Every Flavoured Beans.

"I think," Milo said around a huge mouthful of the bizarre sweets, "that I like this whole Christmas thing. A lot of work, though."

Harry (wearing an emerald sweater knitted by Mrs Weasley) opened his last package. A silvery-grey, gossamer cloth floated out of it and fell to the floor.

Ron gasped.

"Huh," Harry said. "Looks like a cloak."

"Put it on," Ron urged. "If it's what I think it is... well, there's only one way to find out."

"You," Harry said pointedly, "have been spending too much time with Hermione." Nevertheless, did, and promptly vanished.

Milo and Ron both gasped.

"It's an Invisibility Cloak!" Ron said, while Milo said "It's a Cloak of Invisibility!"

Harry pulled it off.

"Why do they call it that?" he asked.

"'Cause it makes you invisible," said Ron.

"Duh," added Milo.

"I didn't feel invisible," Harry said skeptically. "Here, you put it on," he passed it to Ron, who held it reverently. True to form, Ron vanished as soon as he put it on.

"Huh," said Harry. "Don't see that every day."

"I do, actually," Milo pointed out. He usually prepared Invisibility once a day. "Oh! I've been meaning to test something, actually. Harry, put it on again."

When Harry complied, Milo cast See Invisibility. Harry appeared in front of him as a translucent shape.

"Excellent," Milo said. "Score one for my magic, for once." Must be because of the vague wording of See Invisibility, Milo thought. It just says "reveals any objects or creatures that are invisible," not "creatures that are affected by Invisibility."

"Did it come with a card?" Ron asked curiously. "Those things are really expensive; I wonder who would spend that much on you?"

Harry rooted about on the ground for a moment, then produced a small note with a handwritten message.

Your father left this in my possession before
he died. It is time it was returned to you.
Use it well.
A Very Merry Christmas to you.

"That," Milo said, "is singularly unhelpful. Put it on the list."

Harry was looking at the note strangely.

"What's the matter?" Ron asked.

"Nothing," Harry said. Milo shrugged, and began preparing spells for the day. Fortunately, his ... episode ... in the morning had come from yesterday's spells. Harry and Ron settled down to play a game of Exploding Snap.

"Hey," Milo said suddenly, having finished renewing his allotment of spells. "Anyone know if Hannah's staying for the holidays?"

"Uh," said Ron. "Yeah, I think I saw her at dinner the other day, with Lavender Brown."

"Cool. Bye," Milo said, leaving the dorm abruptly. On his way out, he passed Fred and George, wearing matching Weasley jumpers.

"—and then we'll say 'we know we're called Gred and Forge,'" Fred was saying in a low voice.

"Oh, hey Milo," George said as Milo passed.

"Hey," Milo said, barely giving them a glance. "Wait," he said, and turned. "Have either of you seen Hannah Abbot around?"

"Yeah," said Fred. "Last I saw, she was heading out of the Common Room."

"Oh," George added. "She was wearing a coat and scarf, so she was probably going outside."

"What, in that?" Milo asked, gesturing at the window. The snow was really picking up. "Didn't you try and stop her?"

"Yeah, but she ignored us. Don't worry, I'm sure she'll be—"

"—all white."

Milo groaned, and not just because of the terrible pun. He was going to have to go out and find her to deliver her mandatory apology present. Milo hustled out of the Common Room and down the stairs to the Great Hall, pulling on parts of his Cold Weather Outfit from his Belt of Hidden Pouches as he went. On the way, he decided that his next project would be to make his uniform Shiftweave as well, which allowed it to transform into other outfits instantly.

Milo opened the massive Great Hall doors to find snow piled up to his head.

"I am not walking in that," Milo said. "Fly," he cast, and suddenly felt himself become weightless. "Locate Object—Hannah's Robes," he cast, and felt a light tug to his right. Milo effortlessly floated up off the ground and through the heavy snow.

Shouldn't she have left tracks? Milo wondered, looking around. Of course, it was possible that the snow had filled them in already... but really, with snow that deep, she'd have to dig a tunnel to get around.

Something felt very wrong about this whole situation. The wind was picking up, and the cold began to bite effortlessly through Milo's robes (Milo decided an Endure Elements enchantment was in order as well). You'd have to be suicidal to willingly venture out here, Milo thought. And she went alone? Highly suspect.

As Milo flew, skimming a few feet above the ground, he felt his Locate Object spell abruptly end.

Okay... Milo thought, his teeth chattering. Either she entered an area warded against Divination, she's surrounded by lead, someone dispelled my spell, or she's out of range.

Let's assume the first one is out, because there isn't much interaction between my magic and the local strain. It's possible their wards against detection would work, but improbable. My spell can't have been dispelled, because I'd have noticed when I made the opposed Caster Level check... unless the local equivalent doesn't allow a check.

Milo groaned. He really had no idea what happened.

Only one thing for it.

"Circle Dance," Milo cast quietly, swapping out Summon Monster III. Circle Dance is an obscure spell that locates the direction from you to a creature (much like Locate Object or Locate Creature) except that it had no range limit. However, it takes a minute to cast, burns a 3rd-level spell slot, and only has an instantaneous effect—if the target moves, you won't have any idea. On the plus side, it gives a vague impression of the target's physical and emotional condition.

Milo spun in a circle with his eyes closed until he finished casting the spell, which left him feeling dizzy. He opened his eyes, pointing in the direction she was in, and knowing she was unharmed and, emotionally, perfectly content (which was concerning, but not the most concerning thing).

Milo groaned.

He was looking directly at the Forbidden Forest.

Really, he wondered, why did I ever think this little trip wouldn't end up with me in mortal danger?

With a sigh and a longing glance at the comfortable Gryffindor tower, now only a speck of light in the whiteout, Milo sped off towards the forest.

Milo had just gotten past the edge of the forest when Fly ran out of duration, and he fell heavily in the snow.

"Should have known," he said, his teeth chattering, "that, if foul weather is mentioned, I'd soon be out slogging in it. The c-c-castle is making me c-c-complacent."

With difficulty, Milo cast another Locate Object on Hannah's clothing (swapping out the previously prepared Invisibility). To his surprise, she was somewhere behind him.

At the start of a combat, all characters involved have to make an Initiative roll with a bonus based off of their Dexterity and a few other things. This determines the order in which combatants act—people who rolled higher on Initiative, due to luck or by virtue of possessing quick reflexes, act before those who rolled lower. This makes Nerveskitter (a 1st level spell which grants +5 to Initiative rolls) an extremely unusual spell, as it must be cast while rolling Initiative, or, in other words, after a character is aware that there is trouble but before his muscles have had time to respond to his commands. For someone such as you or I, this is patently impossible. A Wizard, however, is somehow capable of both speaking the verbal components and waving his hands about in a complicated gesture to cast the spell before he is physically capable of doing either.

"Nerveskitter," Milo cast, speaking every syllable simultaneously and in harmony, in blatant violation of the laws of common sense. He was surrounded by a brief blue glow, and rolled to the side just as a glowing red bolt of magic flew past the space he had previously occupied. The bolt hit a tree, pieces of bark flying away from the contact point.

"Mirror Image," he cast, and a pair of illusory Milo duplicates appeared next to him. The real Milo lay down flat in the snow, minimizing his visibility.

Another red bolt of light hit one solidly in the torso, causing the image to fall to the ground, motionless.

Milo quickly ran through his options. He had no idea what the location or identity of his attacker was, which precluded the used of Grease, Glitterdust, or, in fact, any offensive spell.

"Summon Hippogriff," Milo cast. Hippogriffs could track by scent, so didn't strictly require vision. Milo grinned, happy that he had learned Summon Monster III after his battle with the Troll.

The proud horse/eagle hybrid appeared in front of Milo with a shriek and ran forwards. It got about ten feet before Milo saw a green flash, and the summoned monster keeled over, dead.

Holy crap, Milo thought. They're using the Killing Curse.

And Milo was running low on spells.

Okay, he thought in a panic. Okay. It's not so bad. They clearly can't see you, either, right? Or you'd be dead already.

A few more curses flew over Milo's head and hit some evergreen trees, which promptly turned brown and withered, dropping needles.

And they can cast more than one per round. Or there's three of them, ganging up on me.

A desperate plan came to Milo's mind. None of his prepared spells would help him, as far as he could tell, so he had to use something he could cast without prior preparation—a Divination. Most casters believed Divination to be a soft school, but Milo knew better.

Divinations could kill.

"True Strike," he cast, granting his next attack a +20 to hit, which would be enough to hit an unusually petite fly at a distance from about here to Jupiter.

More curses flew over his head.

"Guided Shot," he cast, which allowed his next attack to ignore cover and concealment. Neither of these would help him target a Grease or Glitterdust, or even a Fireball if he knew how to cast it, as those were all area attacks. They would only help him with a direct attack, the kind of which required accuracy—also known as the type of spell Milo avoided like the plague.

So, instead of casting a spell at all, he drew his (so far, never used) Cold Iron dagger and threw it in a completely random direction. Milo's plan was to then cast Locate Object on the dagger, which did a paltry 1d4-1 damage (practically nonlethal against the targets Milo was used to), which would let him identify the location of his foe, so he could follow up with an arcane barrage.

It was only after the dagger left his fingers, and he had confirmed a critical hit for double damage, that he realized his mistake.

The dagger, guided by Milo's magic, had flown in exactly the same direction as his previous cast of Locate Object, which was still active, told him Hannah was standing.

Milo heard a sickening thud, and the curses abruptly stopped flying.

Chapter 19: Visitors

Author's Notes: As promised, Bonus Chapter!

EDIT: A helpful reviewer pointed out that in Britain, people say "anyway" instead of "anyways," something of which I had no idea. There's no way I'm going to be able to get all of the local slang and things right, but nevertheless, I went back and edited as many instances of those which I could find. Milo, coming from another world (which the fates have decided, extremely conveniently it would seem, speaks Canadian English) still says adds the "s." If I make any dialect-related slipups like that in the future, feel free to PM me (or drop it in a review, of course, but PM's are somewhat less embarrassing).

It's just another thing like Wizard/wizard and Red Cap/Redcap that distinguishes Milo from the locals.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Deciding that saying something 'tastes like Christmas Dinner' would be categorically impossible for a Dark Wizard utilizing their titular Dark Powers to mentally control an injured eleven-year-old girl, Milo had relented and returned Hannah's wand in order for her to magic up some fire to warm their freezing tent.

It was late—Milo wasn't sure how late, because his nap of unknown length had thrown his perception even of passing rounds and the sun went down very early this far north in the dead of winter—when they heard yet another audible crunch in the snow outside, waking Milo up from a deep sleep he hadn't quite realized he'd ever started.

Milo cursed (figuratively speaking—not a literal Curse. Milo briefly wondered if that was the reason the locals seemed to use the word 'cuss') under his breath, and not only because there was a decent probability that the Redcap's (or "Red Cap" as the locals called them) buddies had come to finish what the first one had started (or, perhaps, to finish off the first one, yum). He required eight hours of continuous, uninterrupted rest to prepare new spells and regain hit points, so his injuries (which would have certainly killed someone from Hannah's world) were exactly as painful and sore as they were however long ago it had been since they'd been inflicted.

Milo glanced over at Hannah, whose eyes were wide and alert.

Well, we're screwed, he thought.

Milo, as stealthily as he could (which is not, admittedly, particularly stealthy without any ranks in Hide or Move Silently), pulled his quarterstaff out of his Belt of Hidden Pouches and raised the tent flap very slightly. Unfortunately, he couldn't see anything but snow from his narrow window.

"Stay here," Milo said quietly to Hannah. "I'll go see what's outside."

Hannah, her face pale and ashen, became determined.

"No," she whispered. "I've got a wand, and I can do magic, which is more than I can say for you."

"But—" Milo said, a hundred protests coming to mind. You're not a PC. Your injuries are debilitating, mine are not. You're lower level. The spells you know are not combat optimized.

But despite everything, the practical part of his mind agreed she did have a point. Hannah, despite being a novice at magic, had no limit on spells per day and even the simple Jinxes and Hexes that Hogwarts students used on each other to settle heated disagreements would be more effective than a quarterstaff wielded at a measly +2 BAB and a -1 Strength Penalty—at least, when used in the number that Hannah was capable of, which was infinite.

"Fine, we'll go together," he said at last. "On three, we leap out of the tent and catch them by surprise—try to stay behind me, my robes are enchanted to protect me. I'll club anything that gets close, you hex anything that moves." Milo couldn't believe he was volunteering to tank damage so someone else could cast. It was just so, so wrong.

"Okay," Hannah said, fear and excitement battling evident in almost equal parts in her voice.

"And remember—you're braver than you think."

"I'm braver than I think. I'm braver than I think," Hannah said, constantly repeating the words under her breath as she did in the Sorting Ceremony.

"One... Two..." Milo took a deep breath. "Three!"

The two heavily injured spellcasters did not so much charge out of the tent, which would have been, perhaps, more dramatically appropriate, as they did stagger out painfully. They were a pretty pathetic sight, and the only foes they would have intimidated would be those who were both squeamish about blood and who were in possession of excellent night vision.

To the heroes in question, however, it felt as if they were leading the charge in the Battle of Vienna, with the might of tens of thousands of heavily armed and armoured elite cavaliers at their back, all thirsting for blood.

"WAAAAAAAGH!"

"Wha' in the ruddy hell?" came a surprised, thickly accented voice from the chill darkness.

"Mister Hagrid?" Hannah asked, stunned.

"Dancing Lights," Milo cast, while Hannah cast Lumos. Four glowing white spheres of light shot out of Milo's hands, flying in a search pattern around their immediate vicinity while Hannah's wand tip glowed brightly. Hagrid's huge body came into clear view, holding his crossbow in one hand and Fang's leash in another.

"Wha' are you lot doin' out here?" Hagrid asked. "And is tha'—is tha' blood?"

Milo narrowed his eyes.

"How do I know you're really Hagrid?" he asked suspiciously, leaning heavily on his quarterstaff.

"Wha' kinda question is tha'?" Hagrid asked. "Yeh know another bloke o' my size who jus' happens ter have a crossbow an' a dog?"

"I think," Hannah said quietly to Milo, "that we'd best trust him. He's kind of our only hope."

Milo still stared at him suspiciously, trying to decide what he would do if he had the ability to simply possess people—something he didn't, as he'd forsworn the Enchantment school altogether when he specialized in Conjuration. Presumably, powerful wizards and witches had some form of defence against mental intrusion—otherwise, Dumbledore would long since have been turned into a puppet of some Dark Wizard and used to rule the world. Likely, that ruled McGonagall, Snape, Flitwick, and Quirrell out as well as potential puppets (although, not as suspects necessarily. Milo needed another glance at his Plot flowchart just to remind himself who was currently trying to kill him). Hagrid, who apparently had no magical power of his own at all, was therefore an obvious choice to possess... at least, at first glance. If Milo were behind this, he'd simply choose another student. Obviously, the possessor was able to force his puppets to use spells the puppets would normally be unable to, which essentially bumped up any possessed student to Dark Master level of threat.

So, assuming his possessor had, in fact, any brains at all (and Milo's numerous assumptions were correct), Hagrid was probably just Hagrid.

"Okay," Milo said. "But be careful."

"Now, can someone explain wha' the ruddy hell is goin' on? Actually, nevermind tha'," Hagrid said, looking closer at the extent of Hannah's and Milo's injuries. "We gotta get yeh up ter the hospital wing. Can yeh walk? Ah, nevermind, I'll jus' carry yeh. Yeh can explain on the way."

Hagrid hung his crossbow from a strap on his shoulder, and held out a big, meaty hand to Hannah and Milo. Neither he nor Hannah had the same level of friendship with Hagrid that Harry (and, to a lesser extent, Ron and Hermione) had developed, and the pair of them hesitated for a moment.

Milo shrugged and climbed aboard, Hannah soon following suit.

Hagrid carried the pair of them in a surprisingly gentle manner, given his somewhat brutish appearance. On the way, Milo decided he might as well tell Hagrid what happened. Hannah, however, was being unusually silent.

"This morning, I heard that Hannah went out into the snow—"

"Are yeh mad, girl?" Hagrid asked Hannah.

"Sorry," Hannah said in a quiet voice.

"Hang on Hagrid, it wasn't her idea. I went out after her—"

"Why didn' yeh jus' tell Dumbledore? Or McGongall?" Hagrid asked.

"Er..." Milo said. Why hadn't he told anyone? In hindsight, what he'd done seemed remarkably stupid. "Anyways, I tracked her down with magic, eventually, but she tried to hex me."

"Why would yeh do tha'?" Hagrid asked. "Ruddy bad manners, if yeh ask me."

"Wasn't her choice, Hagrid," Milo said again, patiently. "she was being controlled by magic, or something."

"What?" Hagrid asked, and stopped moving. "Are yeh sure?"

"Oh, pretty sure alright," Milo said, Hannah's horrible, uncaring expression coming back to mind.

"We have ter tell Dumbledore," Hagrid said, and started moving again, this time at a greatly increased pace. Milo carried on, explaining about the encounter with the Redcap.

"Why didn' yer jus' use—" Hagrid began.

"Uh," Milo interrupted, not wanting to go into details about how he was a different sort of wizard. "Never quite got a hang of that spell."

"Well, wha' abou'—"

"Nope, nor that one."

"Yeh really gotta do more practicin'," Hagrid urged. "Them's ruddy simple spells."

"Yeah... I'll do that."

"An' the Redcap's wha' hurt Hannah?" Hagrid asked, wading through the snow as if it wasn't there.

Milo fell silent for a moment, at a loss for words. The terrible fear he'd felt when he'd first realized who his attacker was returned like a defeated Dark Wizard with access to the Clone spell.

"Yes," Hannah said. "Used Milo's knife on me. Fortunately Milo knows a bit of Muggle medicine, or..." she trailed off, and fell back into silence.

"Firs' sensible thing yeh did all day," Hagrid said critically. "An' I'll be havin' a word with Flitwick. Healin' Charms ought ter be on the curriculum; ruddy useful, they are. Er. Not tha' I know firsthand, o' course."

"So," Milo said, wanting to press through this next awkward bit as quickly as possible, "I, er, killed the Redcap."

"Though' yeh said yeh didn' have yer wand?"

"I used a big stick."

"The other Red Caps aren' gonna like tha'," Hagrid said, concerned. "Bu' it explains Fang."

"Oh?" Milo asked, curious.

"Bou' a half hour ago, he made a righ' racket, so I let him out. Must've smelled its blood—Red Caps have a very distinct scent, yeh know. Led me righ' ter yeh. Migh' a' saved yer lives."

"That's... very convenient," Milo said, looking at the dog. Suspicions started to grow in his mind, but he shook them off—surely he was just being paranoid, seeing puppeteering behind every shadow. Besides, he thought, why would the Dark Wizard have possessed the dog to help save me? Whoever it was clearly wanted me dead.

Unless...

Milo's brow furrowed, lost deep in thought despite the freezing cold and rumblings from Hagrid, who was still chastising them for being reckless.

Could it have been reconnaissance? Milo wondered. Did someone attack me just to find out how I'd fight back? Hannah did open up with Stunners, I think—although, why they're called Stunners, I have no idea, as they leave the target Unconscious, not merely Stunned—although she did fire off a number of Killing Curses as well...

And in any case, if someone wants to find out how I fight, it can only be because they plan on fighting me themselves. Meaning they want me dead. Meaning they would have just left me to, hopefully, expire in the cold.

Something still felt wrong, though, although Milo couldn't quite figure out what it was.

Regardless of their intentions, Milo thought, I may have revealed my hand. They saw Glitterdust, Grease, and Summon Monster III. They'll probably have worked out a counter to them by the time they challenge me in person—and they know about my last-ditch contingency plan... Milo cursed himself. Which can easily be countered by preventing me from speaking. And in any case, Gating in enough Efreeti to Wish myself into omnipotence would take minutes or hours, so is effectively impossible in the middle of a combat.

So, Milo thought as Hagrid carried him and Hannah to safety, what would I do to kill me, given what I'd know about myself and the local magic?

The answer was surprisingly simple.

Surprise attack with an Avada Kedavra loaded with as many Attack Bonus-boosting buffs possible.

To which the only defence was... what? To anticipate the attack? To not be there to begin with? Death Ward would counter the Killing Curse, but it was a Cleric spell. Nerveskitter would help him win on Initiative, but that wouldn't do much if the attacker had a Surprise Round.

Milo needed to have a good, long look at his spellbooks to determine what, if anything, he could do to counter such an attack.

A loud creak broke Milo out of his train of thought. With a start, Milo realized that they were already at the castle, and Hagrid had just pushed the main door open with his shoulder. Hagrid wasted no time carrying them up the stairs to the hospital wing, which Milo was starting to think of as a second home.

The giant groundskeeper rapped hard on the doors until Pomfrey, still in her dressing gown, opened it sleepily. She took one look at the children and sighed.

"What did he do this time?" she asked (Milo resented, somewhat, the implied accusation that it had been his fault—until he remembered that Hannah's injuries actually had been by his hand), but despite the exasperation evident in her tone, she had them lying down on the firm cots and checked over in record time—after shooing out Hagrid, that is, who didn't mind as he was leaving anyways to go find Dumbledore.

She gasped when she saw the extent of their injuries.

"What happened to you?" she asked Hannah. Then, after thinking a moment, added "No, nevermind. Dumbledore will sort that out later; don't say anything." A few Healing Charms later and Hannah was out of the worst of it, albeit still exhausted and sore.

"And as for you," she said, turning back to Milo, "I think all you need is bandages, a Cleaning Charm to stave off infection, and prolonged bedrest, based on your rather numerous prior visits to my hospital wing." The truth was, though she didn't say anything, that she was afraid to do anything else—she lay awake at night in a cold sweat caused by wondering what the hell the reason was behind his physiology, especially his apparent super healing powers.

"But—" Milo protested.

"No buts. Now if you excuse me, I believe I'm shortly going to have to fend off the Headmaster, and it always helps to have a certain measure of mental preparation before attempting so daunting a task. You two just try and get some sleep."

The strict little mediwitch bustled off, muttering under her breath about how people never seem to require emergency medical attention at a reasonable hour, showing no consideration whatsoever. That left Milo and Hannah alone in the dark hospital wing (with the exception of the gently snoring Neville Longbottom, who had broken several ribs when Peeves had dropped a bust of some old, long forgotten headmaster on him. As it turned out, Peeves had actually, as far as anyone could tell, dropped it by accident. Go figure.)

"So," Milo started saying to break the awkward silence. "How about that local sports te—"

"Why did you go looking for me?" Hannah asked. Then she paused for a moment. "I mean, before you knew I was out in the snow. Agh, you know what I mean."

"Right!" said Milo, who felt sort of dumb. "What time is it?" There was a clock on the wall, but he still couldn't make heads or tails of all the numbers.

"Uh," Hannah said, momentarily thrown. "It's, uh, 11:54. But what does—"

"So, it's still Christmas?" he asked.

"Yeah, for six—no, wait, make that five minutes."

"Awesome," Milo said, visibly relieved. "Okay, hang on a second, I need to find something." Sifting through the many pockets of his Belt of Hidden Pouches (technically, he could just hold his hand over it and order the belt to spit out whichever item inside that he wanted, but he wanted to stay out of the habit of doing things that way to prevent from announcing to the world what he was about to draw), he eventually found the small package he was looking for.

"I had a lot of difficulty with this," Milo admitted. "See, where I'm from, we don't really give presents very frequently. People, well, Adventurers are least, tend to hoard their money and treasure and wouldn't dream of parting with it for anything. When we get presents, it's usually for, I dunno, rescuing the Prince's sister from bandits or clearing out a cave of Orcs. We tend to ignore holidays, and, frankly, I don't know what the NPCs do during them. So I'm kind of new to this whole Christmas thing; it's... bizarre. So I asked around, and from what I understand, most people buy something from shopkeepers that they think the recipient would enjoy. I tried that, at first, but ran into a number of difficulties—anything I wanted, I'd have to owl order, obviously, because there aren't any shops in Hogwarts. But also... this world is strange. I don't understand what any of the local wizarding stuff is or does, most of the time, so I wouldn't know what to buy or even where to look for what to buy. Back in Azel, there's strict price and production controls and everybody knows exactly what's for sale everywhere and that a bucket will always go for five Silver Pieces. They're posted in the Equipment Lists. And don't even get me started on the Muggle stuff; it's more foreign to me than Psionics."

Hannah stared at him oddly, apparently not understanding some of the terminology but, generally speaking, getting the gist.

"You didn't have to... I mean, you shouldn't have worried about it."

"I was led to believe it was important," he shrugged. "Anyways, I came to the conclusion fairly quickly that if I was going to get you a present, I'd have to make it myself. The thing is, mundane stuff—er, non-magical, that is—can, from what I can tell, be made by Muggles better and faster than anything I could pull off, even if I used magic to help. But what I can make, and I'm pretty good at it, is Magic Items."

"But, that sounds really expensive..."

"Eh," Milo shrugged. "I've got ways of making money fast, if I need to. That wasn't the big problem."

"What was the big problem?" Hannah asked riveted.

"Every single Magic Item—and I mean every Magic Item that has ever been designed—is for killing, or in some manner facilitating the killing of, Goblins and Dragons and things. That, or for carrying their stuff away afterwards. Any other use is largely the result of happy accident or complete afterthought. And killing Goblins isn't something that you seem particularly interested in," Milo said, as if the notion was both unthinkable and unpleasant, "so I had to see if I could twist the purpose of already existing Magic Items for more... civilian" (Milo was about to say 'NPC,' but stopped himself at the last second) "purposes. And there were a few that could do that—I mean, this Belt of Hidden Pouches I have would be handy for anyone, right? Same with a Magic Bedroll or maybe a bag of Everlasting Rations." Milo paused for a moment. "Something with Endure Elements, now that I think about it, probably would have been a good idea. But anyways, everything I found, even then, required spells only available to Clerics or Druids or whatever. Wizards are usually... a bit more on the offensive side of things."

"Look, it's totally fine if you didn't get me anything," Hannah said quietly. "I wouldn't have minded."

"So, the list of already designed Magic Items exhausted, I realized I had to design something from scratch, so I turned to the spells I did know to see what I could do. I had... similar problems. To a somewhat lesser extent, a Wizard's spells are almost all designed for combat; even the utility ones are mostly to help a Wizard get to—or, knowing Wizards, away from—combat. There was nothing that seemed particularly... fun," Milo said the last word as if it were from an unfamiliar foreign language. "So, I said, 'screw it!'" (Milo's actual wording, which he wisely decided not to repeat to Hannah, was somewhat different from this) "'I'll do what an Adventurer does best and combine spells that were never designed to be combined, gosh darn it!' And this, your present, is the result. But before I give it to you, I need an answer to a very important question."

"What's that?" Hannah asked, looking somewhat surprised.

"What's your favourite animal?" Milo asked.

Hannah thought about it for a moment.

"Hamsters," she said. "Definitely hamsters."

"Okay," Milo said. "Cool. Just one second." Milo had left, literally, one second in the Magic Item crafting process unfinished when he'd originally made the item right before Christmas Eve. The result was the he could, at this point, still change any of the variables that had to be decided 'during item creation.' "Now, here you are, Hannah Abbot," Milo passed her the present, wrapped in festive-looking holiday paper. "Happy Christmas."

"Thank you," she said, accepting the package and, not being one of those fussy people who simply remove the tape and leave the paper unblemished, tore the wrapping paper to pieces from the middle outwards in about a third of a second. Then she gasped. Inside, in a tiny box, was a tiny, fine (admittedly, somewhat lopsided looking) fragile-looking silver lily that could be attached to clothes by means of a minute pin on the back of the stem. An actual silversmith would shudder at the sight of Milo's somewhat crude handiwork, but, all told, it was pretty well done given that Milo didn't actually have in ranks in any form of Craft.

"I made it by heating up a Sickle until it was malleable enough to sculpt," Milo said. "Couldn't have done it without those dragonhide gloves we have for Herbology and Potions."

"It's beautiful," Hannah said, somewhat breathless. No doubt her perceptions were somewhat addled by her traumatic day, sleep deprivation, and whatever was in the potions that Pomfrey had prescribed for her, as the silver lily was could only be described as beautiful when using the loosest possible sense of the word.

Milo shrugged, somewhat embarrassed.

"That's not really the point," he admitted. In truth, he'd made it out of silver so it could be used as an improvised weapon against Devils if necessary (it never hurts to be prepared, after all) but Milo decided, for some reason, against saying so at that precise moment. "If you tap it and say 'I'm bored,' it'll—actually, just tap it and say that you're bored and you'll see."

Looking at Milo curiously, Hannah complied.

"I'm bored," she said, tapping the silver pin.

Nothing happened.

"Oh, right, you have to be wearing it first," Milo said. "Forgot about that part."

Hannah, looking extremely curious, pinned the lily to the front of her robes.

"I'm bored," she repeated, with another tap. Suddenly, a small, fluffy, impossibly cute—in fact, almost sickeningly so—brown and white hamster appeared in her hands. "It's so cute!" Hannah squealed in the manner of little girls everywhere as the hamster scurried up her arm, chirping in a manner that would make real hamsters feel like they had to go and watch Die Hard while doing one-handed push-ups just to counter the sheer adorability. The hamster didn't have fat so much as it had pudge, fur so much as it had fluff, or eyes so much as it had big, glassy, shiny windows to your very soul. Simply seeing it required a Will save, or you were compelled to want to hug it (okay, not really, but it may as well have).

Milo was particularly proud about his little invention, which was simply a tricked-out Wondrous Item of Unseen Servant and Minor Image (both of which he had had to research specifically for this task) and a little Detect Thoughts. The Servant, which was a formless, invisible blob capable of moving around and exerting a limited amount of force, was surrounded with an illusory body of an animal chosen during item creation (in this case, a hamster), the specifics of which were chosen by using a brief Detect Thoughts-like effect on the pin's first user to find the form that user would find to be maximally cute. The Servant was then ordered to play with the user until dismissed, unless otherwise commanded.

"This," Hannah said, the hamster running up her arm to the shoulder, "is the best Christmas present ever."

"Thank you! Er, or you're welcome. I'm not actually sure which is applicable here," he admitted.

"I believe both are perfectly acceptable," Hannah said, stifling a laugh.

"You just tap the pin and say 'Bye' and it'll go away until you reactive it," Milo explained. "It can do other stuff, if you tell it to, like carry or clean things."

"Things like Hogwarts statues?" Hannah asked eagerly.

"Things exactly like Hogwarts statues," Milo said.

"Thank you," Hannah said again. "Really. I mean it, you clearly put a lot of effort into this. I was just going to get you a big pack of Every Flavoured Beans, 'cause of how much you enjoyed them on Hallowe'en, but now—"

"Every Flavoured Beans?!" Milo's face broke into a huge smile. "I love those things."

Hannah hesitated for a second.

"Okay, then I'll still get you a big pack of Every Flavoured Beans. I've got them up in the girls' dorm... I didn't give them to you already, because, er... well. It doesn't matter now, actually." She must mean the week or so she wasn't talking to me 'cause I asked her about the lake, Milo thought. People are strange. "You can have them in the morning."

"Sweet," Milo said.

"No pun intended?" Hannah asked.

Milo groaned.

"Bye, hamster," Hannah said, tapping the pin, and the impossible cute critter vanished. Hannah hesitated for a moment, then said "I'd go over and give you a hug, or something," she looked somewhat embarrassed, "except that I don't think my legs really want to respond."

"That's okay," Milo said, feeling somewhat awkward. "I'll take a rain cheque."

"Good, good," Hannah said, and an awkward silence, punctured only by Neville's calm and consistent snoring, descended for a beat or three as Milo decided there was absolutely nothing more fascinating than his fingernails and Hannah examined the pin.

"So, how about—" Milo said, while Hannah said "I think we should—" at the same time. They both, then, paused for the other to continue.

"You go first," they said simultaneously. They both looked around the room, for a while, waiting for the other to continue.

"I was going to say we should maybe go to sleep," Hannah said.

"Same," agreed Milo.

"Okay, goodnight!" she said, and rolled over to face away from him.

"Goodnight."

People are weird, Milo thought again—and not for the last time, at that—and rolled over to do the same.

o—o—o—o

"So, you have defeated my minions!" Thamior the Thaumaturge spat, reaching for his pouch of fell spell components. "But—do you really think you can challenge me? You fools! For it is I, the Dread Ma—"

"Wait—Thamior?" Milo said as his companions reached for their weapons, "I'm confused."

"That is only natural, seeing as how you are a fool, fool!"

"It's just that I thought Thamior was a male name," Milo said, his tone kept carefully neutral.

"Which is fitting, seeing as how I am, in fact, male," Thamior said, slightly confused—and evidently irritated at being interrupted in the middle of his monologue.

"But you're an Elf," Milo said.

"You have a talent for stating the obvious, fool! Unfortunately, it won't help you avoid joining my Legion of the Da—"

"But I thought there weren't any Elf males?"

"You will pay for your insolence!" the purple-cloaked Thamior shouted, his eyes glowing red. "When I am god-emperor of all the multiverse, I will – wait, what's going on?"

Milo felt a strange tingling sensation somewhere in his midriff, gradually growing to encompass his torso. In a panic, he looked down to find that, where his stomach should be, there was a slowly growing sphere of darkness, occasionally crackling with what looked like green lightning.

"Gah!" Milo said, the sphere growing to reach his neck. "What did you—how did—I won Initiative, damnit! This isn't fair!" but Thamior looked just as surprised as Milo felt, and was backing away slowly from him.

There was a brief flash of blindingly bright light, and Milo suddenly felt cold all over. His lungs strained painfully, trying futilely to find air, and his brain screamed at him that things were very, very wrong. Gravity seemed to tug at him inconsistently in every direction, before finally agreeing to pull him backwards. He struggled, swinging his arms wildly to try and find something solid, anything, until...

—Thud—

Milo sat bolt upright clutching his side where just a moment before, the sphere of blackness had begun to grow. To his surprise, he realized both his hands were wrapped around his Belt of Hidden Pouches.

He looked around, expecting danger, but saw instead only the depressingly familiar sights of the Hogwarts hospital wing. He blinked, realizing it was only a dream... and a weirdly vivid one, at that. Milo couldn't, this time, speak from experience, but from what he'd heard from other Adventurers, dreams that were more like flashbacks were always important to the plot. The only thing was, in this case, he couldn't figure for the life of him how this could be so.

Milo wasn't sure how long he was staring at the ceiling, trying to figure out what the Hells was going on, what had brought him here, and just what the significance of his dream was when he realized he wasn't alone. (Well, he knew he wasn't alone—Neville's rumbling snores, unfortunately, made sure of that. Also, Hannah. Okay, he obviously wasn't alone. What Milo meant to think was that there was someone else, awake, in the hospital wing with him. You could consider cutting him some slack, of course, seeing as how he just woke up).

"Professor?" Milo asked curiously.

"M-Milo," Professor Quirrell, standing by the door, stammered. "I w-was just checking in on y-y-you, to s-s-see if you would b-be up for the D-Duelling C-Club on Sunday."

"That's..." Milo did some rapid arithmetic. "Four days from now? Definitely. I'll be up and about by tomorrow."

"I-indeed?" Quirrell asked, surprised. "Y-your injuries l-look m-m-most severe. I s-s-see the good M-Madam P-P-Pomfrey has opted n-not to use m-magic on you?"

Milo shrugged painfully.

"I can heal anything short of death in about a day, if I have help. I think Pomfrey's afraid of how your magic will interact with my... well, with me, I guess."

"W-well," Quirrell said, glancing at the clock. "I'm afraid that I h-have to r-r-run; the D-Doxies in the d-d-dungeon won't ch-chase themselves out. I w-wish you a speedy r-r-recovery, and, to that end, left y-you a present," Quirrell gestured at a box of Chocolate Frogs on Milo's bedside table. "G-goodbye."

"Erm. Bye! Thanks," Milo said. The DADA professor walked out of the room at about a half-step faster than normal walking speed, presumably to avoid a lecture from Pomfrey. Milo waited for the door to close behind him, then turned to the frogs.

"Detect Poison," he cast, just in case. When they turned out to be clean, he stashed them in his Belt for later. Milo glanced at the heavy mechanical clock on the wall, noting that, while he could tell that the little hand was pointed at just past the six and the big hand was pointing at the three, he had no idea what that was supposed to mean. Deciding it didn't really matter one way or the other, Milo figured he ought to just go back to sleep.

Only a few minutes passed before Milo heard the door creak open.

"Back, Professor?" Milo asked, sitting up despite his protesting muscles and various grievous wounds.

"Front, Student?" came an aged, grandfatherly voice.

"Headmaster?" Milo asked, genuinely surprised, as Dumbledore walked calmly up to his bed, dressed in his signature purple robes and half-moon spectacles. "I thought Madam Pomfrey—"

"What the good mediwitch said to me was, in fact, and I quote, 'you won't be bothering any of my patients tonight, Headmaster, Supreme Mugwump or no.' As it is, in fact, now the morning and not, in fact, the night, her prohibition is no longer in effect." Dumbledore paused for a moment. "But, ah, it is entirely possible that she would not, in fact, see eye-to-eye on my interpretation of her command, so if you would be so good as to keep your voice down...?"

"Sure," Milo responded quietly. "What brings you here? And, more importantly, why did you say 'Front, Student?'"

"I was taking, as it were, a shot in the dark at what I had guessed—incorrectly, as it would appear—might be a social custom from your homeland. You see, you said, 'Back, Professor,' so I thought that, perhaps, the correct response was to, as is the custom among a small tribe of Merfolk living in a pond in Kashmir, to say the precise opposite. Alas, as is so often the case when one ventures into the murky grounds of speculation, I was incorrect. And as to your first question, I am here, as you can surely guess, to question you about the events of yesterday."

"Oh, that. It's fairly straightforward," Milo said, and gave Dumbledore a rather more accurate version of the story than the one he gave Hagrid (lying to Dumbledore's face seemed, to Milo, about on par with kicking a Lantern Archon). To his credit, Dumbledore sat patiently, listening to the entire story through until the end before asking questions.

"—and then Fang led Hagrid to us, and he carried us back to the castle," Milo finished. "Speaking of which, I'm going to need to go back at some point to get my rope and stuff. Made by Elves, you know." Or at least the sign had said so. In truth, it was hard to find rope anywhere that wasn't claimed to have been made by Elves.

"By Elves? One day, when we both are free from the constant pressings of urgent business, I would greatly enjoy listening to you tell me all about the strange land from which you hail. But, until then, some much briefer answers to more specific questions will have to suffice. First, could you explain to me exactly what the effects are of the Charm you cast on Hannah to free her from the effects of her mental control?"

"Sure," Milo said. "Protection From Evil. Right now, it lasts up to five minutes, but I can push that to seven with these gloves," Milo held up his gloved hands, wiggling his fingers somewhat, "and for the duration, the target can't be affected by any form of mental control. When the spell ends, the control starts up again. Also, they can't be touched by summoned non-Good monsters."

"Fascinating," Dumledore said. "That little spell of yours would have saved the Ministry a great deal of trouble over the years."

"May I counter with a question of my own?" Milo asked.

"Of course you may," Dumbledore said, "but whether I shall answer or not is, I am afraid, another matter entirely. I can promise this: everything I say shall be the unblemished truth."

"Can you tell me how Hannah was being controlled, who did it, where they live, and how well protected they are?"

Dumbledore laughed softly.

"That was four questions, you realize, and I am afraid that I am only able to answer the first. I cannot be sure until I question Miss Abbot directly, of course, but I am quite certain that she was the unfortunate victim of one of the darkest forms of magic known. You already have, unfortunately, witnessed the use of the most terrible of the three Unforgivable Curses, the Killing Curse." Milo nodded. It was the first spell he'd seen cast by the wizards of this world, in fact. "The curses are so-called because the use of one on a human being is enough to warrant a life's sentence in Azkaban, the wizard prison. Normally, the specifics of the Unforgivables are not learned until a student's Sixth Year, but in your case, I fear you may well be in danger without being forewarned. Along with the Killing Curse are the Cruciatus Curse, which causes extreme pain in its victim, and the Imperius Curse. This last one, despite being the most pleasant for the unfortunate victim, has caused more disasters, deaths, and crises than the other two put together, directly or indirectly. The Imperius curse allows direct mental control over the target for, if necessary, years at a time. Used by a skilled wizard or witch, is almost impossible to detect and even harder to resist."

"You mean, it doesn't allow a Will Save?" Milo asked, incredulous. Such a spell was too powerful to exist.

"I'm afraid I don't altogether understand the question," Dumbledore admitted. "Who is Will, and why does he need saving?"

"Uh," Milo said. "I mean, it can't be fought off with strength of will alone?"

"Oh, it is possible," Dumbledore conceded, "but only a handful of exceptionally strong-willed individuals are able to do so."

"You're kidding, right?" Milo asked. These wizards were insanely broken. A spell that killed on a touch attack without a save was bad enough—at least you had to be hit. But add in a spell that lets you Dominate someone indefinitely and had, apparently, an incredibly large bonus to its DC? Milo was briefly surprised that the whole Ministry wasn't run by Dark Wizards, before remembering how many pies Lucius Malfoy had his fingers in.

Well, he thought, that would explain why people don't seem to realize how obviously evil he is. Anyone with any power is probably his thrall already.

A frightening image came to Milo's mind of a thin, pale spider sitting in a large, dark room, surrounded by thousands of silken spider webs, from each of which dangled a major Ministry official like puppets. Milo realized he was badly mixing his metaphors, but, under the circumstances, had other things to worry about.

"So... what do you do about it?" Milo asked. "What's the counter-strategy?"

"There isn't much," Dumbledore admitted. "Keeping a close eye on one's associates and friends to see if they begin acting strangely, occasionally checking if they still remember past events, that sort of thing. It is, at best, only moderately effective."

Milo paled.

"And now, you see why it is that knowledge of these curses is kept to the upper year students," Dumbledore said. "But now, I have another question for you."

"Hit me," Milo said, trying to keep his mind from the horrifying implications of the Imperius.

"I think I will refrain from doing so," Dumbledore said, "as corporal punishment has generally more frowned upon now than it was in the days of Emeric the Evil. Why did you go out in search of Miss Hannah Abbot yesterday morning?"

"Oh," Milo said. "I thought I mentioned. I had to give her her Christmas present."

"Fascinating as that is, that is not precisely the answer I was looking for, as I think you know. To clarify: why, after you discovered that Miss Abbot had left the building, did you head out in search of her?"

Milo sighed.

"I thought something seemed wrong," Milo said, "and that she might be in trouble. And before you ask, no, it never occurred to me to ask a teacher for help."

"And why is that?" Dumbledore pressed.

"Same reason as with the 'Troll,'" Milo explained, as if it were obvious. "It's what I do."

"I rather think not," Dumbledore said. "After Hallowe'en, you explained to me—and I have reason to believe you were telling the truth—that you challenged the Troll rather than doing the sensible thing and running away because fighting monsters was, as you say, what you do. You said, when I asked you then whether it was to protect innocent lives, that that was not the case and doing so was only a... a 'perk' was, I believe, the word you used."

"What's your point?" Milo asked, not used to prolonged conversations with NPCs and not fully realizing that he was being rude.

"Did you have any inkling, when you left, that a monster or Dark Wizard was involved in Hannah Abbot's mysterious exit?"

Milo thought about it.

"No," he admitted.

"Did you suspect, at that point, that she was being forced against her will?"

Milo scratched at his itchy bandages, playing for time. Eventually, he was forced to admit that he hadn't suspected anything of the sort.

"So, as far as you knew, she had simply been exceptionally foolish and wandered out into the snow in harsh winds and subzero temperatures?"

"I hadn't really thought about it," Milo admitted, "but if someone had asked me right then why I thought she was outside, that's probably how I would have answered."

"And you went looking for her."

"Of course," Milo said, still not entirely sure where this was going.

"Not to fight monsters."

"Nope," Milo agreed.

"But to protect an innocent life?" Dumbledore asked.

"I... suppose so? To protect Hannah, mostly."

"It's a start," Dumbledore said. "And you didn't do it because, from a cold, mechanical perspective, she would be of some use to you? Perhaps, in your crusade against Evil?"

"No," Milo said. "I can't see how she would be. Her talents lie in other directions," Milo said, feeling, for some reason, a bit defensive about her. "Not everyone has to be good at fighting to be worth saving, Headmaster."

"I feel, and feel free to correct me if I am wrong, that that may not have been the answer you gave me when we first met."

Milo shrugged.

"She's my friend," Milo said. "I've always protected my..." he trailed off. He had been about to say 'I've always protected my friends,' but, now that he thought about it, he'd never really had friends. He protected his partymembers, of course, but that came with the job description, like fighting monsters. Hannah... Milo was, for once, unsure of her PC/NPC status, but was fairly sure that she wasn't, exactly, in the party. But didn't that make her, by definition, an NPC? Milo went cold. He'd risked his life to save an NPC without any hint or hope of a reward. He'd spent days, thousands of Gold Pieces, and hundreds of XP working on a Magic Item to simply give to an NPC because he'd hurt her feelings. He actually cared about what an NPC felt. What the Hells was happening to him?

Milo felt queasy. I didn't even loot the corpse! He was stunned. He'd simply thrown away the Redcap's sword, which could have probably got him at least 10 gp, assuming it counted as a Short Sword. And who knows what else the grotesque abomination had been carrying? Milo was disgusted with himself. He'd let his emotions run away with him, getting in the way of good old pragmatic greed.

"I think," said Dumbledore, "what you are feeling, right now, and it may be that you are experiencing it for the first time and, as such, it is confusing you, is an aspect of a form of magic more ancient and powerful than any that Voldemort himself possesses."

"What?" Milo gasped. "Detect Magic," he cast, but nothing happened. For a brief, horrible moment he wondered if this mysterious magic that had apparently so addled his brain had also disabled his spellcasting. Then he realized he was simply out of spells, even Cantrips, until he could prepare new ones. "What kind of magic? Dispel me! Dispel me, Dumbledore!"

Dumbledore chuckled.

"Even if I could," he said, "no power on Earth could compel me to do so."

"Do you mean to say that you're behind this insanity?"

"No, Milo, the power of which I speak, the power that Voldemort so casually disregards, the power which was his undoing eleven years ago, the power which is, currently, already drawing you under its influence and subtly altering your perception of the world and your actions, is, you will find, quite beyond the reach of any mortal magic."

"So you do have deities around here!"

"The power of which I speak, young Milo, is love."

Milo stared at him in utter silence, his jaw hanging open, trying to work, but no sound came out. In the end, Milo had to make a Concentration check simply to focus the necessary thought to activate his vocal cords.

"Bull. Sh—"

"I think," said Dumbledore, "that I will so rudely head you off before you finish that thought."

"Love." Milo said flatly. "You-Know-Who was brought down by the Power of Love. Maybe instead of learning magic, we should be putting flowers in our hair and frolicking in the forest like those pointy-eared pansies and singing around campfires. Voldy would be powerless to resist our Flower Power."

"If that stretches your credulity, perhaps, I could more clearly state that it was love which triggered ancient and powerful protective magic," Dumbledore said calmly.

"Oh, well why didn't you say so in the first place?" asked Milo. "Ha! I'd love to have seen the expression on He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named's face when a throwaway, poorly thought-out rule from an obscure splatbook that he never even bothered to read blew up in his face."

"Why do you say it was poorly thought out?" Dumbledore asked curiously.

"It allowed an infant to defeat the most powerful Dark Wizard that ever lived," Milo said, as if the reason were obvious. "That's got to be the most broken rule in existence. I gotta get me some of that. What, exactly, happened to trigger it?"

"Normally, I would leave this for Harry himself to tell you, but in this case, the story is quite well-known. You see, Voldemort was defeated because Harry's mother sacrificed her life to protect her son out of love, which placed a protection upon Harry that Voldemort was unable to overcome."

Milo paused, the implications of this dawning on him.

"How on the Prime Material did You-Know-Who ever get to be that powerful in the first place, then?"

"I'm not sure I completely understand your question. Voldemort used a combination of subterfuge, cruelty, devoted followers, and powerful magic to—"

"No, I mean... I'm obviously no expert on the subject, but do mothers here not care about their children?" Milo asked, still perplexed.

"Of course they do," Dumbledore said. "I should think that the story I just told you was proof of that."

"Do Dark Wizards not kill infants, then?"

"Unfortunately, innocent children are no safer from their evil than fully trained wizards."

"Then how, in the name of the Eternal Library of Boccob, did You-Know-Who—and Grindelwald, and all the other Dark Wizards that ever lived—manage to rise to power without, at some point, attempting to kill a child that their mother died to protect? I mean, how many mothers wouldn't die to protect their children? Especially if they lived in a world where doing so made their child literally invincible to dark magic." Milo was idly wondering if he could work something like it into his backstory, which would neatly solve his problem of dealing with the Killing Curse.

Dumbledore opened his mouth as if to answer, but, before he could, the door slammed open.

"Out!" shrieked an irate Madam Pomfrey. "I won't have you bothering my patients! They need to rest in peace—wait, poor choice of wording... they need peaceful rest, not to be bothered by constant questions!" Ironically, while Dumbledore was speaking quietly and softly, it was Pomfrey's tirade that woke up the sleeping Hannah and Neville.

"Blast," said Dumbledore quietly. "Rumbled, it would seem." He stood up, and walked slowly towards the mediwitch, hands outstretched in a calming gesture. "Ah, my dear Madam Pomfrey, just the witch I was hoping to see. Did I ever tell you how exceptional I've always found your work?" He put an arm on her shoulder as he walked to the door, evidently hoping that she'd be taken in and follow him out. She looked briefly mollified, then her eyes hardened again and she brushed his arm off.

"No! I'm on to your tricks, Headmaster! Don't think you can silver-tongue your way out of things this time!"

"Alas," Dumbledore sighed. "Foiled again. Might we, at least, continue what I'm certain will be a most pleasant discussion outside, so as not to disturb your patients further?"

Pomfrey threw a quick, surprised glance at Hannah and Neville, who were looking around blearily to find out where the war had started and whether they ought to go and find helmets and a foxhole.

"Perhaps that would be, er, for the best," Pomfrey said in a much quieter voice, and followed the Headmaster out, having lost the initiative. Dumbledore glanced over his shoulder and winked at Milo, then walked out with the somewhat bemused-looking healer.

"Why was Doreumble... Dormble... Dumbledore here?" Hannah asked, fighting down a yawn.

"He wanted to ask me about yesterday," Milo explained. "He'll probably come back later to talk to you about it."

"Oh," said Hannah, who, if truth be told, would be just as happy forgetting it had ever happened. Then she shrugged, and went back to sleep.

Milo, whose brain was wracked with too many unanswered questions—Dumbledore, Milo had noticed, had an unfortunate habit of answering a question in a way that provoked twelve more—started memorizing spells simply to clear his head. Unfortunately, the arcane sigils in his book kept blurring together and dancing in front of his vision for him to make much progress there, and he grudgingly set aside his spellbook for later. He hadn't had trouble preparing spells since he was apprentice level.

So, I've been bewitched, have I? Enchanted by powerful and ancient magic that's compromising my ability to think logically. There must be some cure... Break Enchantment probably wouldn't even do it, as it only works on spells of fifth level or lower. This love magic business sounds closer to ninth level. Assuming magic here even has levels, of course. Maybe there's some cure to be found in the local magic... Dumbledore said there wasn't, but not even he can know everything, right? Maybe if I—

"Hey," Neville said abruptly.

"Uh, hi, Nev," Milo responded. "What's up?"

"Well, you looked busy earlier, but now that you're not studying anymore, I thought I'd ask what happened. You and Hannah look pretty beaten up, I mean. Did Peeves do something?"

"No, I got gutted by a Redcap with a sword."

"Oh," said Neville. "Wow. Why didn't you just pull out your wand and cast—"

"Didn't have time," Milo lied.

"Shame, 'cause it's a dead easy spell. Even I can do it, and I'm rubbish at, well everything."

"We should probably be quiet," Milo said. "Hannah's trying to sleep. Damnit, I did it again!"

"Did what?" Neville asked.

"Uh. Nothing," Milo said, having forgotten that NPCs could hear you when you weren't speaking directly to them.

"You're right, though, of course," Neville said. "You can tell me all about it later."

Milo lay back, cursing his confused brain. Everything had seemed so simple a few months ago. PCs help you defeat monsters and get treasure, NPCs give you treasure for defeating monsters. Everything was becoming so tangled lately.

And his combat skills must be going rusty as well; that Redcap, judging by the XP he earned, was only CR 2. He'd nearly died fighting it, which was completely unacceptable. The problem, looking at it in hindsight, was obvious: Milo's spell list was carefully optimized for what he had previously considered to be a typical combat. As a Wizard, his job was to neutralize as many enemies as possible in the first few rounds of combat so that his partymembers with knives and pointy sticks could move in and do the actual damage unimpeded. To that end, he preferred spells that could make as many enemies as possible as useless as possible as quickly as possible—thus, Grease and Glitterdust. But lately, he'd been involved in a lot of solo encounters, and Milo just wasn't capable of dishing out the kind of damage necessary to finish off an enemy—which is why he'd had so much trouble with the Troll and the Redcap. It meant he had to burn a much larger number of spells per enemy than he normally would, and, as a result, ran out of ammo precipitously fast.

"I should stop going out alone," he realized. "I need backup. That and the capability to rain down fiery doom, just in case." Milo briefly considered Fireball, but realized that at his current level, the much more toned down Kelgore's Fire Bolt would deal the same amount of damage without the same possibility for collateral damage. Also, being a Conjuration spell, he would get a few bonuses from his specialty school. Fireball would take longer to research, being a 3rd level spell (Kelgore's little toy was only 1st level) so Milo opted to begin research on Kelgore's Fire Bolt now and get Fireball afterwards—and maybe Scorching or Seeking Ray after that.

Thinking about spells, tactics, and general optimization had put Milo back into his more usual mindset, and he opted to continue memorizing spells.

A few minutes after the requisite hour had passed, the door opened again to reveal yet more visitors.

Harry and Ron walked in. Ron looked part worried and part excited, while Harry just looked distracted. Ron, to Milo's delight, was carrying a platter laden with toast, butter, and tea.

"Blimey!" said Ron. "What happened? We were worried when you didn't come back at night, but figured you'd just gone off to work on something mad like you usually do. Next morning, Dumbledore himself walks into the Common Room and asks us to take breakfast up to you and Hannah—hi, Hannah" (Hannah had woken up when they entered, and was staring at the food with undisguised greed) "—and blimey you look terrible." Ron was, however, carrying food, so Milo decided to let him live—this time.

"Yeah," Harry said distractedly.

Milo shrugged, and for the third time told the story again, glossing over the part where he'd accidentally knifed the girl now sitting a few feet away from him.

"I reckon you couldn't have just driven the Red Cap off with—"

"No," Milo sighed, resolving to punch the next person who suggested using one of the local wizards' simple anti-Redcap spells. "I can't cast those, remember? Anyways, what's up with you two?"

"What do you mean?" Ron asked.

"Harry's off in his own little world," Milo said.

"Is he?" Ron asked, looking over his shoulder at the Boy-Who-Lived, who had been staring absently at one of Milo's bed fixtures. "You're right," Ron said, surprised. "He is. Oi! Potter! What's going on in there?"

"I saw my parents last night," Harry said reluctantly.

"What, like in a dream?" Milo asked. "'Cause they seem to be going around."

"No," Harry said. "In a mirror."

Chapter 21: Bewitched

Author's Notes: Sorry for the lateness (and, again, shortness) of this chapter! I'm still flat-footed from my trip. Since Term is starting, I'll be switching to Sundays for updates (thus giving me Saturdays to write). Once again, this chapter was only briefly edited, so please forgive any errors! I'll try to fix things over the course of the week. Things should be back to normal in terms of length and grammar for the next chapter.

Also, an extremely helpful fan has shown me a workaround for a problem I've been having with myth-weavers, so I might be able to post chapterly character sheet updates. We'll see how things go.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

"You reckon we should go after him?" Harry asked.

"In a minute," Ron said absently, still staring at the Mirror.

"It's just ..." Harry said. "I dunno, he seemed a bit, well, off."

"I'm sure he's fine," Ron said, making a vague gesture.

"Looking into a mirror that shows your heart's desire and screaming your head off doesn't seem particularly fine to me," Harry said with growing certainty. "And, I mean, he's injured and all."

"Hey," Ron said, suddenly alert. "What do you reckon Hermione would see in here? Herself with a load of the world's dullest books probably ... still, we should probably show her when she gets back. And what about Fred and George?"

Harry looked at Ron, his eyes narrowing.

"So you think we should show a bunch of people?" Harry asked neutrally.

"Dunno," Ron shrugged. "Just wondering what they'd see is all. What about Neville? Bet it'd be himself with no bandages holding a Remembrall that's completely dim, eh? Or an 'O' in Transfiguration."

No way, Harry thought. Could Milo have been right about the Mirror?

"I think," Harry said slowly, "that we should go talk to Dumbledore — or McGonagall."

"What, really?" Ron asked, as if Harry had just suggested they jump into a pit of venomous snakes.

"Yeah," said Harry. "I reckon the Mirror, it's, well, it's like Milo said, it's making you want to go and get other people to show it to." The last several words spilled out all at once.

"What?" Ron sputtered. "Need I remind you that he also nicked the contents of everyone's trunks because he thought they were, and I quote, treasure chests? He's off his rocker."

"But when I saw the mirror the next thing I did was to go get you two, and now you want to go get other people! It's just like he said!"

"I was just wondering what they'd see is all," Ron said defensively. "And anyway, it's not like it's a crime, is it? It's a fun mirror, I mean. But it's not like I was seriously considering it."

"That so? Or is the Mirror making you say that?"

"If I was being possessed," Ron said firmly. "I'd know about it."

"I didn't know when it made me show it to you!"

Ron rolled his eyes.

"Look, say you're right and it's this big dirty evil magic Mirror that's controlling me with its big dirty evil magic Mirror powers," Ron said patiently. "If that were true — and it isn't, but if it were — then we wouldn't be having this dumb conversation because you'd be controlled by its big dirty evil magic Mirror powers also."

Harry frowned for a moment, then a thought struck him.

"No," he said excitedly, "because he used Protection From Evil on me, remember? The Mirror can't influence me — but we have to find a teacher before it wears off! Can you remember how long it lasts? I can't."

"This is mad," Ron said exasperatedly. "We're just getting jumpy 'cause of Hannah and convinced everyone's possessed whenever they do anything. This time tomorrow someone will suggest we go get breakfast and everyone will be all 'He's possessed! Let's go run to Dumbledore!' or 'He said he was going to the loo! He must be possessed!'"

"That's what you would say if the Mirror were controlling you," Harry insisted.

"It's also what I'd say if I thought you were becoming an increasingly annoyingly paranoid git," Ron said, losing his patience. "Just saying."

"Let's just go find him and go to McGonagall, okay? I mean, what's the worst that could happen?"

"That we all get eaten by spiders in the hallway, obviously," Ron said. "But fine, let's go — if it's the only thing that'll shut you up about this. Now, where do you reckon he is?"

"Where who is?" asked a new voice. Harry and Ron turned, shocked, to find Milo leaning calmly against the doorframe to the classroom.

"You," Harry said while Ron said "What are you doing here?"

"What are you lot fighting about?" he asked, ignoring Ron's question entirely.

"Sir Paranoid here reckons we've both been bewitched," Ron said, "and wants to take us to McGonagall."

Milo snorted dismissively.

"Lead on, then," he said. "Not that it will accomplish much; that's practically impossible to detect."

"One second," Harry said. "Just going to grab the Cloak."

Milo raised an eyebrow briefly as Harry shoved his Invisibility Cloak into his schoolbag, but said nothing.

"Right, let's go," Harry said, shouldering his bag and heading to the door. "And both of you stay in front of me," he added, "just in case."

As they walked to McGonagall's office, Harry kept a firm grip on his wand — he wasn't sure just how much power (if any) the Mirror had over them, but decided not to take any chances.

"Er, mate," Ron said anxiously as they rounded one of the last corners to their destination, "not really sure how to tell you this, but your magic belt thingy seems to be acting up." Ron gestured at Milo's belt, which, now that he was looking closely, Harry noticed did, indeed, seem to be 'acting up.' One of the ten small pouches was wiggling around, as if something inside was trying to get out.

"It does that sometimes," Milo said with a shrug. "It's nothing that need worry you."

"Oh," said Ron. "It's just I never noticed it before."

"Isn't that where you keep your rat?" Harry asked shrewdly. He'd seen the furry little animal poking it's head out of the belt occasionally to look around. In fact, he didn't think he'd ever seen the buckle on that particular pouch done up before...

"Nope," Milo said blithely.

"Oh, okay," Harry said as if it were nothing. Something weird's definitely going on, he thought. Best get to McGonagall as quickly as possible.

"Still can't believe I'm voluntarily walking to McGonagall's office," Ron muttered. "Again. What would Fred and George say?"

Harry expected Milo to make a quip about just how 'voluntary' (or rather, involuntary) Ron's trip to the Deputy Headmistress's office really was, but Milo remained silent, staring straight ahead with his shoulders set.

It felt like it took ages, but in reality, it was only a four minute walk or so from the abandoned classroom to their destination. Harry rapped quickly on the door three times, not taking his eyes off of Milo.

"Come in," Harry heard.

"Right," Harry said, gesturing with his wand (although, in truth, he didn't know any spells off-hand that he would use on them anyways). "You two go in first, and leave the talking to me."

"You're mad, mate," Ron muttered, and pushed the door open.

"Misters Potter, Weasley, and Amastacia-Liadon," McGonagall said, rising from her chair. "What seems to be the mat— why are you holding your wand? And you, shouldn't you be in the hospital wing?"

"I think these two have been bewitched —"Harry started.

"Oh, come now," McGonagall said in a pacifying tone. "Why would —"

"— by a magic Mirror. And so have I."

"Mirror?" McGonagall asked sharply, suddenly alert. "Explain everything on the way. Let's go."

"Where are we going?" Ron asked as McGonagall stepped around her desk to the door.

"To see the Headmaster, of course. This nonsense about bewitchment aside, I need to talk to him about just leaving a certain powerful magical artifact where just anyone can bump into it."

Despite the fact that she had dismissed Harry's concerns about mental control off-hand, Harry noticed that McGonagall, who usually liked to stay at the front of any particular group, stayed a half-step behind Harry, Ron and Milo on the way up to Dumbledore's hidden office — a fact which made it somewhat awkward for him to recount the events surrounding the mirror.

McGonagall guided them down Hogwarts' ever-shifting halls, through false walls, up some stairs, down some stairs, up some more stairs, took what Harry swore were three left turns at one point and still ended up somewhere different, until they eventually stopped in front of an ominous-looking gargoyle statue. While Harry hadn't ever been to this particular statue, he was fairly sure McGonagall had taken a deliberately circuitous route.

Harry saw McGonagall's lips move, but a sudden ringing in his ears prevented him from hearing whatever it was she said. Just as abruptly as it started, the ringing stopped, and the gargoyle seemed to rotate upwards into a spiral staircase. Something about the way it moved seemed subtly wrong to Harry, but he'd seen enough magic to know not to analyze things too closely.

"Up you go," McGonagall said, and they trotted up the stone staircase to a heavy wooden door. McGonagall knocked politely on the door and waited.

"Shouldn't we just go in?" Harry asked, impatient. He didn't know how much longer Protection From Evil would last, or if it had already run out. "This is urgent."

"Neither the Minister for Magic, Nicolas Flamel, nor even He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named would dare enter the Headmaster's office without permission. So we wait."

Harry waited several uncomfortable seconds, tapping his foot impatiently against the ancient stone floor. Eventually, the door simply swung open to let them in.

Dumbledore sat behind a heavy oak desk, wearing a particularly eye-watering multi-hued robe and his trademark half-moon spectacles.

"Why, Minerva, what an unexpected surprise!" he said, looking genuinely pleased. "And I see you've brought guests! Is it tea time already?"

"No, it's not, it's —"

"My colleague Professor Sinistra assures me that, due to the rotation of the earth beneath our feet hurtling through space around the great, smiling face in the sky that we call the sun, it is always tea time. Somewhere, at least."

"Er, well, be that as it may, I have a matter of some importance to discuss with you," McGonagall said, desperately trying to regain the initiative. "It's about the Mirror, and ... something else as well."

"I see," Dumbledore said gravely, all appearances of a foolish old man suddenly gone. Harry had never seen the Headmaster look so serious before. "Go on."

"Perhaps it would be best if Mister Potter explained," the Deputy Headmistress said.

"Very well. What's happened, Harry?" Dumbledore asked.

As Harry nervously told his story, he noticed that Milo appeared to be sweating nervously.

"So, in short, you think you're all being influenced by the Mirror of Erised?" Dumbledore asked.

"Is that what it's called?" Harry asked.

"It is, indeed," Dumbledore said. "And, it appears, I shall have to have it moved from its temporary home. If it will put your mind at rest, the Mirror, while extremely powerful, does not have the ability to directly control the actions of those who gaze upon it — not to say that having their heart's desires revealed to them isn't a form of influence in itself."

"Oh," Harry said, greatly relieved.

"Still," Dumbledore said, "you can't be too careful, I suppose. If you would be so good as to wait here a moment?" Without waiting for a reply, the Headmaster stood up from his desk to walk over to one of his shelves of ticking silver devices on the wall.

"Ah," he said after rummaging about for a moment or two, "here we are. I've always been meaning to try this one out." Blowing what seemed to be generations of accumulated dust off of a complicated-looking spindly silver thing that Harry could only, in all honesty, accurately describe as a 'gizmo,' Dumbledore returned to his desk and sat down heavily. He placed the gizmo on the polished wooden surface where it made an ominous thud that seemed much louder than an object of its apparent mass would make. It had spiky protrusions. It had bits that whirled around for no apparent reason. It had twists and turns and knobs and dials. It had what looked uncomfortably like a dentist's drill only more, well, eldritch.

"But, Headmaster —" McGonagall began, looking astonished.

"Not now, Minerva," Dumbledore said, brushing aside whatever her protest was. "This," he said to Harry, Ron, and Milo with a dramatic flourish, "is the, De ... bewitcher of, er, Destiny."

"I'm sorry, the —" McGonagall began.

"Yes, the Debewitcher of Destiny. It's for, near as I can figure, revealing the presence of any form of magic that allows mental control, up to and including a certain Unforgivable curse."

"But detecting the Imperius Curse is all but impossible," Milo protested.

"Indeed, without the Debewitcher of Doom, it is impossible," Dumbledore agreed.

"Wasn't it called the Debewitcher of Destiny?" Ron asked.

"It's very versatile," Dumledore shrugged. "Now, who shall I use it on first?" As he spoke, he adjusted several knobs and dials on the device, which made its drill extension whir in an ominous fashion.

"I'm not going near that thing," Ron said stubbornly. "What would it do if we were, you know, bewitched? Not that we are, of course."

"Well," Dumbledore said, scratching his beard as he thought. "To be honest, I'm not completely certain. To the best of my knowledge, this dial here controls the severity of the Debewitcher's effect," he said, gesturing at a particularly large, unmarked dial. "It goes anywhere from simply revealing the identity of the guilty party to having the earth itself rise up and swallow the culprit whole."

Ron gave a low whistle.

"The only problem is, the dial is unmarked. Now, of course, the normal convention is for dials to turn them to the left for their lowest setting , but, as I'm sure you can tell, the designer of this particular device was quite clearly bonkers. So, just to be safe, I'm turning it all the way to the right." As he did so, the whirring of the drill-end increased to a frightening pace, and parts of the machine were pumping up and down now at a rate that was shaking the floor. "Ah," Dumbledore said. "See? Perfectly safe."

Harry swallowed nervously. Ron's face was white, and Milo licked his suddenly-dry lips.

"I-I'll go first," Harry said. He'd rather do almost anything other than go near that deathtrap of a machine, but he had to know if the Mirror was controlling him. Also, it set a good precedent for Ron and particularly Milo. Once he'd done it and (hopefully) survived, they couldn't very well back out.

"Then, if you would just place your palm here," Dumbledore said, pointing at a flat disc on one of the Debewitcher's spindly arms. Harry complied, taking care not to go anywhere near the more dangerous-looking appendages. There was a tense second or two as Harry waited for the results. The machine didn't, as far as Harry could tell, give any sort of feedback, but eventually Dumbledore broke the silence. "Well," he said, "it seems that you are, fortunately, no less — or more, for that matter — yourself than you usually are." Harry sighed with relief, collapsing into a nearby chair. "Now, Mister Weasley," Dumbledore said, turning to Ron. "If you would ...?"

Ron gulped audibly, but put his now-heavily-sweating palm on the disc. To his relief, nothing happened.

"See?" he said to Harry, pulling his hand away from the machine. "I'm fine, just like I said."

"And Mister Amastacia-Liadon," Dumbledore said, turning to Milo. "It's your turn."

"But I'm not possessed," he said stubbornly.

"I'm sure you're not," Dumbledore replied. "But, nevertheless, your two friends were brave enough to try it. Surely you — as, by your own admission, a hero — would be willing to do the same?"

"This is pointless," he muttered. "I'm sure we all have much more important things to be doing — especially you, headmaster, as Supreme Mugwump on top of being Chief Warlock of the Wizengamot — than entertaining a boy's delusions. I mean, you yourself said the Mirror can't —"

"You got his titles right," Harry said suddenly.

"Sorry, what?" Milo asked coolly.

"You get everything's name wrong," Harry said, backing away slowly.

"I don't —"

"You once called him the Supreme Muggle instead of Mugwump, and called the Chudley Cannons Cuddly. I've never heard you get two polysyllabic names right in the same sentence before."

"Well, maybe I thought it was funny then, but now things are impor—"

"You trapped Mordy in your Belt."

"He was being unruly," Milo said defensively. "He bit me. See?" Milo peeled off one of his weird blue gloves to show a small bite mark between his thumb and index finger.

"Maybe," Harry said skeptically. "He bit you because you're bewitched after all."

"I'm not —"

"Then put your hand in the machine and prove it," Harry said.

"Fine," Milo snapped, and stepped towards Dumbledore's desk. He reached slowly towards the machine with four sets of eyes boring into him slowly. Just as he was about to place his hand on the disc, he spun around. "Summon Hipp—"

"No," Dumbledore said quietly. There was no threat, no malice, and no particular volume to his words. He wasn't even holding his wand. Nevertheless, Milo blinked in amazement as his spell fizzled out in front of him.

"How did you —" he began, then noticed the large number of wands pointed at him. "Ah," he said. "I see."

o—o—o—o

"Enervate," Milo heard a voice say. In a panic, he rolled to the side and tried to stumble to his feet.

"Don't you dare," he said, feeling dizzy. The whole Material Plane seemed to be spinning in a somewhat concerning manner, and everything more than a few feet away was an indistinct blur. He didn't envy his chances of succeeding the requisite Concentration check to cast a spell given his current status.

"I was just —" the voice said again.

"Enervation, eh?" Milo asked, trying to hide just how dazed he was. "You can keep your 1d4 negative levels, if you please, and tell me what the Hells is going on. Or... or else," he finished lamely.

"I think we've got him back," someone else said.

"Blimey, you reckon?" a third voice said sarcastically.

"If 'onety-four' is a number," a female voice said sternly, "then I shall eat my hat. I believe the word you were searching for was fourteen."

"Everyone, stop trying to be witty," Milo said, his vision growing somewhat clearer, "and give me a straight answer."

"You were controlled by the Imperius curse for an unknown duration by an unknown party," a grandfatherly voice that Milo recognized instantly as Dumbledore's said. "But were discovered by your good friend Harry Potter who, in a notably rare act of sensibility for a Gryffindor, immediately did the sensible thing and told the good Deputy Headmistress. Thirty points for Gryffindor, Harry, by the way. In, what if I dare say was a characteristic fit of quick thinking, I then managed to convince you — and, more importantly, whomever was controlling you — that I could reveal the identity of your controller with this fifteen-hundred-year-old magical juicer. You were presumably ordered to attack us, and Minerva, regrettably, was forced to subdue you."

"Oh," said Milo, as the memory came back to him. The room was starting to stabilize, but Milo decided he'd be perfectly happy staying on blessedly solid the floor for a while nonetheless. "Then why did you try to cast Enervation on me?"

"Enervate, Milo, not Enervation," Dumbledore corrected.

"Demons and Tanar'ri," Milo shrugged. "Same thing."

"While I have lived for quite some time and accumulated no small amount of knowledge of magic, I do not know of this Enervation spell of which you speak — fittingly, since I presume it is from your world. Enervate, however, is a harmless, yet rather unfortunately named spell to wake up those rendered asleep or unconscious by magic."

"Then why did they call it a word that means to suck energy out of something?" Milo asked curiously.

"Everyone makes mistakes," Dumbledore said with the slightest of shrugs. "I'm led to believe that some people at the ministry are working on a functionally identical spell with a more appropriate name. But I digress. I don't suppose there's any chance that you can identify the culprit?"

"Sorry," Milo said. His vision had cleared to the point where he could clearly make out Dumbledore, Harry, Ron, and Professor McGongall's faces. "I was in the hallway near the Mirror when I thought I thought I noticed something, so I cast a spell that detects minds. It told me there were twelve sentient minds nearby, although I couldn't see any of them. Before I could find out more, I heard someone whisper 'Imperio', and then, well, you know the rest. Oh, speaking of," he said, unbuttoning the pouch that Mordy was trapped in. "Sorry, little guy," he said to his friend. "It's okay, now."

"The minds that the spell detected," Dumbledore pressed. "Are you quite sure they were sentient? As in, human-level intelligence?"

"Er," Milo said, trying to remember the spell description. "Anything living that's as smart or smarter than a newt."

"Could it have simply been the wall portraits?" Dumbledore asked. "I daresay, the one that guards Ravenclaw tower is a good deal smarter than a newt."

"No," Milo said. "Those are probably Constructs — er, magically animated objects — and therefore immune to the spell. So whatever they were, they were invisible."

"In fact, that is most unlikely," Dumbledore said. "The ability to become truly invisible, at least in our world, is extremely rare. It is more likely that these twelve persons or creatures unknown were hidden with, say, a remarkably good Disillusionment Charm." Oh, Milo thought. So that's why See Invisibility only worked on the Cloak. Go figure.

"One last question," Milo asked. "Actually, make that two questions."

"Very well," Dumbledore said. "I will answer to within the confines of our earlier agreement."

"The first: how did you interrupt my spell? I'd assumed our different types of magic were basically incompatible."

"Oh, it was quite simple, really," Dumbledore admitted. "I simply used magic of a different sort. I reasoned that, since you once told me that you had worked and studied for your magic — rather than, say, being born into it — that it required a certain degree of mental fortitude and concentration to use, much like our magic."

"So you just..."

"Over the years, I've acquired something of a reputation for myself — most of it undeserved, of course — and I've found that a certain type of wizard, especially dark wizards, seem to believe me capable of almost anything. So, I simply commanded you to stop, and you, believing I actually had the power to do so, complied."

"What would you have done if that hadn't worked?" Milo asked.

"Ah," Dumbledore said with a slight twinkle in his eye. "In that case, I would have done nothing."

"Nothing?" Milo asked, shocked. "Then the Hippogriff would have torn you to pieces."

"I daresay not," Dumbledore said. "Minerva would have Stunned you well before you finished casting your spell. Now, as to your second question...?"

"Right," Milo said. "What the Hells was that Mirror?"

"Ah, the Mirror of Erised," Dumbledore said. "It shows the heart's deepest, and sometimes, unfortunately, darkest desire. Nothing more, and nothing less. I strongly urge you to put it out of your minds, for men have wasted away obsessing over it. Needless to say, it shall be moved to a more safe location as soon as possible."

"Good idea," Milo said, remembering the disturbing images the Mirror had shown him. "Now, if someone will help me to the hospital wing, I'm going to stay there until I've made an amulet of Protection From Evil for everyone and their cousin."

Chapter 22: The Chessmaster

Author's Notes: Thank everyone for the increasingly positive flood of reviews! Hope you enjoy reading this next chapter as much as I enjoyed writing it.

Also, I'm going to experiment with chapterly-updated character sheets now that I can copy-paste them. Here's this one (replace the asterisks with periods): myth-weavers*com/sheetview*php?sheetid=444154

EDIT: Wow, there were about a million embarrassingly obvious typos, grammatical errors, and repeated sentences in the first version. Sorry, guys! I think I caught most of them. Yikes.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

The remainder of the week was, for Milo, blissfully uneventful. Classes resumed, and with them the hustle and bustle of several hundred Hogwarts students returning from their vacation. Pleading illness (and who was qualified to disagree with him?), Milo, true to his word, sequestered himself in the hospital wing with Neville (Hannah, after a few days of rest and dozens of different healing Charms and potions, was deemed fit to return to school) frantically crafting Amulets of Protection From Evil and researching Kelgore's Fire Bolt.

It was here that Milo ran into a small problem of mathematics: it took two days, hundreds of Galleons of owl-ordered supplies (Milo found he could affray these costs somewhat by supplies nicked from Potions), and eighty Experience Points to make each amulet. Milo really didn't know much about the demographics of this plane (all he'd seen was a bit of Hogsmeade, Platform Nine and Three-Quarters, and, of course, Hogwarts) but there were probably several thousand wizards and witches out there. Even ruling out protecting the entire population and focussing on those who posed an imminent threat to Milo — anyone nearby who possessed a wand, had a drop of magical blood, could see lightning and hear thunder — the number of Amulets required was insanely unrealistic.

"This is just so backwards," Milo muttered after, upon reaching the end of the week, completing only his third Amulet of Protection From Evil. The problem was that an Imperius'd wizard or witch was more of a threat to those around them than to themselves, so Milo, in order to protect himself, had to equip anyone and everyone around him with expensive amulets. The problem, however, was that Magic Item crafting benefited from no economy of scale whatsoever: if it took two thousand gold pieces and two days to make one Amulet of Protection From Evil, it would take two hundred thousand gold pieces and two hundred days to make a hundred of them. While Harry was rich, Milo doubted he was quite that rich. At some point, Milo was going to have to start paying him back for the (rather enormous) loan.

"What's backwards?" a familiar voice said. Milo turned to the door to see Hermione standing there, a tray of steaming hot soup in her hands.

"Hey!" Milo said. "I was wondering when you'd drop by."

"Sorry," Hermione said apologetically. "I was going to come earlier, but, well, it's the first week back and I didn't want to get behind — I mean, I only had time over the break to reread A History of Magic, Magical Drafts and Potions, One Thousand Magical Herbs and Fungi, and Magical Theory! I'm dangerously behind in The Standard Book of Spells and A Beginner's Guide to Transfiguration!" Hermione pulled herself together with visible effort. "But, my responsibility as a friend outweighs even academic concerns," she said officiously. "Well, at least, in an emergency. And except in exam period."

"Well, thanks," Milo said. "Just set the soup down on the bedside table."

"So," Hermione said after doing just that, "just how badly were you injured, anyway? I remember after the Troll you were on your feet in no time, and, well, you were in pretty bad shape that time, so... I mean, are you all right?"

"Yeah, totally fine," Milo shrugged. "But if Pomfrey asks, I need another day of complete bed rest to, and make sure you get this right, 'regenerate my recuperative and restorative healing abilities and realign my ki power pool or die.'"

"You could die?"

"Nope," Milo said. "I made all that stuff up."

"You're... you're skiving!" Hermione accused, aghast.

"Well, duh. But it's for a good cause — which reminds me..." Milo fished out the three Amulets of Protection From Evil from his magic belt. "Arcane Mark, Arcane Mark, Arcane Mark, Arcane Mark, Arcane Mark, Arcane Mark," he cast repeatedly, placing a pair of unique symbols on each amulet for later identification. One symbol on each amulet was a faintly glowing rune which was, using Milo's magic anyways, virtually impossible for anyone else to duplicate. The local magic was largely one giant unknown, however, so Milo also put an invisible version of the mark on each amulet as a backup — one that only Milo could see, and even then, only when he cast See Invisibility first. If someone out there (*cough* Snape *cough*) tried to switch the amulets for forgeries, and they somehow managed to duplicate the decoy mark, they wouldn't even know about the invisible one.

"What was that all about?" Hermione asked.

"For later identification," Milo said. "I mark all my stuff that way, comes in handy more than you'd think. Here, put this on," Milo handed her one of the amulets.

"Er, it's, um, pretty?" Hermione tried, desperately, to sound delighted, but the fact was that the amulets were little more than small silver discs on a thin, but sturdy, steel chain.

"Is it?" Milo asked. "Aesthetics were never my strong suit, to be honest. Appearances aside, that right there's what we in the business call a Magic Item."

"What's magic about it?" Hermione asked, examining it curiously.

"Makes you immune to the Imperius Curse," Milo said nonchalantly.

"Sorry," Hermione said. "Could you say that again? See, here I thought you said that this little necklace is supposed to protect you against one of the darkest, most powerful Curses in existence."

"Yeah," Milo said. "And any other mind-affecting magic, also. Just make sure you keep it on at all times, and give this other one to Harry. I'll have Ron's done sometime tomorrow."

Hermione stared at Milo, evidently trying to decide if he was joking or not.

"You're serious, aren't you?" she asked. "I mean, I'd heard from Ron that you had a spell that did something like that temporarily, but this... This is big, do you understand? Really big."

"Well, I guess? I mean, it's pretty trivial magic where I'm from."

"Blocking the Imperius Curse is trivial?" Hermione exclaimed. "From what I've read, during the last war, the other side managed to infiltrate the Ministry at every level, and we're still not sure who was bewitched and who was a volunteer. It was utter chaos, and You-Know-Who nearly toppled the entire government that way. It takes exceptional willpower — as in, one person in hundreds — or years of training to resist. How could preventing something like that possibly be trivial?"

"I figure it's something like Transfiguration. Using Arcane magic — my magic, that is — turning a matchstick into a pin requires an extremely powerful spell. And healing injuries like Pomfrey can do with a wave and a word is nigh impossible. On the other hand, I can see right through Harry's super-rare and expensive Invisibility Cloak without much difficulty because, well, for us, mere Invisibility is an everyday sort of thing. Ironically, it's the inferior Disillusionment Charm that I can't beat. Which actually reminds me of something, Hermione, that I was going to ask you," Milo said.

"Oh?"

"Do you know of any spells that can change someone's heart's desire, if only temporarily?"

"What does that have to do with the Disillusionment Charm?" Hermione asked, perplexed.

"Long story. But can it be done?"

"Let's see..." Hermione scratched her chin, deep in thought. "I presume you're talking about the Mirror? It really depends on what, exactly, 'heart's desire' means. With a decent Confundus Charm — or maybe even after being Obliviated, which leaves the target in a highly suggestive state — you can definitely force someone to want something. Whether that counts as your new 'heart's desire,' however, I think is a matter of interpretation."

"Ah," Milo was crushed by disappointment. He'd hoped to trick the Mirror of Erised into showing him whatever he needed to see, but he was pretty sure that he'd destroyed his chances of getting a favourable outcome in any 'matter of interpretation' when he tried to use Spontaneous Divination to mimic a Cleric spell.

"However," Hermione said, looking thoughtful. "It's possible — unlikely, mind, but possible — that a sufficiently powerful Love potion might have the desired effect."

"A Love potion." Milo said flatly.

"It basically comes down to how, well, fluffy one interprets the meaning of 'heart's desire' to be. Will someone who is madly in love, but drugged by a potion into loving someone else see their 'one true love,' or the person who is pressing on their minds at that very moment? The answer to that, I really couldn't tell you. Seems more up Professor Dumbledore's alley, to be honest. It's all academic, in any case. Harry said he was going to move the Mirror, I doubt we'll ever see it again."

"Of course we will!" Milo said. "It's on the List. If it wasn't going to pop up again later for something important, why would we have seen it after Christmas? It would have been a complete waste of everyone's time."

"You have a very unusual view of the world," Hermione said, her tone making it perfectly clear how she felt about that.

"It's never led me astray yet," Milo said defensively.

"Now that is a matter of some debate," she said. "Oh, also, McGonagall told us that Dumbledore officially pardoned the Gryffindor house for assaulting the Slytherins in Potions. Apparently we've fallen precipitously behind even Hufflepuff, not that there's anything wrong with them, in our courses because of all the detentions."

"Well, that's a relief," Milo said. "I badly need that time for spell research. There just aren't enough hours in the day."

"Tell me about it," Hermione said sympathetically. "I don't see how I'm going to fit all the courses I want onto my schedule in third year," she said. "Which reminds me — I really need to get back to studying."

After she left, Milo returned to work on Ron's Amulet. He'd have to spend most of the rest of today and tomorrow on it, but Sunday...

...Sunday was saved for Quirrell's Duelling Club.

o—o—o—o

"S-s-some of you are p-p-probably wondering w-why the D-D-Defence P-Professor would start a D-Duelling Club," Quirrell stammered to the assembled students. Roughly one-third of the entire student body had signed up for his Club, from first-years to seventh-years, and stood assembled in the Great Hall. "B-because whatever you c-could learn in this c-club, surely, I c-could teach you in y-your regular c-c-course?" Milo blinked. He hadn't been wondering that at all; he'd mostly been wondering how much longer he had to wait before magically curbstomping some local 'wizards.' "Well, the d-d-difference between D-Defence Against the D-Dark Arts and D-D-Duelling lies in y-your opponent. C-can anyone t-tell me what a Red C-Cap, a Werewolf, a Dementor, a D-Doxie, a B-Boggart, and even a V-V-V-Vampire have in c-common?"

Students shuffled their feet, glancing at one another, trying to determine any similarity between these extremely disparate creatures.

"What's the answer to this one?" Ron whispered hopefully to Hermione.

"I don't know!" she whispered back, her eyes looking somewhat wild. "It's not in any of our textbooks, and most of those creatures aren't covered until third year or higher!"

Somewhere near the front, an NPC raised his hand.

"Yes, C-C-Cedric?" Quirrell asked the boy.

"They're not human," he said simply. "And they all have some sort of weakness to memorize, or a vulnerability to a particular Charm or Curse."

"C-correct," Quirrell stammered, "and ten p-points for Hufflepuff." There was some astonished murmuring from the ranks — a Hufflepuff (not that there's anything wrong with them, great people, by the way) answered a question about Defence and got it right? Who was this boy? "In short," Quirrell continued, "as l-l-long as you're prepared and r-r-reasonably alert, most m-magical creatures pose l-little threat to a q-qualified wizard or w-witch. Now, who c-can tell me how fighting another w-wizard or w-w-witch is different?"

Again, it was Cedric who raised his hand first.

"Because, in theory, a wizard fighting another wizard is a fair fight," the handsome Hufflepuff explained. "They both have access to the same spells, and since every spell — Unforgivables aside, of course — can be countered in some fashion, it comes down to the differences between the individual witches or wizards in question."

"C-correct again," Quirrell said. "A-and another t-ten points for Hufflepuff. N-now, to the c-c-crux of the m-matter, what is the f-factor that will d-determine which w-wizard will prevail?"

This time, nearly every student in the hall raised their hand.

"Yes, Mister M-Malfoy?" Quirrell asked Draco, who was standing near the front, surrounded by a gaggle of Slytherins, as always.

"Blood purity and raw magical power," Draco said simply.

"I-interesting," Quirrell said. "And what s-say you, Miss G-Granger?"

"Practicing the most advanced spells," Hermione answered, "so that they can be cast reliably and effectively even under stressful circumstances."

"And y-you again, M-Mister D-Diggory?"

"Having friends and allies you can trust," Cedric said. "Something that Dark Wizards always lack, which is why they are always defeated."

"A t-true H-Hufflepuff answer," Quirrell said. "I'm s-sure H-Helga h-herself w-would agree w-with you wholeheartedly."

Milo realized that, while Quirrell seemed to be choosing people from the crowd completely at random, a suspiciously large number of them — that is to say, all of them — seemed to be PCs or major NPCs.

"Put Cedric on the List," Milo whispered to Harry. "We'll be seeing more of him, count on it."

"M-Mister P-P-Potter," Quirrell said, "the only w-wizard here to s-survive an encounter w-with Y-Y-You-Know-Who. W-what w-would you say is the s-s-secret to your s-success?"

Harry, almost alone among the Hogwarts students, hadn't raised his hand.

"Um," he said. "Well, I mean, I don't really know. So... I would have to say luck. A million factors that neither wizard really knows about come into play, and could result in, well, like you said. Me surviving against You-Know-Who."

"A-and what about you, M-Mister M-Milo of the lengthy last name?" Quirrell asked. "What determines the victor?" Hmm, Milo thought. Good question. Most people would say the highest level wizard wins, but that's not always true, now is it? A high-level Wizard optimized for basketweaving and lute-playing would be crushed by a properly-optimized lower-level Wizard.

"The wizard who memorizes and casts the most appropriate spells wins," Milo said. "Unless, like Harry said, the other one rolls a well-timed twenty. Er, that is, gets in an exceptionally lucky shot. But you can't count on that."

"Indeed you c-cannot," Quirrell said, "which b-brings me to the m-most important f-factor in a d-d-duel," he paused dramatically, letting everyone wonder what he was going to was going to say. "Strategy. As any spell — w-with the obvious exceptions, of c-c-course — c-can be c-countered, the d-duel goes t-to whichever wizard that d-doesn't m-make the f-first mistake. C-Curses, H-Hexes, Charms, and their c-counters can all be t-taught, learned, and p-p-practised in a straightforward m-manner — which we w-will g-get to, in g-g-good t-time — but g-good strategy, and thinking q-quickly on your f-f-feet cannot be w-without m-much difficulty. S-so th-that is where we w-will start." Quirrell gave his wand a complicated little wave and the Great Hall tables rolled into the centre of the room from their resting places at the edges. "And there is no better way to develop strategy than with chess." Sitting on the tables were hundreds of neatly-placed wizard chess sets with a pair of small red tags sitting next to each. "Everyone g-grab a p-partner and a tag," Quirrell said. "The w-winner of the m-match t-t-takes the loser's t-tag and challenges s-someone with a l-like number of t-tags. The l-losers will k-keep playing a-against other l-losers until they r-realize their m-mistake. W-we w-will continue until w-we find the b-best strategist, and therefore d-duellist, a-among you."

The Hogwarts students stared up at Quirrell in a stunned silence.

"Chess," Malfoy said flatly. "We're going to play chess. Why are we listening to this stuttering idiot, anyways? He's afraid of his own shadow."

"H-have you ever entered a n-nest of v-vampires, M-Mister M-M-Malfoy," Quirrell asked, "and s-survived w-with only a st-st-stutter to show f-for it?"

"Well —"

"N-no," Quirrell interrupted. "You h-have not. Y-you will either p-pick a p-partner, Mister M-Malfoy, or y-you will l-leave and w-w-wonder for the n-next t-twenty years why you are the w-w-worst d-duellist of your g-generation."

"Why twenty years?" Draco asked despite himself.

"An optimistic estimate of your l-lifespan should you ch-choose to f-forgo these l-lessons."

Malfoy paled and sat down across from Goyle, clipping a red tag to his lapel.

"This is ridiculous," Milo muttered to Hermione, his chess partner. "Skill Ranks in Profession (Chessmaster) have no bearing on one's ability to stomp squishy wizards."

"See, the thing is," Hermione said, "I know what all of those words mean in and of themselves, but the way you string them together... it's like someone handed a book of Mad Libs to a Confunded Troll."

"I'm a Confunded Troll, am I?" Milo asked with a slight edge in his voice. "Well you're blind to the story unfolding before your very eyes."

"Blind?" Hermione asked, a dangerous glint entering her eyes. "No, you're just convinced this is some storybook fairytale land where everything happens for a reason. And not a good reason, mind, but a stupid, trite, clichéd reason."

"Not a story," Milo said, placing his pieces on the board, "an adventure. Completely different school of magic."

"Real life does not have adventures!" Hermione said, her voice growing louder. "It has rules, responsible adults, homework, and grades!"

"I think we've more or less exhausted the possibilities of this conversation," Milo said coolly. "Roll for Initiative, bookworm."

Hermione, playing white, naturally won Initiative. She sent one of her Commoners forwards, breaking their naturally defensive spear-wall and leaving her Aristocrats vulnerable to a cavalry charge from Milo's flanking Knights.

"My left and right Clerics cast Wall of Stone and Flame Strike, respectively," Milo declared, "while the Commoners garrison these towers and ready an action to provide covering fire should any white soldiers enter range of their crossbows. The Knights run up to this position," he placed the two horses near Hermione's Clerics to Attack of Opportunity them should they try to cast anything, "and my Aristocrats take a full defence action."

"Er," Hermione said. "You can only move one piece on your turn."

"Oh, we're tracking individual Initiatives? Okay. In that case, Flame Strike. Let's see some Reflex Saves, now, shall we?"

"Why me?" Hermione asked the air dramatically. "Why? What did I ever do to deserve this? You know what? Here. Just take my tag, I forfeit. It's just not worth it. I'll go play with Neville in the corner." Hermione stalked off as Milo clipped Hermione's tag to his robes under his own.

"One down," he smirked. "Four hundred to go."

"Blimey," said one of Milo's Clerics. "I don't think you quite understand how this works, do you?"

"Holy Crap! You can talk?"

o—o—o—o

It didn't take long for Ron to win a small hoard of victory tags (crushing Milo mercilessly in the process), leaving him with only one opponent in his level: Cedric Diggory, the Uber-Hufflepuff.

The hundreds of defeated students gathered around, causing such a disturbance that Milo conjured up a massive illusory chess set in the air that mimicked Ron's and Cedric's moves. The game progressed largely in silence, save for the occasional "check" from either player, as the two masters stared at the board in deep concentration.

The game had already lasted longer than the rest of the tournament put together, with the two of them sometimes taking up to fifteen minutes to make a single move. It was Cedric's turn, and, after what seemed like years of careful consideration, he moved his remaining bishop forwards.

"Check," he said, finally.

Ron moved like lightening, slamming his rook into place.

"Check mate, mate," Ron exclaimed exuberantly.

"Ah, shame," Cedric said, but it was with a smile that he passed over his original tag. "Good game though, eh?"

"Best I've ever played," Ron said sincerely.

"And th-th-there you have it," Quirrell stammered to the crowd. "The most b-b-brilliant master st-strategist, and, I'm s-sure, a-accomplished d-d-duellist, of the st-student b-b-body is none other than M-M-Mister R-R-Ronald Weasley."

"Weasley?" Malfoy scoffed. "Brilliant? Hufflepuff will win the House Cup before Weasley learns to tie his shoes properly."

"C-c-class dismissed," Quirrell said with a wave. "W-W-Weasley, can I t-t-talk to you f-for a m-moment?"

"Uh," Ron said, looking somewhat panicked. "Sure, I guess."

"N-n-next time," Quirrell said to everyone, "w-we're learning E-Expelliarmus."

o—o—o—o

Milo followed Harry and Hermione back to the Common Room, where he sat in the corner working on Hannah's Amulet. I need to find a faster way of making these, he thought impatiently, etching a minute arcane rune onto a Sickle destined for melting into the final medallion.

"Well," Harry said, putting aside his History of Magic textbook, "that was sort of unexpected, don't you think?"

"What, Quirrell's club?" Hermione asked.

"Yeah," Harry said. "That man's off his rocker, I swear. Still... if it helps me learn to fight, well, I suppose it'll be worth it."

"I agree," Milo said. "Whatever happened to him over the summer's definitely unhinged him. And this 'chess' is hardly an adequate simulation of realistic battlefield conditions — I mean, why in the Hells can the heavy cavalry only move in right angles? It makes no sense!"

"You're just sore because the rules can't be gamed," Hermione smirked. "Which, incidentally, is why it's so popular. You have to use actual strategy and tactics."

"Strategy is gaming the rules," Milo responded. "It's analyzing the situation and seizing any and every possible advantage, even if it's completely ridiculous on the surface. Why, I once met this Half-Ogre who managed to defeat an entire Legion of the Tharllian Empire's best troops with a Spiked Chain because —"

"I'm sorry," Hermione said, looking sick. "Did you say Half-Ogre?"

Before Milo could answer, Ron entered the Common Room through the portal with a chess set in his hands.

"Oi!" Harry said. "What did Quirrell want?"

"To play chess," Ron answered happily. "Weird, eh? He said he wants to test his skills against a worthy opponent, so every other day I make a move against him and every other other day he makes one against me. He gave me this chess set," Ron held up his new set, "which is linked to the one in his office. If I make a move here, he sees it there, and vice-versa. Cool, eh?"

"Why so slow?" Hermione asked. "If he wanted to test your duelling aptitude, shouldn't you be playing speed chess?"

"Or using actual magic?" Milo added.

"He said that this way, I'll have as much time as I need to think out my move and make sure I make the right one," Ron shrugged. "He says it's more interesting that way. He implied that he hadn't had a decent sparring partner in years."

"Seems a bit late in the plot for him to suddenly develop such a major character trait as 'chess grand-master,'" Milo mused. "I wonder what he's up to?"

Hermione glanced at Ron and rotated her finger slowly around her ear in the universally-accepted sign for 'crazy.'

"Maybe he just really likes chess?" Harry suggested. "I mean, it's not like we would have had a chance to see it in action before, right?"

"I suppose... but, even so. Harry: add 'chess' to the List, and Ron: win that game against Quirrell."

"Why?" Ron asked. "Well, I mean, I was planning to anyway, but why is it important?"

"I don't know exactly," Milo said. "I just have a gut feeling that something important is riding on that match," he said, "and, as a rule of thumb, winning always leads to the more desirable outcome — and with it, the best swag."

"Okay, well, I'll do my best," Ron said.

"And I'd best get to Quidditch practice," Harry said, rising from his armchair. "We're playing Hufflepuff on Saturday, and Wood's gone into mad slavemaster mode again."

"This was nice," Hermione said, relaxing in her chair.

"What was?" Milo asked.

"A whole weekend went by and nobody was hospitalized," she said.

"Except Neville, of course," Milo said.

"Right, except Neville. Sad business, that. I had no idea a bishop could do that to a person. Still, be nice if every weekend was like this, but, I suppose that'd just be wishful thinking."

Despite Hermione's complacent attitude, Milo still felt something was wrong. This whole Duelling Club business smelled somewhat off to him, and he still didn't know who the Dark Wizard who Imperius'd him and Hannah was, or what he wanted. Was it Snape, trying to kill Milo to remove an obstacle between him and the Stone? Or Lucius, stepping out from the shadows and getting his hands dirty personally? And why had Milo been Imperius'd in the hallways — whoever had done it didn't seem to get much out of it. The whole attack seemed, in hindsight, remarkably poorly-planned... it was almost like they didn't want to succeed — or, alternatively, their goals were so obscure that Milo simply couldn't figure them out.

Unless...

Milo frowned. Once he'd been possessed, it didn't seem like his controller knew quite what to do with him. His orders had been vague and, seemingly, without purpose. Had it been one of the servants of the Dark Lord, surely, he'd be ordered to kill Harry or steal the Stone? If it was Lucius — or Snape for that matter — you'd think he'd be ordered to do something incriminating and be expelled (or, failing that, simply walk out of the school grounds to be captured). And what of those other eleven minds he'd detected?

On the whole, if that were some sort of strike against Milo or his allies, it had been a rather clumsy attempt. The more Milo thought about it, the more he was certain that he was looking at things backwards.

Suddenly, Milo felt as if a Wight had an icy hand around his heart.

"Hermione," Milo said slowly. "What were the methods you suggested for changing someone's heart's desire?"

"Are you still on that?" she asked, racking her memory. "Love potions, the Confundus Charm, or a Memory Charm. Why?"

"What, exactly, is a Memory Charm?" Milo asked, but he was sure he knew the answer already. Back on Hallowe'en, when Milo touched the Remembrall...

"It's an advanced spell that wipes someone's memory of a duration of time," she explained. "A skilled user can replace them with false memories altogether. I wouldn't worry about it, though," she said reassuringly.

"Why not?" Milo asked, feeling somewhat mollified.

"We don't have to learn them until Seventh Year," she said happily.

Milo cursed sulfurously and nearly ran for the exit.

"Wait!" Hermione called. "Where are you going?"

"To see Neville," Milo said.

Chapter 23: The Duelling Club

Today's character sheet: myth-weavers com/sheetview php?sheetid=447028 (Replace the spaces with periods)

(Extra Long) Author's Notes (feel free to skip them, there's nothing particularly important): This weekend, I decided that now might be a good time to go back and reread some of my earlier chapters and make sure I didn't have any plot threads I'd left hanging. While I was at it, I thought, I could make improvements to the start of the story using what I'd writing the rest of it.

This proved to be a colossal mistake. A number of wiser and better writers than me tell me that it is universal among writers to be embarrassed by anything they've ever written, but I never really believed it until now. The first chapter of this story is terrible. It is shamefully bad. I can't imagine how any of you managed to stand it (but I'm glad you did).

I got three pages in and closed the lid of my laptop by reflex as a defence mechanism to get the horror away. That said, I managed to change a sentence in which I used Milo's name twice (pronouns FTW) and posted the edit, so that's something.

/Horrified Rant.

On a completely different topic, I've had a large number of reviews and messages asking me similar questions, so I think I'll make an official sort of FAQ statement now:

Q: Does D&D (the tabletop game) exist in the world of Harry Potter and the Natural 20?
A: No, it does not, and neither do its descendent spin-off RPGs. In any case, the story is set in the early nineties, and 3e wasn't released until 2000.

Q: Will [insert HP character here] gain D&D class levels or powers? (Or, alternatively, will Milo gain HP wizard magic?)
A: No. Milo and [insert HP character] are an entirely different kind of human that follow an entirely different set of laws of the universe. Milo is closer to a Muggle or Squib than a wizard, and HP-world characters do not gain experience points.

Q: Why doesn't Milo invent a spell (or feat) that does X?
A: I'm avoiding having Milo invent new spells (or feats, PrCs, etc.) altogether (that is, spells not present in any of the D&D core or splatbooks) because homebrew material involves a lot of DM discretion which to a certain extent negates the point (and fun) of min-maxing. Imagine Milo's world is run by a hardline Rules-As-Written DM who gets wrathful when anyone tries to push anything too far.

Q: Have you ever heard of/will you update to Pathfinder or 4e?
A: Pathfinder is a fantastic improvement of the 3.5 rules that I highly recommend to anyone and everyone; I'm not a fan of 4th edition for a number of reasons, but lots of people like it so I suppose it can't be all bad. That said, I'm staying strictly within the 3.5 rules because a) they're what I'm most familiar with, b) I'd feel bad about poking fun at a smaller company like Paizo (WOTC is fair game, though), and c) I feel that updating the rules partway through would detract from the story, screw with any readers that aren't major D&D fans, and necessitate a lot of jokes and fun-poking at the differences between 3.5 and 4 or 3.5 and Pathfinder, and generally detract from the jokes and fun-poking at the differences between Harry Potter and D&D3.5.

Q: Will you do the whole series?
A: That's the plan.

Q: What splatbook is Myra (City of Light! City of Magic!) and the Azel Empire from?
A: None of them. The names are pulled from campaigns I've DM'd over the years, but are otherwise completely original (or rather, completely unoriginal, seeing as how the Azel Empire is a deliberate cariciture of most campaign settings). The "City of Light! City of Magic!" line is a reference to The Elder Scrolls: Morrowind, in which the Mournhold city guards spout the line endlessly.

Q: Is Milo (at least, at the start of the fic) an example of how you play D&D?
A: Only when I hate the DM.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

"I think it's about time we had a little chat," Milo said, closing the office door behind him. "About what really happened in the Forbidden Forest in September."

Quirrell slid his office chair backwards slightly, covering the motion of his hand as he covertly drew his wand.

"W-what about it?" he asked, his voice kept carefully neutral.

"There were always a few facts about that night that never quite added up to me," Milo said, ignoring the Professor. "For example — how did I get poisoned? The Acromantula never had a chance. How did the Acromantula die? The log I dropped on it wasn't nearly enough to do the deed."

"It l-looked quite heavy t-to m-m-me," Quirrell stammered.

"It should have shrugged the log off and eaten me on the spot," Milo told him. "And it's body had no signs of prior injury, so it isn't like the log was enough to push it over the edge into negative hit points. No, something else killed that Acromantula. Something that kills its target without leaving a trace."

Quirrell tightened the grip on his wand beneath the desk.

"I-I don't —"

"Oh, I think you do," Milo said. "There's only one spell that could do that, and, Hells, you used it against Fluffy. You're a hero for it, after all. The Killing Curse."

"W-what —"

"But the Curse is hardly stealthy, it has a signature bright green flash. The spider was right in front of me and it was pitch dark — there's no possible way I could have missed it."

"Y-you m-must have," Quirrell said. "Or r-rather, the Acromantula d-died s-some other —"

"No," Milo cut him off. "Don't you see? I saw the spider killed. A wizard did it right before my very eyes. He just walked right up, killed the Acromantula, and left. He cut off one of the spider's fangs — Acromantula venom is potent even after death, after all — and stabbed me in the stomach with it. I saw everything."

"Then w-why d-d-didn't you s-say so earlier?"

Milo reached into his robes, and Quirrell, surprised, nearly killed him on the spot. It was only the knowledge that Milo had no need of a wand to use magic that stayed his hands.

Of all things, it was a Remembrall that Milo withdrew from his pocket.

A Remembrall which shone like the sun.

"I was Memory Charmed."

"Th-that's hardly proof," Quirrell pointed out. "P-perhaps you s-simply f-f-forgot to b-brush your t-t-teeth l-last night?"

"I, like any self-respecting Arcanist, use Prestidigitation, which is quite beside the point. I can prove to you that it was no inconsequential memory that I've forgotten," Milo said calmly. "Describe the Remembrall for me, Professor."

"I d-d-don't understand," Quirrell said.

"It's quite simple. Just... a quick description of this ball will suffice."

Quirrell shrugged. What's this boy's game?

"It's a t-tennis b-ball s-s-sized c-clear g-g-glass ball f-full of smoke," Quirell said. "I-it t-turns red when the h-h-holder f-forgets something and c-clear when it is r-r-remembered."

"That's an awful lot of adjectives, Professor," Milo said with a slight grin. "At least four."

"S-so what?"

"And it first turned up months ago in a seemingly inconsequential manner — something unimportant about Harry joining the Quidditch team — and again on Hallowe'en, when it broke. Fortunately, one of Neville's supporting characters sent him a replacement. That makes this the third time it's turned up, Professor."

"This m-matters how?"

"Rule of Three. This here, judging by the amount of attention it's gathered, is a very significant plot device. Why, it'd simply be a waste of time if it didn't turn out to be important."

"That's your proof?"

"I've seen men hanged for less in Myra — City of Light, City of Magic!"

"Even a-assuming this is t-t-true," Quirrell said, watching the boy closely, "w-who would d-do such a thing?"

"I think we both know the answer to that question, Professor."

Quirrell tensed, ready to strike.

"It was, of course," Milo said, leaning forwards slightly, "none other than Professor Snape."

"S-Snape?" Quirrell asked. "H-how d-do you know?"

"Honestly, who else would it be?" Milo asked. "You can't shake a staff in this castle without finding an evil plot Snape's behind. I'm starting to think he's only still a teacher because of how dull things would be without him."

"W-why wouldn't he j-just l-let the A-Acromantula k-kill you?" Quirrell asked.

"That's the bit I can't figure out," Milo admitted. "But I'm sure he'll be good enough to explain it in his villain monologue at the end."

"W-why are you t-telling me this?"

"Oh, simple. Snape can pull memories from my head, so I figure I should disseminate important information to trustworthy NPCs — as a sort of backup. Also, and I hate to say this, I'm starting to think I'll need all the help I can get. This situation is becoming... complicated, for a number of reasons. Gods, what I wouldn't give for a straightforward sidequest or monster hunt. In any event, I don't suppose you know of any way to cure Memory Charms?"

"S-sorry," Quirrell apologised. "I-I'm afraid they're g-generally q-quite permanent."

"Hells," Milo cursed. "And Protection From Evil won't do a thing against them, either, based on Hermione's description, which means I'll need to think of something clever. Well, I suppose it can't be used on me as long as I've got my..." Milo trailed off for a second. "That's it!" he exclaimed, and headed back for the door.

"W-wait!" Quirrell called, but Milo, frustratingly, seemed suddenly oblivious to his existence.

o—o—o—o

"It was like an Attack of Opportunity," Milo explained to his party (and Hannah). "His plan wasn't to Imperius me to further his elaborate scheme; he Imperius'd me because I was there."

"Why?" Harry asked. Milo was standing in front of them in the Gryffindor Common Room, a revised version of The Plot hovering in the air, shimmering slightly.

"To prevent me from finding out what he was up to with his eleven Disillusioned friends," Milo answered. "He didn't know or care about the Mirror. He just wanted me gone before I figured out what he was up to. It worked, too."

"So why not simply Stun you?" Hermione asked.

"Or even better, just finish you off for good?" Ron added.

"Or, even better, Memory Charm you — like you said he did after the Acromantula."

"I can't say for sure," Milo said, "but I think it's because he was hoping nobody would notice. A perfect crime, so to speak. Snape doesn't seem to be skilled enough at Memory Charms to replace the target's memories with false ones — at least, I hope he isn't, or we're all screwed — so I'd wake up wondering where the last several minutes went. Something which Mordy here would be all too happy to fill me in on. As for why he didn't kill me... well, he doesn't seem to want me dead anymore, for some reason — except when he does. He's very inconsistent, in fact."

"What do you mean?" Hannah asked.

"Well," Milo explained, "one day he wants me expelled and the next he's possessing you to kill me."

"Sorry about that," Hannah said quietly.

"It wasn't your fault," Milo said. "Just keep your amulet on, and you'll be fine." Milo had decided on impulse to give Hannah the Amulet of Protection From Evil that he'd reserved for himself, meaning he'd have to wait another two days for his. He still wasn't quite sure why he'd done it.

"I'm starting to wonder if something more complicated isn't going on," Milo said.

"Even more complicated than that?" Ron groaned, pointing at The Plot.

"Snape's erratic attempts just aren't lining up anymore. If he really wanted me resting in Boccob's uncaring embrace, why did Hannah open up with Stunners?"

"I thought you said she used Unforgivables," Hermione said.

"She switched when I ducked for cover," Milo explained. "Unless there's some rule or class feature I'm unaware of, Hannah's strategy made no sense."

"Hey," Hannah said.

"Sorry, I mean, Snape's strategy made no sense."

"Well," Hermione mused, "maybe he doesn't want you dead at all?"

"Then why did Hannah use Killing Curses at all?" Milo asked. "It's completely nonsensical."

"Then one of your assumptions is wrong," Hermione said bluntly. "Personally, I don't think it's Snape at all."

"But we know it's him," Milo protested. "He was out meeting Lucius in the forest and everything. Use your eyes, Hermione! He's so obviously villainous."

"And yet," Hermione said coolly, "Dumbledore — the brightest mind of his generation and the most powerful wizard alive — lets him teach here regardless. What do we know about Snape?"

"That he's a smarmy git?" Ron suggested helpfully.

"And that he's allergic to shampoo?" Harry added.

"No," Hermione said firmly. "We know that he met Lucius in the forest and Lucius ordered him to have you expelled, Milo. Expelled. Not murdered."

"Well, maybe he's upped the ante since then —"

"See, I don't think he has. Assuming he was behind the attack on Harry in the Quidditch match, and the test to show you can't make potions, that's two completely non-lethal attempts to expel you."

"Then why would he release a Troll on Hallowe'en, stab me with an Acromantula fang, possess Hannah to kill me, and have the Drow in the kitchen poison my treacle tart?" Milo asked.

"Why indeed?" Hermione smiled. "What if he didn't do any of those things?"

"What," Milo scoffed, "are you suggesting the treacle tart poisoned itself on its own accord?"

"No," Hermione continued, "I'm suggesting there's another agent at play here. Could you adjust the display for a moment? Place Snape and Mister Malfoy off to the side with the various attempts to expel you, and Draco to a different side with his fumbled Quidditch plots."

"If it makes you happy," Milo said, adjusting his illusion. "But that leaves a big hole here, though, with the various assassination attempts."

"Indeed it does," agreed Hermione.

"So... who fills the gap?" Ron asked.

"That's the question we should be asking."

"You aren't seriously suggesting that there's three entirely separate camps of villains working against us?" Milo asked. "That'd just be a huge mess. They'd spend half their time tripping over themselves."

"Why shouldn't there be?" Hermione asked. "Sometimes, real life is just a huge mess."

"Otiluke's Razor suggests otherwise," Milo countered.

Hermione paused.

"Don't you mean Occam's Razor?" she asked tentatively. "'The simplest solution is usually the best one?'"

"Psht! What nonsense is that?" Milo said dismissively. "No, it's, 'the most dramatically appropriate solution is usually the best one.' In this case, it's clearly that You-Know-Who is pulling all the strings behind the scenes." Milo rearranged The Plot to demonstrate, "Except that there's some unknown factor thrown in there as well — probably a betrayal by someone close to us, I'm thinking Neville — which will only be revealed by the villain's final rant. And, as the time-tested Tenser's Theorem states, 'any attempt to discover a shocking twist before the end of an adventure will be doomed to failure, so focus on the job in front of you.' Ergo: defeating 'Puffs in Quidditch."

"I ... don't follow," Hermione admitted.

"Remember when Harry stomped the Slytherins?" Milo asked. "It was a big deal. The Daily Prophet had a field day about... well, about something to do with broomsticks, anyways."

"That both the Nimbus and the prototype Firebolts seemed to suffer from a similar flaw and went haywire," Ron said. "And that the Boy-Who-Lived is quote, unquote 'in addition to being top student in his year, also the best Seeker Hogwarts has seen in many a year —'"

"But I'm not the —" Harry protested.

"Hold up, I haven't even got to the part where it talks about how supremely handsome you are," Ron snickered. "Malfoy wasn't mentioned at all, by the way."

"You see?" Milo said. "There's obviously some kind of subplot or sidequest involving Quidditch. I can only assume that we'll get bonus XP or Magic Items if we win the Cup. So: we'll win."

"But that match against Slytherin was hardly fair," Harry said. "There were plots within bloody plots. I've only been in one real game, what if Hufflepuff wins?"

"Well," Milo said conspiratorially, "I think I can help you a bit, there..."

o—o—o—o

"Mount your brooms, please," Milo heard Madam Hooch say from his seat up in the stands. The Hufflepuffs had arrived with banners bearing a variety of fairly unoriginal slogans (and occasional trash-talk, but Milo suspected that was from the Slytherins, who, strangely, had come out to the witch and wizard to root on the Hufflepuffs) to which Milo had responded with a Silent Image of a fifty-foot tall Crimson-and-Gold Gryffindor lion devouring a Hufflepuff badger. When he added Ghost Sound (which accurately mimicked, in both pitch and volume, the roar of an enraged Dire Tiger, amplified by the voices of the actual students of House Gryffindor — and more than a few Ravenclaws), McGonagall awarded him five points for amazing spellwork and then banned all form of banner, magical or otherwise, from the rest of the match.

When Hooch gave a loud blast of her whistle, the signal to start the game, the players blasted off into the air — but Harry was much, much faster than the rest. This was due to a combination of two factors: Harry's vastly superior Nimbus broomstick, and the fact that he was currently under the effects of Levitate, making him effectively weightless.

"Locate Object — Golden Snitch," Milo muttered under his breath. "Message: Harry, it's thirty-three degrees to my right and eighteen degrees upwards." Milo had carefully chosen the seat closest to dead-centre in the auditorium that he could manage, which put him (unfortunately) almost directly next to Snape.

As Milo continued to mutter instructions under his breath, he noticed something surprising. Quirrell, sitting nearby, had one eyebrow cocked quizzically. Probably thinks I'm praying or something, Milo thought. He can't know what I'm up to, though, can he? Idly, Milo wondered if there was a rule against him pointing the Snitch out to Harry. In any case, what could they do? Milo thought, it's not like you can award a penalty against the audience.

The Hufflepuffs, to be fair, did fairly well for themselves — they managed to seize possession of the Quaffle early on, and the three Chasers, passing the ball between themselves rapidly, were quickly boring down on Wood, defending the goals — not that it helped them much, in the end. Roughly forty seconds (forty-two to be precise, or exactly seven rounds) after the start of the match, Lee Jordan's magically amplified voice rang out over the pitch.

"POTTER HAS THE SNITCH! POTTER HAS THE SNITCH! HA HA, TAKE THAT YOU DUMB, DIRTY, HUFFLEPUFF B—"

"JORDAN!" McGonagall shouted sharply.

"Broomstick flyers, Professor. I was going to say broomstick flyers — honest."

The score was 150-0. The Hufflepuffs were too stunned to process their defeat, much less respond, while close to one-third of the audience erupted into thunderous applause.

"Blimey," said Fred, who sat nearby.

"We're going to need to raid Honeydukes again," said George.

It was, as Lee pointed out happily, the second shortest Quidditch match in Hogwarts History (the shortest, in 1412, ended before the whistle was finished blowing; the Snitch had flown directly down a Hufflepuff Chaser's throat. The Hufflepuff died, tragically, but there was much rejoicing nonetheless — it had been Hufflepuff's first win in over three centuries.)

o—o—o—o

"N-now that y-you know the b-b-basics of D-Disarming," Quirrell stammered to the Duelling Club that Sunday (which had shrunk somewhat since their first, chess-oriented meeting), "p-p-please p-p-pick a p-partner and p-practice."

They'd spent all morning learning Expelliarmus — or, rather, everyone else spent all morning learning Expelliarmus; Milo had been alone in the corner working out some of the kinks in his Fireball spell research. Quirrell's call to grab partners caught Milo somewhat by surprise, and he wound up partnered off to a first-year Ravenclaw NPC.

"I w-will c-count to three," Quirrell said, "and y-you will both t-try to d-disarm your p-partner. Only d-disarm, M-Mister C-Crabbe, I s-saw that l-look."

Milo looked up and down the lines of students. To the upper years, of course, Expelliarmus was old hat — but, in Quirrell's words, they could always be 'b-b-better.'

"Aren't you going to draw?" the Ravenclaw asked him nervously.

"What do I look like, a sketch artist?" Milo snorted derisively.

"No, your wand," the boy hissed. Milo blinked. Oh, right, he thought, and pulled his shiny, barely-used wand from his pocket. He could still smell the varnish that Ollivander (Milo shuddered, repressing the horrible memories) used.

"One," Quirrell counted. The Ravenclaw's wand hand shook. Milo wondered vaguely if a local wizard could accidentally trigger a Silent Spell just by making the right wand motions.

"T-two." Milo whistled casually, staring at the Great Hall's amazing ceiling.

"T-Three," Quirrell finished. A great cry of "Expelliarmus!" rose up from the upper-years, and wands flew in every direction. The first- and second-years, however, were not generally quite so lucky. Most of their spells fizzled out feebly, hardly having any impact whatsoever on their target's wands. Hermione managed to get Ron to drop his wand, but Ron later confessed (out of earshot of Hermione, of course) that he dropped it because his hand was sweaty.

Without a doubt, the worst student off in the hall was Milo's poor Ravenclaw target, who found himself pinned to the ground by a Hippogriff that had not existed a moment before. Several nearby first-years turned and ran in horror, their screams echoing throughout the hall.

"Fetch, Rary!" Milo called to his summoned monster. The Hippogriff grabbed the Ravenclaw's wand from his feebly protesting hand and trotted over to Milo, dropping it at his feet. "Good girl! Now, go back to the Upper Planes from whence you came!" Milo waved his hand, and the Hippogriff vanished as suddenly as it had arrived.

Students nearby — those who hadn't run off — backed away from Milo slowly. The Ravenclaw lay sobbing on the ground.

"It was horrible!" he moaned to himself. "With the talons and the beak and the eyes! Merlin, the eyes! The cold, uncaring eyes!"

"I think I won," Milo said over the screams and tears. "You're disarmed." The fact that nonlethal combat and stage fights only award less than half XP regardless, Milo had almost paid off a week of item crafting with a single spell.

Eyes looked towards Quirrell expectantly, the Hogwarts students presumably waiting for him to either tell Milo off or deduct House Points for traumatizing children. The Defence Professor, however, did nothing more than watch Milo with unreadable eyes.

If I get 75XP for every first year I defeat in a duel, Milo mused, I wonder how much I could earn practicing against a second year — or, for that matter, a seventh year.

As a couple of students carted off the gibbering Ravenclaw, Milo found himself face-to-face with Harry Potter.

"Look," Milo said to his bespectacled partymember. "We're an unbalanced party right now, and I'm higher level than you. That's just fact, it's not a bad thing, necessarily. Everyone started at level one at some point. You'll get up to my level one day, but until then, don't feel bad when you lose. It's really not your fault, I'm a wildly inappropriate CR for you."

"One," Quirrell counted.

"Don't worry," Harry said quietly, "I won't."

"Two."

"Glad to hear —"

"Won't lose, that is."

Milo simply chuckled softly.

"Th-three."

"Expelliarmus!" Milo stared in horror at his suddenly-empty gloved hand. His useless wand had been tossed halfway across the Great Hall, in plain view of dozens of witnesses. By a level one. In a fair fight.

"How did you do that?" Milo exclaimed. "Half your year can't even cast the spell, much less on their first try after winning Initiative!"

"I dunno," Harry admitted. "The spell just, sort of, came naturally to me."

"Rematch?" Milo asked.

"Sure," Harry agreed. Without needing to be asked, Mordy dropped out of his pocket and scurried across the floor to retrieve Milo's wand. "Whoever's wand hits the floor first loses."

"Expelliarmus!" Harry cast again as soon as Quirrell finished counting.

Milo's wand flew out of his hand, but abruptly stopped in midair a few feet behind him and floated back into his hand.

"How did you —"

"Cast Mage Hand when you weren't looking. Also, Grease." The wand in Harry's hand suddenly slipped through the fingers of his right hand, but, with reflexes only a Seeker could match, he caught it adroitly with his left.

"Expelliarmus!"

"Hells!" Milo cursed as the wand flew from his fingers again. He'd had to break concentration on Mage Hand in order to cast Grease, which he'd been certain would end the duel.

"Rematch?" Harry suggested cheerily.

"Count on it," Milo answered, and waited for Quirrell to start counting again. I'll have to stop underestimating him, Milo decided. He must have Improved Initiative and a high Dexterity score — makes sense, considering his Quidditch skills.

"Three," Quirrell finished.

"Nerveskitter! Grease!" Milo called, while Harry shouted "Expelliarmus!" simultaneously. Both their wands dropped to the floor with a clatter.

Milo picked up his wand and twirled it about his fingers idly. A few nearby students gave him an askance glance — if any of them started spinning a wand like it were a pencil, something was likely to catch fire.

"That... was impressive," Milo admitted grudgingly. If I'm level five and Harry's level one (is Harry still level one?) then he just got enough XP from me to level up about a dozen times. Could Harry level up? Do these local yokels even have levels, in the conventional sense? And if so, do they gain XP? The idea seemed farfetched to him, but it wasn't impossible — Redcaps, for example, increased in level by dipping their caps into the blood of dead sentient creatures. At least, his Redcaps did.

"Thank you," Harry said, sounding genuinely pleased. "Not like it'll do any good in a real battle, of course."

"Are you kidding?" Milo asked. "A no-save auto-disarm spell? Against enemies incapable of using magic without a wand in their hand? What you've got there, buddy, is a game changer. Sure, the other side seems awfully fond of Killing Curses — but really, when it comes down to it, they're tactically almost identical. A wandless wizard and a dead wizard are different only in time elapsed."

"I suppose," Harry said, his brow furrowed. "Shall we call it a draw, then?"

Milo managed to disarm another three NPCs in first- and second-years before running out of disarm-capable magic, at which point he became target practice.

"Yeah, yeah, laugh it up," Milo muttered, picking up his wand for the dozenth time in a row after some snotty punk of a Ravenclaw disarmed him (odd how the more he lost, the snottier and punkier his opponents seemed to become).

"A-and I think that's all for t-t-today," Quirrell said, dismissing the club. Almost everybody turned to leave, but a large number of students (including, to Milo's satisfaction, a certain young Malfoy heir) had to root around to find their wands first. As people filed towards the exits, the turbaned professor walked over to where Milo was grumbling. "I h-have to ask," Quirrell said softly, "why are y-you in this c-club? It's n-not like you c-can learn anything I h-have to t-t-teach."

"Are you kidding?" Milo asked. "I got two hundred and twenty-five Experience Points today. Not a patch on what I got from that Redcap over the holidays, but it's a respectable amount nonetheless."

"Indeed?" Quirrell said, and suddenly smiled. "W-well, I'm g-glad to hear it."

The strange thing was, he really did seem happy on Milo's behalf. Great, Milo thought irritably. For once I succeed a Sense Motive check, and that's what I learn? Why do I even bother?

"Thanks," Milo muttered.

"S-something you s-said last w-w-week stuck in my m-mind," Quirrell said. "About s-sidequests and s-subplots."

"Oh?"

"I th-think I h-h-have one s-such opportunity," Quirrell said quietly. "B-but it m-m-must stay b-between us. C-can you agree t-t-to that?"

"Of course," Milo said. He knew a plot hook when he saw it; he'd say just about anything to get the conversation to the 'quest offer' point.

"S-something is s-still preying on unicorns," Quirrell said conspiratorially.

"Is the Troll back?" Milo said. "I heard it ran off pretty quick last time."

"N-no," Quirrell said. "At least, n-not to my knowledge. No, I b-believe s-something else is hunting the p-p-poor, d-defenceless, innocent unicorns."

"Really?" Milo asked, intrigued. "So, the Troll was innocent the whole time? This complicates things even further," he mused.

"N-now, it's e-extremely d-d-dangerous," Quirrell said, "a-and I'd q-quite understand if you —"

"I'm in," Milo interrupted. Adventurers, as a rule, didn't go around not doing extremely dangerous things. "What's the job?"

If Quirrell was thrown by Milo's sudden agreement to help, he didn't show it. "There is a c-c-cave deep within the F-Forbidden F-F-Forest," Quirrell explained. "So d-deep it's n-nearly on the f-far border."

"Caves are good," Milo said fervently. Gods, what he'd do for a decent dungeon crawl.

"N-not this c-cave, I f-fear. It's unlikely, b-but I f-f-fear it's p-previous ... occupants ... have r-returned."

"And they're killing the unicorns for blood?"

"They d-do seem the t-type," Quirrell admitted, "b-being V-V-V-Vampires."

Milo gave a low whistle. He knew he hadn't been carrying around five pounds of garlic powder all these years in vain. "Why do you need my help?" Milo asked.

Quirrell glanced from side to side nervously. "T-to t-tell the truth," he said, "I'm t-t-terrified. It's m-my d-d-duty as D-Defence Professor to investigate, but... V-V-V-V-V—"

"—Vampires—"

"Yes, thank you, V-V-V... bloodsuckers t-terrify me. I w-wouldn't be asking for help if I d-didn't know you h-had so m-much experience w-with th-them."

"When do we leave?" Milo asked.

"Friday," Quirrell said. "J-just after d-dark."

Milo was so fixated on his conversation with Quirrell that he completely failed to notice that Draco Malfoy, despite having long since found his wand, had yet to leave the room...

Chapter 27: Enchanter's End Game

Some time before 7 AM, the villagers of Hogsmeade were surprised to find a dirty, bloodied, half-dead (or rather, four-thirteenths, to be precise, since you asked) young boy stumble into their village.

Again.

But, today, the boy didn't look exhausted. He didn't look lost, or confused, or afraid, or even hungry (making him practically unique among eleven-year-olds everywhere).

He just looked determined.

"Someone tell Dumbledore," he said to a random NPC. "I need help."

"I'm right here in front of you," the NPC replied sullenly.

The boy blinked, and, his mask of determination briefly broken, evidently decided to reconcile the apparent impossibility in front of him by ignoring it. Just as quickly as he appeared, the NPC, as far as the boy was concerned, was deleted from existence, as was all non-plot-relevant information in the town. Shops, taverns, and potential bolt-holes were taken in with a glance and carefully categorized and noted for future use. Houses, paving stones, magical streetlights, owls, and trashbins were summarily dismissed as irrelevant, never even making it to his conscious brain.

"Well," the boy said aloud. "I suppose there's nothing else for it." Without a glance backwards, as if Hogsmeade had no further use for him, the boy strode out of the town and towards the castle.

"Nobody ever wants to send for me," Aberforth said, sounding slightly disappointed.

o—o—o—o

Harry was surprised to find Professor Quirrell tapping his feet impatiently by the Fat Lady when he stumbled through the portal, bleary-eyed and ready for breakfast. He'd hardly gotten any sleep the night before; he, Ron, and Hermione had stayed awake worrying about Milo. The only thing that held him back from charging off to rescue his friend headfirst was the simple fact that none of them had any idea where the Death Eaters had apparated to. Hannah had vanished into the girls' dormitories early in the evening to be by herself.

"Professor?" Harry asked, bouncing with anticipation. "Have you found him?" There was no need to mention who he was talking about.

"Y-yes," Quirrell said grimly, then softened slightly. "I-I'm s-sorry, H-Harry. I know he was a friend of yours."

Icy tendrils gripped Harry's heart.

"You don't—you can't mean—he isn't..." he trailed off lamely.

"N-not yet," the Professor said. "B-but at this p-point, it's really only a matter of t-time. He was hit by a powerful curse. I'm s-sorry, Harry."

He couldn't believe it. It was impossible. The strange boy had, despite his oddities, quickly become one of Harry's best friends. Milo had once faced down a Troll and very nearly not gotten thrown out a window. He couldn't believe it would end like this; it felt wrong. Unfair. Like he'd been cheated out of something.

"Isn't there anything that can be done?" Harry insisted. "We have all this weird, wondrous, crazy magic. There must be something—have you taken him to Madam Pomfrey? Or Saint Mungo's? Where is he—can I see him?"

"He's at Saint M-M-Mungo's," Quirrell explained. "But he's unconscious; their b-b-best healers are w-w-working on him. Unfortunately, they d-d-don't know where to b-b-begin, his physiology is s-so different from ours. He's slipping f-fast. I'm s-sorry to be the one to t-t-tell you."

No. Harry refused to let this happen.

"We can save him," Harry insisted.

"I know y-you're d-distraught—" Quirrell began, but Harry was in no mood for condescension. He didn't feel distraught, oddly—he just felt determined. There was something that had to be done, and he would do it.

"There's something in this castle that can cure any illness," Harry said slowly. "It can save him. I'm sure of it."

Quirrell looked stunned.

"Surely, you d-d-don't mean..."

"Yes. We need the Philosopher's Stone."

o—o—o—o

Milo Amastacia-Liadon slammed open the Hogwarts front gates, casting an embarrassingly short shadow (an eleven-year-old's stature does not generally lend itself to appropriate levels of drama) down the front hallway; the rising sun blazing a brilliant orange behind him.

"Oh, has the ickle-wickle firstie snuck out again?" came a taunting, mocking voice from the air above him. Casually sidestepping a dropped bucket of whitewash—honestly, warning him before attacking? Fastest way to waste a Surprise Round against Flat-Footed AC he knew of—Milo glanced at the poltergeist. Just glanced. It had taken him the better part of a day to walk to Hogsmeade from the Malfoy Manor—again—not including the night he spent in the wilderness to regain his spells. He'd come too far, there was too much at stake, for him to be distracted by an undead clown with poor fashion sense. He couldn't see his own expression, of course, but whatever it was made Peeves's pale (to the extent that a poltergeist is able to, that is) and bolt clear through the wall.

Striding up the stairs to Dumbledore's secret office—Hermione thought having the Headmaster's office password-protected and isolated from the students contributed to an atmosphere of fear and suspicion, but Milo thought it was simply practical—even though he knew the headmaster wouldn't be there. He didn't know where Dumbledore would be, or what the Headmaster was doing, but one thing was for sure: the Otyugh was about to hit the Blade Barrier, and, for that to happen, all powerful, friendly NPCs must go.

That said, Milo's Plot-sense had been wrong before, so he at least had to go through the motions.

"Sherbet Lemon," he said, and the gargoyle corkscrewed upwards.

Cautiously—Quirrell must know Milo would drop by Dumbledore's office before heading for him; there was always the possibility of a trap—he climbed the stairs and peered into the perennially buzzing, clicking, and whirring room.

No Dumbledore. No Fawkes, even.

"Nerull's knees!" Milo cursed. Sometimes, he hated being right. Milo turned around, intending to head to the fateful third-floor corridor. He always knew it would come to this.

"Wait!" It was Mordy's voice. He stopped reflexively; the familiar hadn't yet led him astray.

"Why?" Milo asked. "For all we know, he's already got the Stone and is halfway to his master."

"Remember what we decided about going alone?" The rat, sitting on Milo's shoulder, asked. "And, for example, what a terrible idea it is? No Class is a Party."

"They're not ready," Milo objected. "They could die." Hannah could die.

"Then we'll tip the Cleric. Worse things have happened, and can we really afford to pick and choose? We'll need them. Can't you feel it?"

The worst part of it was that he could. Just as he knew he had to first go to Dumbledore, he knew, in his heart of hearts, that he'd need backup—even low-level backup.

"All right."

Milo had to force himself not to sprint down the winding, ever-shifting corridors to the Gryffindor Common Room—any time gained by running would likely be lost being harassed by Filch, who viewed any student running as an excuse to chase. He was assuming they were in the Common Room. He hoped they were. He could use magic to find them, of course, but he needed to save his spells for what was to come next.

"Well, well, well," a particularly grating voice taunted. "What have we here? Little freak, all by himself?"

"Draco," Milo said to the pale, blonde-haired boy with false cheerfulness. Crabbe and Goyle were flanking him, standing exactly half a step behind him like the rear wheels of a tricycle. They probably drilled the formation. "I met your dad last night. Kicked his ass, too."

"Why, you lit—" Milo didn't even wait for the Slytherin to finish his trite, clichéd comeback. With a smooth motion, he pulled his darkwood quarterstaff from his belt and gave Draco a good, solid whack to the stomach. The expression of surprise on the spoiled boy's face was worth a fortune—okay, well, maybe a few hundred gp, tops. Milo wasn't willing to invest a significant amount of his allotted Wealth-By-Level in anything involving what amounted to a schoolyard bully. Of course, the WBL system had been shot to Pandemonium by Harry's massive inheritance. The sentiment still stands.

Crabbe and Goyle, torn between wanting to help their master and take vengeance from Milo's hide, hesitated one crucial second.

Milo's combat skills, especially his Base Attack Bonus, were pitiful—by the standards of another Class of equivalent Level. However, from what he could tell, the local wizards (inexplicably) didn't seem to improve in hand-to-hand combat at all unless they deliberately trained in it. While this made no sense to Milo—everyone knew that sufficient practice in anything that grants Experience Points improves all aspects of one's Character—he had no qualms taking advantage of it. Crabbe and Goyle were moderately competent fighters (for eleven-year-olds), but Milo had them lying on their backs in twelve seconds, flat.

With a needlessly showy twirl, he sheathed his quarterstaff back into his extradimensional space and continued on toward his destination, not bothering to look back.

Malfoy and his cronies would be back later, Milo was sure. Recurring villains were like pimples on a teenager in that sense. The harder you tried to finish them off, the more likely they were to show up the night of the Hallowe'en dance when you're trying to impress Lisa Sanders from Home Ec. One day, with a few more Levels under their belts, they'd likely be a genuine threat. But until that day... they could talk to the stick.

Milo left them, shocked and gasping for breath, on the hallway floor. A few minutes later, he rounded the final corner and arrived at a familiar portrait.

"Password?" asked the Fat Lady.

"Squeak," Milo answered impatiently, and the portrait obligingly swung open.

"Milo!" Hermione and Ron, who were (conveniently, Milo noted) evidently just about to leave Gryffindor Tower for breakfast and class, stared at him in surprise.

"How did you escape?" Ron was stunned. "The last we saw of you, you were being carried away by—"

"Hold up," Hermione said, cutting him off. "How do we know you're really you this time? For all we know, you're another doppelganger."

"Another Doppelganger?" Milo gasped. "I didn't realize you had those here, as well. And I won't be able to cast True Seeing for, like, five levels!"

"Okay, nevermind," Hermione said with relief. "It's really you. How'd you get away?"

"No time," Milo said. He'd tell them later, in the Post-Adventure Between-Session Downtime Assumed Debrief. Nobody ever had time to waste telling people what happened when they weren't there for adventures for one reason or another. Instead, they'd handle it in the time between scenes, like sleeping or item crafting.

"Where's Harry?" Milo asked. The plot here clearly revolved around the Boy-Who-Lived, and Milo wasn't about to embark on a potentially campaign-changing adventure without him. Besides, Milo had seen his Expelliarmus in action (and been on the receiving end on more than one occasion).

"No idea," Ron said. "He left ages ago to get breakfast; haven't seen him since."

Milo sighed. "And you didn't think to check up on that? No, I know, it's not your fault, you didn't know. By the way, Quirrell's our guy. He's been evil all along."

"Wh—"

"No time, I'll explain along the way. Let's move."

"Where are we going?" Hermione asked curiously.

"Where else?" Milo asked. "The forbidden third-floor corridor. It was always going to end there, one way or another."

"So, about Quirrell. I can't believe he's really—" Hermione began skeptically.

o—o—o—o

"—he's really evil. I can't believe it," she said, stunned, as they approached the forbidden door and Milo finished his boring, off-screen exposition. "We should tell Dumbledore."

"Can't," Milo said. "Believe it or not, I tried that already—"

"—You did what? I mean, Quirrell was surprising enough, but you? Going to a legitimate authority figure in a time of crisis? I mean, what is the world coming to?"

"—and he wasn't in his office, obviously."

"What do you mean, obviously?" Ron asked, his forehead wrinkled.

Milo was about to launch into an explanation of how the powerful NPC ally had to be out of the way to move the plot forward—Milo suspected an explanation would be forthcoming eventually about how he had important paperwork to do in East Nowhere or something—but, surprisingly, Hermione beat him to it.

"No, it makes perfect sense. I mean, think about it," she said. "Quirrell wouldn't make his move for the Stone if Dumbledore was actually in the castle. That would be like trying to, I don't know, hold up a police station or kidnap an auror: suicide. So he waited this long to make his move."

"...Right," Milo added. "What she said. Excellent deduction, grasshopper."

"Grass—" she sputtered indignantly.

"Team! Focus! Big wooden door to get past, boy wizard to save," Ron said with exasperation.

"Oh, right," Hermione said. "Aloho—"

"—Wait!" Milo cried.

"What?" she asked testily. "I was just about to unlock it."

"No, you weren't. Do you think they'd lock the Philosopher's Stone behind a door that could be opened by a first-year student—even a brilliant first-year student—in a school for magic? The door is likely trapped. Dumbles even warned us: 'the third-floor corridor on the right-hand side is out of bounds for anyone who does not want to die a horrible and painful death.' It's trapped with something gnarly. Probably the wanded wizard equivalent of a Fire Trap or something."

"Good point," Hermione said, looking somewhat pale.

"How did you remember his exact wording like that?" Ron asked. "You can't remember anything. Remember the Cuddly Cannons?"

"No, I don't. I just used Autohypnosis to memorize the Plot last time I had a chance to see it. Took a while with, er..." he was going to say 'with my low Wisdom,' but at the last minute changed it to "the primordial forces Arcane being as they were. The ley lines were all a-flux," Milo had once heard a Bard futilely try to make a Spellcraft check, and quoted him mercilessly, "and there was a fae disturbance in the realms of spirit, beyond the veil."

"So, what do you suggest we do, exactly?" Hermione asked.

Milo shrugged. His usual plan was to send the Rogue in, tied to a rope (thus making it easier to retrieve the body, and all her ill-gotten loot). "Torch the door."

"What?" Hermione looked at him as if he had just suggested she sell her mother to Goblin slavers. "Why?"

"We know this isn't the only layer of defence—there used to be a giant three-headed dog on the other side of this wall, and presumably there's more beyond. This door is to keep out thieves, not a frontal assault. That comes later. Dumbledore probably assumed that anyone crazy enough to try to destroy a door in the middle of a public hallway would be caught by passerbys."

"Passersby," Hermione corrected idly, obviously thinking hard. "And I think you're wrong. Dumbledore doesn't think nearly as twisty as you do, and he wouldn't put a trapped door in the middle of what was, as you pointed out, a public hallway. He's more the type to say the door led to certain death, but, really, still give the person sneaking through more than one chance to escape with their life. That dog you mentioned was chained down—out of reach of the doorway. So someone accidentally breaking in could see the dog and, if they have any sense, which by the way we seem not to have, flee. The door is only locked."

"You might be right," Milo conceded, "except on one point. Dumledore's mind is twistier than mine could ever be."

"Alohomora," Hermione cast as Milo discreetly moved to stand behind Ron, just in case.

The lock clicked open.

"Right," Milo said. "We have no idea what's on the other side of this door. Quirrell killed the dog already, passing it off as necessary to save Hermione. He could have replaced it with anything. Trolls, Giants," he glanced at Ron and grinned, "Giant Trolls, Dragons, whatever."

"What's your point?" Ron asked. "We're going in anyway. We both know it."

"What I'm saying is: be ready for anything." Milo calmly drew his staff and traded his knife from his extradimensional Belt pocket to a more-easily-reached sheath, then checked his Magic Items to be certain. Robe, Belt, Amulet, Gloves, Headband, check. He took a deep breath. "All right, party. It's taken us long enough. Let's do this thing," and pushed the door open with his gloved hand.

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: I'm Back.

AKA "We now return you to your regularly-scheduled fantastic fan fiction."

AAKA If you don't get the reference in the chapter title, go read anything by David (and Leigh) Eddings. You won't regret it.

AAAKA Merry Christmas, Internet.

(But seriously, short updates suck – but better short than never. I decided to stop being a perfectionist and just release it, warts and all. Fixing of typos and whatnot will come later. If this keeps up, I'll have your next update Thursday or Friday of next week.)

Chapter 32: Dumble-dénouement

"Tell me again why you carry a grappling hook at all times, mate?" Ron asked, giving Milo's silk rope a hefty tug. He had an ugly bruise on his temple, and likely an assortment of minor injuries, but was otherwise okay. "And a rope, for that matter."

"Came in handy, didn't it?" Milo pointed between pulls. "Every adventurer has at least fifty feet of rope. Some carry hundreds."

Getting back up the shaft that led to the Devil's Snare seemed, at first, an insurmountable problem—until Milo remembered he still had rope in his belt. Hermione levitated it up to the surface and latched the grappling hook onto the heavy cast iron ring the trapdoor used as a handle. Climbing up wasn't exceptionally difficult (a rope with a wall to brace against was a mere DC 5 with a 10 point reduction for having a wall to brace against. A paraplegic triple-amputee could make the check). No, the hard part was getting the still-unconscious Professor Quirrell to the top. In the end, they simply tied the rope around his waist and shoulders and decided to pull him up.

"Reckon we should have just left him there," Harry muttered. He still looked pale and shaky from Quirrell's torture spell, but hadn't mentioned it. The others decided to drop it, though Hermione gave him occasional concerned looks.

"He's a Hogwarts Professor!" Hermione sounded scandalized. "We can't just leave him!"

"We could have told McGonagall or Dumbledore, and they would have gone down and got him. Besides, he did try to kill us all."

Hermione made a hmph! sound, but dropped the issue. It took several more minutes, but they eventually got Quirrell's limp body up to the room where Fluffy once stood.

"You know," Ron mused as he grabbed the Professor by the shoulders and dragged him onto the floor, "We likely could have just levitated him, like Hermione did the rope."

"He's far too heavy," Hermione pointed out.

"For all three of us at once?" Ron asked. "It wouldn't have taken a moment."

Harry, Hermione, and Milo stared at him for a few seconds in total silence. Hermione opened her mouth like she was going to speak, then fell silent.

"Why me?" she asked nobody in particular.

"I, for one, can think of no witch more suited for the task," someone said from the doorway. Milo, keenly aware he had only five hit points remaining (he'd gained three upon levelling up), not to mention no spells more powerful than Acid Splash, warily turned to the door.

"Professor!" Harry said in relief. In the doorway was none other than Professor Dumbledore, still dressed in the same purple robes he'd worn to Lucius's Manor.

"Indeed, that is my chosen vocation. Quick, as always, Mister Potter. Now, could somebody please illuminate me as to what in Merlin's name is going on in my school?"

Everyone spoke at once.

"Voldemort—"

"Lucius—"

"Please don't tell my mum—"

"Oh, I know you said we weren't to enter the forbidden corridor, but—"

Dumbledore simply waited patiently while they all told the story, as they saw it, beginning at different times and, frequently, in backwards, frontwards, and, occasionally sidewards order.

"So, you mean to say that Quirinus—while under the sway of Voldemort—led young Milo out into the forest where a group of masked men led by Lucius Malfoy intercepted them, inadvertently foiling the plans of their incognito master, captured Milo, Disapparated back to their manor, only to have Milo escape and return to Hogwarts while the Defence Professor took Harry under the false pretenses of needing his help to rescue Milo—who needed no help, it appears, after all—to find the Philosopher's Stone, assuming that Harry would be able to breach whatever defences I had placed, only to be foiled by Milo, Ron, and Hermione?"

"Was... was that all one sentence, Professor?" Milo asked in awe—partly by the feat of linguistics, but mainly that the Headmaster had managed to listen to all four of them simultaneously. Probably comes from a supernaturally-extended lifetime of teaching teenagers. "Also, yes. That's pretty much how it happened."

"Very well," Dumbledore sighed, and gestured for them to follow him. "I think, perhaps, it would be best if we returned to my office to discuss this matter further."

"Where were you?" Harry asked en route. There was a faint accusatory note in his voice.

"The Ministry," Dumbledore said. "The reasons for which should become clear once we reach my office." The mild rebuke was enough to make Harry look at his feet and remain silent for the rest of the short, winding walk.

Upon entering the office, Dumbledore sat down on his customary chintz armchair, and, his fingers forming a steeple in front of him, spoke.

"I assume you have questions," he said. "I will, if at all possible, answer to within the best of my ability. But first, to answer Harry's: I was at the Ministry. After I was tipped off by a certain... trusted source that Milo was held within one of the Malfoy's estates, I wasted no time in informing friends within the Department of Magical Law Enforcement and assisting in what is, I believe, generally called a raid. Incidentally, this was also my first clue as to Professor Quirrell's deception—he came to me with his story that Milo was held by vampires. I did not, however, realize the full extent of the situation until well later. By that point, I was bogged down with what I daresay was a tremendous quantity of paperwork. It appears that deploying Aurors without warning against one of the more well-respected members of the wizarding community of Magical Britain is not without cost."

"So they caught Malfoy, then?" Milo was surprised. He hadn't thought that their scuffle in the manor would be the last they'd see of him. There were too many unanswered questions for that.

"Alas, no," Dumbledore sighed. "Officially, a pair of deranged wizards attempting to revive the criminal organization known as the Death Eaters broke into Malfoy's residence in an attempt to punish him for his betrayal at the end of the war. Their actions were, it appears, independent and without support from others."

"But that's not true!" Harry insisted. "He was one of them! You have to believe us!"

"Oh, I do, dear boy. But that doesn't change the fact that it will take more substantial evidence for the Ministry to mobilize in full. In the meantime, be comforted in knowing that there are those within the Ministry who are working diligently—and, unfortunately, secretly—to uncover the truth of the matter."

Harry didn't look particularly happy, but let the matter rest.

"I have a question, Headmaster," Ron interjected. "How did You-Know-Who get to be on the back of another bloke's head?"

"Unicorn's blood," Dumbledore said sadly. "It can be used to prolong one's life almost indefinitely, but at the cost of being doomed to living an unnatural half-life."

"Unnatural is bloody right," Ron muttered. "Er, sorry Professor."

"Not to worry," the Professor said, "I was momentarily distracted by a delightful passing bluebird, and seem to have missed everything you said just then."

"Er. Right."

"So," Harry said slowly, "Is he gone, then? Voldemort?"

"I'm afraid not," Dumbledore said gravely. "I don't know if it will be a year or ten, but I can be certain that he will return."

"How could you know?" Milo asked. "There's no telling the crazy results when our forms of magic interact. Mind, he's obviously not gone—it's the only thing that makes sense, he has to be the final boss, and this was hardly final—but still. By you people's standards of logic, the Amulet may well have finished him off."

"While that may be a possibility," Dumbledore admitted, "Harbouring it would reduce our vigilance for his return. In general, I have found that, when it comes to dealing with Voldemort, it is best to hope for the best, prepare for the worst, and, when it comes to it, expect even worse."

"But—"

"Also, young Milo, I have access to certain sources that you do not."

"Fair enough," Milo admitted. "Now, what happens to the Defence Professor?"

"That depends," Dumbledore admitted. "I will have to talk to him when he awakes. The question to determine is to what amount he was a willing supporter of Voldemort, and what amount he was a slave. Based on your stories, it appears that he deliberately took action to expel Voldemort's spirit from his body, which implies it was some of the former. I can scarcely imagine living a life such as that."

"Oh?" Harry asked, curious.

"To my limited understanding of the process, Professor Quirrell's resident, so to speak, had the power to read the Professor's mind directly. Any plan that Professor Quirrell developed could be immediately detected by Voldemort, who could—and, knowing him, would—punish his servant severely."

"Are you suggesting that Quirrell had to develop and execute his plan without, at any step along the way, consciously thinking about it?" Milo asked incredulously.

"Is that even possible?" Hermione was stunned.

"I will need to speak to him to be certain, but it would appear to be so," Dumbledore responded. "It is entirely possible that he set up the entire chain of events that led to him getting his hands on Milo's amulet deliberately. Or, perhaps more likely, he seized on the opportunity provided by his master's distracted state, caused by the brave young Mister Potter here. Whatever the case, it still remains to be determined whether or not he was, well..."

"...Evil?" Harry suggested.

"In essence. If so, I shall turn him over to the Ministry without delay. But if not... I might consider offering him a teaching position. There is, however, one thing I can say for certain."

"And what's that?" Milo asked.

"Come next term, he will no longer be the Defence Professor."

"How do you know?" Hermione asked.

"Call it an old man's intuition," Dumbledore smiled.

"I have a question, Professor," Hermione said. "What will you do with the Philosopher's Stone now? And, for that matter—where is it?"

"Ah," Dumbledore said with a mischievous grin. "It was in the Mirror all along. However, I had bewitched it only to give it to someone who wanted the Stone—but not to use it."

"So he was right!" Milo exclaimed. "You had set the Mirror up as some kind of elaborate test of character!"

"And I failed?" Harry asked. "Wait..." he looked at the Headmaster for a second, then suddenly laughed. "He sabotaged himself!"

"Excuse me?" Hermione asked.

"He guessed it was a test of character, but he told me that he needed the Stone to save Milo," Harry explained. "So..."

"So you wanted to use it," Milo said, grinning. "You were desperate to."

"Indeed," Dumbledore said. "And as for the Stone... it is not fully my decision to make. I'll send word to Nicolas Flamel, and together we will decide what is best. However, I think that, for now, it would be best if you all went to see Poppy in the Hospital Wing." As they all turned to leave, he added, "Except for you, Mister Amastacia-Liadon."

Milo sat down as the others left, feeling somewhat concerned. "What's up?" he asked.

"I believe it has come time for us to discuss what to do about you."

"Oh?" Milo asked apprehensively.

"Well, the simple fact of the matter is that, forgive me, you don't fully fit in here," Dumbledore said, "your form of magic being all but completely incompatible with that which is taught in this school. I can think of any number of wizarding families that would be happy to have you stay with them until such a time as we can figure how to return you to your home."

"Are... are you kicking me out?" Milo was floored. Sure, the magic was different—and he was failing Transfiguration and Potions—but he'd never imagined that he'd be thrown out like this. "Because, quite frankly Professor, you're mistaken."

"Oh? On which issue?"

"Hogwarts is my home," Milo said firmly. "And I've never felt that way about anywhere else."

"Very well," Dumbledore said slowly. "I must confess, I had thought you wanted nothing more than to leave. But, seeing as that is not the case, you might want to look to your studies. Minerva is your Head of House, and she is well within her power to expel you for your grades, which, I am told, are somewhat less than doughty."

"But I'm doing my best!" Milo protested. "I can't actually do your magic! How am I supposed to pass?"

"You seem to have managed in at least four courses," Dumbledore pointed out.

"Two of which have no magic involved whatsoever," Milo countered, "and in Charms, I just got lucky. One of my spells is similar to the Hovering Charm, which is basically the only actual spell Flitwick taught us. The rest was theory. Thank the gods above and below that he didn't ask me to Hover anything sideways, or I'd have been up the Styx without a paddle." Levitate could only move things vertically.

"I understand, dear boy, I do—but I'm not, quite frankly, certain what I can do about it. You see, currently, I am the only member of the faculty aware of the nature of your powers—though Minerva knows some of it, and Poppy is developing suspicions that you are, in fact, an 'Eldritch Horror from Beyond Time Come to Sow Destruction.' I could inform them, but it would come at the risk of letting your secret get out to the wider world."

"I see the problem," Milo said reluctantly. "I might—might—be able to fake my way through Transfiguration." He'd need a week to plan at least, and likely a month of spell research. "The other courses are, so far, not much problem—though, I suspect, at higher levels DADA will become less theory and more application, in which case I will be in trouble. But, in Potions, there's nothing I can do." Even if he took the suboptimal Brew Potion feat, he could still only make his kind—that is to say, Arcane—Potions, which were very specific in their nature, effect, and brewing process.

"Then there is, happily, no problem," Dumbledore said broadly. "Graduation with a T in Potions is perfectly acceptable, though not, of course, strictly encouraged. In fact, I can pass word around that you were strongly traumatized from a young age by certain potions, and, as a result, have a severe psychological handicap to overcome. It might make things somewhat easier for you."

"You wouldn't even be lying," Milo added happily. "I'm severely traumatized by Potions every time I go into Snape's classroom."

"Very well, I believe this matter is settled," Dumbledore said with a glint in his eye. Milo was reminded once more that he was speaking to someone considerably wilier than himself, and wondered whether or not this had been the intended outcome of the conversation. "Now, I have just one more question for you," Dumbledore said slowly.

"Yes, Professor?"

"What was your mother's name?"

"Ley Amastacia." The question caught him completely by surprise, and Milo answered without thinking. He stared at Dumbledore for a moment before the knut dropped. "Pelor, Nerull and Kord!" he exclaimed. "My backstory!" The moment he said it, he knew that his mother's name was Ley, and could almost picture her face.

Dumbledore simply smiled. "I think, if you move alacritously, you may be able to catch your friends before they reach the hospital wing. If you do see them, could you tell them that all four of you earned fifty house points each? Oh—and, if you could ask Harry to come visit sometime this evening, it would be much appreciated."

"Th-thank you, Professor," Milo stammered. He was still too surprised by his sudden discovery to fully process what was going on. His backstory was working again—but it seemed somewhat different from before. Back then, the answers simply appeared as necessary, but now... it was as if Milo had been the one to will them into existence. This warranted further thought and experimentation—but for now, he would just enjoy what had happened. He had to level up, sooner or later he'd have to deal with the consequences of beating Malfoy and his mooks senseless, and figure out a plan to turn a matchstick into a pin, but that could (hopefully) be done another day.

As Milo turned the doorknob, Dumbledore spoke once more.

"Oh—and Milo? I'm proud of you."

o—o—o—o—o—o—o

Author's Notes: Fear not! Harry Potter and the Natural 20 is not over yet! Next week's chapter will be mini-epilogues (a couple of largely disjointed short stories covering a few things left to wrap up) which will then be followed by year two, maybe after a week or two of planning, Harry Potter and the Confirmed Critical. For simplicity's sake, as far as Fanfiction is concerned they'll be the same fic (The first chapter of book two will be Chapter 34 of Harry Potter and the Natural 20). That way, you don't need to worry about finding and subscribing to a new fic.